It's so good to see all of you.
I was so thankful today as I was driving in
that I get to be with the people of God today in the house of the Lord.
Amen.
And how many of you are so thankful to God for his goodness that we're here today?
Amen?
Look around at your brothers
and sisters in the Lord and tell them
I'm saved today.
I am saved.
Jesus has saved me.
Amen?
So he deserves all of our praise today.
Come on, let's lift our voices this morning.
Give him our God's worship.
He's withheld nothing from us, amen.
So Jesus, we give you everything this morning.
We love you today, Lord.
And we're going to lift up your name in this place.
Hallelujah.
Come on.
What am I God?
We serve.
Angels bow before you end up the door.
What am I gone?
We serve.
What if I God, we deserve?
What if I God we serve?
Angels bow before.
Heaven at the door.
What if I got we suffering?
What if I thought we deserved?
Angels bow before we do it.
What if I thought we be sure?
We in the name of the name of Jesus.
In the name of Jesus.
We have the live.
Satan will have to be.
Oh in his name, Jesus.
Jesus.
We have a victory.
In the name of Jesus.
Send our who can step in for us
when we born his way again.
Jesus.
Jesus precious.
We have the victory.
I will come on the blood.
Bless it be the back.
Bless it be the back of my subject.
Bless it be the block.
Let's it be the block of somebody.
Bless it be the block of somebody.
What type of we serve?
Why we come on be served?
I've been a story.
Why we come on be the server?
One line, we deserve.
That man is a door.
What life we got we deserve?
Oh my beyond we deserve.
Why we thought we deserve.
Angels are before me.
That's why that joy.
What life we thought is in the name of Jesus.
In the name of Jesus
in the name of Jesus
we have the winnings all we need.
In the name of Jesus, in the name of Jesus
say that the hand to leave me.
Tell me who can send me for us when we fall.
He is ready.
Jesus.
We have a free glory.
Oh sing it again.
Come on.
Oh in the name of Jesus.
In the name of Jesus.
We have the main glory.
Send everyone to be.
In the name of Jesus.
We have a thing for me.
Satan will have to plead me.
Tell me who can stand for us when we call his prayer.
Jesus, Jesus precious, Jesus
we have a thing who said we called Jesus, Jesus, Jesus, Jesus.
Jesus Christ us.
Jesus.
We have come to the Lord.
We give you praise, Jesus.
Hallelujah, Jesus.
Hallelujah to your name.
Blessed be your name, God.
We praise you this morning, Lord.
We worship you today, oh God.
Oh Lord, it's a new day to lift up your name.
Another day, God, to give you our praise, Lord
for all that you've done, Lord.
We glorify you, God.
We worship and adore you today, Lord.
Like never before, God.
Like never before, Lord.
To worship you with all of our hearts today, God.
Worship his holiday.
All my soul worship God.
The sun hunter is a beauty.
It's time to sing the song again whatever they follow me.
Let me be singing when we come on through turmoil state.
Oh my soul.
Worship is so my soul.
Worship your Lord being your vision and your soul to barrier.
Your name is great
and your heart is mine.
For all your goodness
I will be on seeking ten thousand reasons for my heart to lie.
Oh my soul.
Worship is holy day.
See my death before.
Oh my soul, worship your and that day
when my strength is saving the end of seven when my time has come
still my soul will see your brain and down to shit.
Just the voice.
Can we just take some time to worship the Lord right now?
Just out of your heart.
Out of your heart right now.
With all your heart.
Jesus, we give you praise today.
We bless you, Lord.
We bless you, Jesus.
You are an awesome God.
You are so kind.
You are rich in love.
You are slow to anger.
What a mighty God you are.
We love you today, Lord.
We lift our voices in praise to you, God.
Worthy are you, Lord.
Worthy of all of our praise.
All of our affection.
All of our adoration, all of our hearts today, God.
We give it to you, Lord.
Be glorified in this place, Lord.
Oh God, may this be a place
where your name is lifted high.
Where your people worship you in the spirit energy.
Oh God.
You are the Lord of Lord.
You are the precious Lamb of God.
There is none but you, God.
You reign in glory today, Lord.
Seated on a throne, God.
Everything is under your foot, Lord Jesus.
You are in total control, Lord.
We glorify your name, Lord.
We fix our eyes on you today.
We stand in awe of you, God.
We are amazed at you, Lord.
What a wonderful God you are.
All power in your right hand, Lord.
And yet you love us today, God.
Your eyes are turned towards us today, God.
Your heart is moved by your people today, Lord.
You shower your mouth and your mercy on us, God.
Who are we, God
that you would love us, Lord?
You've given us your very life, Lord
so that we would know you today, God.
So we come back into your presence, Lord.
And we bless your name, Jesus.
Hallelujah.
Come on, let's sing it.
Give him a shout of praise this morning with blessing Jesus.
We bless your name, God.
We praise you.
We thank you that you are in our midst today, Jesus.
You are with us, God.
We're conscious that you are with us today, Lord.
So we worship you like you're with us, God.
You are here.
You are among your people, God.
You're not far off, Lord.
You dwell within us, God.
And we give you praise, Jesus.
We give you praise.
We give you glory.
We bless your wonderful name today, God.
And we give you this meeting.
We pray your direction.
We pray your moving.
We pray your anointing, God.
We pray that you would touch your people again, Lord.
Bless, bless everything that happens.
Bless every person that's here, watching online
and those that will watch in the future.
Bless them, meet them, God
because you're gracious.
You don't treat us, God
according to what we deserve, God.
Lord, you show us mercy and grace.
So we come to you, that throne of grace, God, ready to accept every gift, God
that you would give us today, Lord
and we thank you for it in us.
We bless you, Lord.
We praise you, and we give it this name in Jesus' name.
Sing praises to the king.
Sing the praises to them.
For he is the king of kings.
Sing praises to the king.
For he's the king of kings, give him glory
for he's the king of kings, give him glory
for he's the king of beings.
Sing praises to the king
for he is the king of beats
sing praises to the king
for he's the king of things
sing praises to the hunger ,
your praises before single , boys , the king of things , in the glory
, all these pig that pigs in the glory , all these pig nutrients , in the
dark , all these big nuts , in the dark , all these big nutrients , in the dark ,
all these big nutrients , with a big nutrients , in the big nutrients , in the house
and we're not gonna be able to do that.
But now I see the life I knew was hopeless until you rescue me.
Now I search for all you so Jesus.
Now I have you the praise for all my God.
I thank you, Jesus, Jesus for all the dumb.
I thank you, Jesus, Jesus
Oh what a friend I saw Oh the joy that you give to me
and I said so I see God you call us
you would be with me
And that'll never ever be
So I'll give you the praise through all of my days until your face I just want me
I thank you because she does Lord I thank God I thank you every day I thank you
Lord I thank you for your goodness
and your mercy Jesus Thank you, Jesus, Jesus for your tender love and kindness
Oh thank you, Lord Each and everything, thank you, thank you, Jesus for me
no money Jesus mighty mighty God to me open up this morning
and thank you Started me on my way
Thank you Jesus That's why Thank you Jesus with every break Jesus You pray it
that's why I say Lord
I thank you
Then you put food on my table Lord
I beg you give me my health and strength
Thank you Jesus I lift my hands to stick with all you pay
for all you done for all you've done for me
for me I fall in the rock
and all the past we both go back to the way to before you stay
and take the beat back to go back to the way to beat before the day news to before
the presentation to the way you to be let's take me I won't go back
Let's say come on, everyone says
flap your hands as hard as you can for the Lord.
We praise you, Jesus.
We praise you with his blood.
So it was on a prayer meeting night eleven years ago
when I had previously been out to California speaking in um
where they have the Rose Bowl, Pasadena.
I was in Pasadena, California
for an event for the Southern District, Southern California District of the Assemblies of God
and they were laying hands
and sending people out for home missions, like team challenges to Native American reservations and then foreign ports.
Way out there, there was a young lady named Amaren from Southern California.
The Lord drew it her to my attention
and uh she was gonna go learn Arabic
and go and be placed in some undisc undisclosed spot in the Middle East
to try to sh uh share Christ.
And then there was this man
and it ended up he was married
and with three children named Adam Boyd.
So I found out he was gonna go to Papua New Guinea
which is further away than London, then Korea.
Papua New Guinea, wow
it's way out and then down in the southern Pacific.
And um they were going to go out under the auspices of Whitecliffe Bible translators
and they were going to a tribe, the major tribe in Papua New Guinea, um
who speak a language called Anga, E-N-G-A. Everyone say Enga.
Anga.
And the Anga people had no New Testament in their language.
So how could they study about Jesus?
How could they learn about Jesus?
How could they learn about the ministry of the Holy Spirit?
How could they learn about what the Bible teaches about the second coming of Christ?
How could they learn about how Christians should love each other?
How could they learn anything uh with authority coming from the very word of God?
Well, they couldn't
but they were Christians
but it had been verbally transmitted the gospel.
So he was part of this team to put the Bible into the Enga language.
And um So I want you to watch this, okay?
Let's go to dark and watch this.
What they call the Enga people are goal getters.
They're influential in the capital city of Port Moresby
where they work as business leaders
uh leaders in the government
and they tend to be the movers and shakers.
And so making sure that the Enga people have a translation of the New Testament is very important
because they're influencing the rest of the country.
English is not our language
and pigeon is not our language, too.
Hearing and reading the Bible in pigeon.
The meaning of the word God is not very clear.
Somebody was preaching.
You know what he he did?
He read it into pigeon
and then translated with his vocal.
That I don't know.
It's not accurate.
The missing lot of points or the adding lotter point.
That's not accurate.
I want them to read it
and understand the whole message as it is.
So that is why some of us came together
and found out that we should translate the Bible into anger.
It is not that you know one particular group
or one particular church took initiative to translate this.
No, all we all the churches in anger, the church in denonation.
We come together and to translate this Bible
and now it's it's come into in our hands now.
I want to see the anger people taking Jesus at his word and living in peace.
I wonder if people who love God
and hear the story and then acknowledge and believe.
Christ died for all people.
When we are to work with all people
the gospel of Christ might come to all people
and understand the love of God.
That's what I'm talking about, the Anga New Testament.
So we laid hands on that couple.
Their kids were much they were young then.
And now, eleven years later, guess what?
The Anga translation has been done.
All the people then who's there who speak Anga.
And um uh I've been following the newsletters that Adam Boyd
who is the um man of God and his wife Martha.
And now their children
imagine their children are now twenty, eighteen, and sixteen.
And they were just little of eleven years ago
they seemed so small.
And here they were gonna leave everything in America to go to Papua New Guinea.
And I know at least for a while
they were living out in uh nowhere's way out there.
And uh grew up served God, still serving God
and it just so happens we're blessed to have Adam Boyd visiting with us.
I want him to come up and say hello, everybody
put your hands together from my friend Adam Boyd.
Come on!
Oh, good morning, church.
It is such a joy
and an honor to be with you.
This church, this isn't our home church
but it feels like our home church.
Uh, I've never been around such a loving, prayerful group of Christians.
And so it's just uh a blessing to be able to share this moment with you.
This is the Anga New Testament that we have.
That's good.
We've been able to complete the Anga New Testament uh in print format
as an audio, uh solar-powered audio player
because most people don't know how to read very well.
It's a Bible app
you can get it on U version
and so people have access to it in a variety of ways.
But I'll tell you what
it's not been easy.
There's been a lot of challenges, a lot of discouragement, a lot of obstacles
and uh your prayers and your support have been so uh crucial to this process.
And so I can't thank you enough.
Coming here, you know
there's times we want to give up and quit,
and coming here is like a shot of adrenaline.
And so thank you so much uh for that.
Um, when I look at all the obstacles and difficulties and discouragements, you know
I said to my wife Martha about a year ago, I said, you know what
it's really a miracle that this even exists.
And so I give thanks to God.
I thank Brooklyn Tabernacle from the bottom of my heart.
Thank you so much.
And Pastor, I want to I want to give this thing in New Testament to you.
For me?
Yes.
This is uh a sign of your participation.
There you go.
I have no idea what this says.
I I'll teach you how to read it.
I thought that.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Thank you, brother.
Let's hear one more time for Adam Boyd.
You know, sometimes we greet each other uh in another language um this morning.
Uh in the morning we say
do it in Spanish or whatever.
Swahili.
And I turned to uh some um people helping me who were they're from Jamaica, and I said
How do you say good morning in Jamaica?
And they said, Manin, neighbor.
Manin.
Everybody turn and say, man, neighbor, to your friend.
So uh listen, we've been supporting no you, me
we've been supporting this family for eleven years.
Isn't that an honor?
I don't
I don't think like, oh
should we support Adam Boyd and his family?
That's like that we can be part of the reward.
Imagine we went to get to heaven
and the rewards are passed out.
There'll be rewards for him
and his wife and those show to then they can go and do that
but who will support them?
Who will take care of them?
So he's not the only one.
We have people all over the world that we're supporting
which we never take a separate offering for.
So I'm saying to those watching online and all of you
would you continue to please give even this morning?
When you leave, there's baskets out there.
You can put your offering in.
And um when you um or you can give online.
I really get discouraged sometimes when I see the statistics.
You know, um I I don't want to be legalistic about anything.
But you you see statistics.
When I was growing up, my mom
even though my dad started drinking, lost a job
my mother was taught and and took it upon herself.
Well, look, in the Old Testament before Christ came
the people gave a tenth of their net pay.
So if you took home four hundred dollars, you gave forty.
Comprend that no compared.
So that was just a given, right?
And now I see statistics of people who go to church
and sing in choir and
and deacons and just all over the whole thing.
Something, Adam,
less than less than six percent of all the people who go to church and call themselves Christians,
less than six percent give regularly ten percent of their income.
Let's say uh well
I don't see that in the New Testament.
I don't want to argue with you.
Um but if they were giving before Jesus died
they gave ten percent.
So what should we give less now to the work of the Lord?
Does that make any sense to you?
No, I'm asking you
does that make any sense?
So it's it's money
the love of money is the root of all kinds of evil.
I was just reading through what was it
Luke how Jesus died
I mean the final coup de gras.
Was Judas betrayed him for filthy money.
For filthy money.
Not out of hate, but for money.
He lost his soul for money, for silver.
And when I see those statistics, um churches suffer, missionaries suffer
churches could do so much more if the people, all of them, just gave systematically.
Uh so I just want to challenge all of you
and I never have checked once in my life here at this church
the pastors we're not privy to what people give.
That's that's not right.
I'm not should be digging into what you give
I should be just worried about what I give.
Amen?
And then some churches
someone told me this again the other day
they grew up in a church
where the pastor would put on the bulletin board in the lobby what everybody gave the week before.
I mean, really.
That's like spiritual extortion, right?
You're gonna pressure people so that and shame them.
We don't want to do that
because God doesn't love a come uh a compelled giver.
He loves what kind of giver.
So I I'm just you uh what when you don't give
you lose out of the blessing, the peace of God.
There's just special blessings.
Uh what does the Amplified Bible say say?
God loves bracket, cherishes above all other things
will never do without
will never abandon those who are cheerful givers.
Because he's a giver, God's a giver.
So um I just challenge all of you
because American Christianity is whack in many ways.
It's not biblical.
You know, they're fighting to get the Angel language so
that people can learn what the Bible says.
And we have the Bible in English
but we don't do what it says sometimes.
But listen, it's more blessed to give than to receive.
Isn't it something at Christmas time coming up soon, God willing?
Isn't it something that around the world people curse God
they don't know about anything
yet they buy a gift
and they give it to someone.
And that's something that the birth of Christ reminds people about this thing of giving.
For God so loved the world that he gave.
Lord, I take a moment here to pray
that you would bless us and the offering today, but an online giving.
But God, would you help all of us to be faithful stewards?
What what do we have
that you didn't give us?
There's nothing I have, God
that you didn't give us.
And now I'm gonna withhold an offering to you.
God forbid.
So help me and Carol to be better givers.
And all of us here in the room and watching online
help us to remember that you are Jehovah Jira Jaira, our provider.
And help us to share back.
Bless this offering.
Let it go not only more money for the translation Anga
but let it go around the world.
Help us pay all our bills here.
We ask all this in Jesus' name.
Amen.
I don't speak much about giving
and I don't do sermons about giving and all of that
but I did just want to exhort you about that.
So today is Good News Sunday.
And we're gonna just share the good news about Jesus Christ, the gospel.
A reminder for all of us.
And maybe you're here today and you're a churchgoer
but you're not a Christian.
Wow, how did that happen?
You know, one of the most mysterious verses in the New Testament is this Jesus said
Many will say in that day, Lord, Lord
did we not cast out devils in your name
and prophesy and heal in your name?
Obviously, knowing the name and knowing the power that's in that name,
and believing in the supernatural.
And then Jesus said
and then at the end I will say, Depart from me.
I never knew you.
You didn't walk the way I asked you to walk.
You didn't honor me with your life.
So today is good news.
We want to talk about the good news.
How many are happy Jesus is about good news and not bad news?
There's enough bad news.
Oh, is there bad news?
Is there bad news out there?
So I want to give you a living example of the good news of Jesus Christ.
I have never heard her testimony.
I've heard about it.
And walk through some of it with her.
She's employed by the church.
Her name is Shireen Bridgewater.
Would you would you put your hands together in the room with Shereen Bridgewater?
Good morning, church family.
How are we today?
I'm up here just to share a portion of my testimony
and what God has done in my life.
I was raised with my mom
and my dad in the beginning.
I'm the oldest of four.
How many know that when you're the eldest
there's a lot on you?
I'm the eldest of four.
Um so my dad struggled with drinking a lot.
So you could just imagine how my home was, right?
So at a very early age
my mom became a single parent.
I remember at seven
my dad came home in a rage and he was drinking.
And he came home and he started to argue with my mom.
My siblings and myself were in the kitchen
and we didn't know what was going on
but then he started physically abusing her.
And so he beat her so bad
that she had to go into the hospital.
And me and my siblings
we watched this and we couldn't help her because we were so young.
And we were afraid that if we tried to help
that he would probably do something to us.
So we wind up going to live with my nana.
We went to live with my nana
because my mom was in the hospital recovering.
My dad fled.
And so we never saw him again.
And so while living with my nana, though
my nana was a devout Christian.
And I found that my uncles
also my mom's siblings, they were Christians.
My mom was just vaccinated at the time.
And so my nana would always say
You gotta go to church.
So now that we're living with her
we're in church.
And we go into church
and then I remember when I was about 16
I accepted the Lord as my Savior
and got baptized in that church.
And as I continue to go to the church, though
I realized what I didn't know then that I know now
that it was a lot of legalism going on in that church.
I couldn't wear pants on at the church
I couldn't wear jewelry
I couldn't wear makeup.
There were so many things
and I was like
I can't get my ears pierced?
I can't wear lip gloss?
I couldn't understand it.
But I was young and I was very naive.
My mom was very strict after my dad left
and so she would we couldn't do a lot of things.
How many grew up in the era
where it was because I said so
or because I told you so, right?
So anytime we wanted to do anything
and why can't we do it?
Because I said so.
And so we just left it that way.
And so now I got so tired of trying to be good in this church
that I was in that I left.
So I left, and maybe about 17, 18
there was a guy that moved next door to me.
We lived in a house and he lived next door
and so we got to befriend one another.
We started dating.
Um, dated him until I was probably 21, got married, had a daughter
and this was around 1980
when Crack reared this ugly head.
Okay, and everybody was doing everything to get this crack.
And he decided that he wanted to go out with his friends
and he got hooked on the crack.
And so that marriage was over.
My oldest daughter is special need
so I had a lot on me at that time.
So, really and truly
I didn't mind that he left.
Um, and so after that, I just started, you know
just living my life.
I just started living my life and not reading the word, not going to church
living in a backslidden state
just doing what I do.
Um, had another child
and then after this
um just just doing what I do.
I met another guy.
Now, at the at this time
all of these things I was dealing with abandonment for what my dad did
unforgiveness for what my dad did.
I had a lot of insecurities.
There wasn't any words of affirmation going in my house.
It was never, you can do it.
I'm proud of you, I love you.
None of that went on in my house.
So I was really looking for love.
Okay, and so I met this guy
and he said to me everything that I thought I needed to hear.
Everything that I thought I wanted.
And so we started dating
and he moved in with me after this.
After some time, he moved in with me
and everything was going good.
Everything was going good.
Took care of me
took care of my children at the time, had two
took care of them.
I didn't want for anything.
Everything was fine until it wasn't fine.
So I'm in my apartment, bathing my kids
and I'm hearing a knock at the door.
And I'm saying, okay
somebody's knocking at the door.
My boyfriend's in the back room.
I go to the door.
There's a postal man there.
He says, Hey, you share me?
You
Yeah, I got a package for you.
I take the package.
I put the package on the coffee table.
I say, Hey, you got a package.
I yell to the back.
I knew it wasn't for me
because I didn't order anything.
So I went to bathe my kids again.
Now, after I'm bathing my kids
maybe a minute later
I'm hearing a forceful, like a real bang in the door
like somebody wants to break in.
I go to the door
I open the door
and it was about five
or six DEA agents with guns in my face saying
Where did you put that package?
And I'm like
Where did I put the package?
I put it on the corby table.
I look, the package is gone.
He already took the package.
Apparently, he probably was waiting for the package unbeknownst to me.
So I'm here with my hands up
they're all in my face.
They say, Who's in the apartment with you?
I say, My boyfriend's in the apartment.
He comes out, they say
You got any more drugs in here?
I go, We got drugs in here?
I was so like
we got drugs in here?
He had a little duffel bag that I would just put his clothes in
I'd wash it and put his clothes in there.
Apparently, because I took that package
I found out that he there were many more packages that came that I didn't know about
and they were allowing these packages to come so
that they can build this case.
And so when I took the package
I'm saying to them
what was in the package?
Oh, you don't know what was in the package?
I said, No, I don't.
My hands are still up
the guns are still in my face.
They said a key kilo of cocaine was in the package.
I said, What?
Okay.
Now I'm devastated, I'm upset, I'm angry
because how did you put me
and my children in harm's way like this?
So I still got my hands up.
We both got our hands up.
They go, You got any more drugs in here?
I'm looking at him because I'm like, you better not.
So they looked in his bag, all the way down in the bottom of his bag.
There was another key of another kilo of cocaine and $65,000.
So you can only imagine what I'm feeling now, okay?
Because it's my apartment.
The package came in my name
and everything that they found
it was in my apartment.
So I'm like, wait a minute now.
All of this was going on right under my nose
and I didn't even know.
This is how naive I was.
And so you can only guess what happened.
And by the way
that little postal man that I took the package from, oh
he was a DEA agent.
He was disguised.
And so we're off to jail.
So I'm in the federal prison.
And I had to get someone to watch my kids
had to get my neighbor to watch my kids and let them know
tell my mom what happened
when she came home from work.
So now I'm in prison.
I'm in jail.
We're both in jail.
I had two days before I went before the judge.
And when I go before the judge
she's looking at me
she got cases before me
and then she goes
The prosecutor is telling the story.
How he's telling the facts
everything's in my name
it was my apartment
but he was making me sound like I was flinging drugs all my life.
I'm like, who was he talking about?
Me.
My lawyer starts to speak on my behalf
and he did the best that he could with the facts
but the fact still remained that everything laid on me.
So the judge looked at me.
She said, bail set at one million dollars.
And you can only imagine how I was feeling.
I would had so many many emotions.
Who's gonna watch my kids?
What is going on?
I still was so confused because it happened so fast.
I go back to my cell
my lawyer comes to visit me.
He said it's not looking good for you.
He said, Everything is against you
everything is in your name
it's not looking good.
He said, You're looking at 25 years to life without parole.
It was a horrible day for me.
I felt abandoned, shame, still dealing with unforgiveness, a lot of insecurities.
I was dealing with a lot.
And so, but I remember when I had to go back into my cell
I remember the church that I went to.
I remember my grandma telling me, you know
about Jesus and what I learned about Jesus.
And even though it was very legalistic
I remember they said Jesus loves me
and he has a plan for my life.
And I knew that this was not the plan.
So when I went back into my cell
I started to have a real conversation with the Lord.
Didn't know how to pray
didn't know if he even heard me or was listening to me.
I just had an honest conversation with him from a heart of despair and confusion.
I just spoke and it said, God
look what I've done to my life.
I've messed up.
I said, Well, what happened to my kids?
I'm so sorry for what I've done.
It I dug, I was in a pit so deep
so deep that I didn't even know how I was gonna get out of that.
I stayed in my cell for the whole week I had to wait.
And I stayed in my cell.
And I said, Lord, this is it.
I go in front of the judge
and she's just sending people to jail.
Ten years, five years.
I was so I stood in front of her
and she said to me words that I'll never forget.
She sit up in her
she sat up in her chair, she leaned over, and she said
I don't know why I'm doing this
but I'm letting you out on your own recognizance today.
That was only the mercy of God.
Only the mercy of God.
I got out of prison that day
and I had to go to every single court date.
If I didn't go to every single court date
she was gonna take back that.
Every single court date.
Can I tell you how good God was to me?
25 years to life without parole, cancelled.
One million dollar bill, cancelled.
I turned my life back to Jesus.
He dealt with my um my my abandonment, my unforgiveness
everything that I was dealing with.
He took it all away.
I've been serving God ever since.
And let me tell you
God hated the crimes of his children.
He never turned into the crimes of his children.
He's as close as the mention of his name.
Trust him.
We serve an awesome God.
God bless you.
Isn't that amazing?
Did you know there I just want to give you this no sermon?
There's a word in the New Testament
which is used over and over again, very meaningful.
It's the word come, C-O-M-E.
As in a request, like, come here.
And Jesus would use it like this.
Come unto me, all ye that are labor laboring and are heavy laden
and I will give you rest.
What do you have to do to get the rest?
You gotta come.
He used it another time, I'm thinking, um, is anyone thirsty?
Let him come to me and drink.
Rivers of living water will come out of his life.
In other words, if you're living without peace, like she was, like I have
like you maybe have
you gotta come to Jesus.
But it has nothing to do with physical movement.
It doesn't mean come from there to there, or even come from the street into a church.
It's your heart moving to Jesus.
Your heart saying, like she said, Lord, I messed up.
This ain't right.
You have to help me.
And it's amazing that even though we have all good things waiting for us from Jesus
if we'll just come
God has given us this gift of free will so
that many never come even though it's to their own destruction.
Listen what I'm saying.
God has created this world and us humans
and he will not violate something called our free will.
We can say yes or we can say no.
No, you can't stop God from doing what he wants to do.
Yes, you can.
By just saying, no
I'm not coming.
At the end of his three
and a half years of ministry as an adult, 30 to 3.5, let's say
Jesus wept over Jerusalem.
Listen to what he said about the city that he came to.
Jerusalem, Jerusalem.
I wonder how many people he's weeping over right now in this building.
And it was a religious city.
The most religious city you could imagine.
And Jesus said, Jerusalem, Jerusalem
how many times I would have gathered you
and hovered over you and took you in close to me
and protected you and given you salvation.
How many times I would have done that
but you wouldn't let me?
You said no.
And now you got a bad future ahead of you.
It wasn't that he wasn't loving and kind
it wasn't that he didn't invite them to come
but the problem was they said no.
They said no.
You can just keep playing, Jeffrey.
I don't want to talk for long here.
She was the preacher this morning, wasn't she?
She said she was nervous in my office.
She didn't look nervous to me.
She looked like a preacher to me.
What do you think?
Can we thank God for her?
So he wept over that city.
Now, if he could force them to come
why would he weep over them?
No, it's like you love someone
and they jilt you.
Have you ever loved someone and they went, get out of here?
That hurts.
It's painful.
And that's what people do to Jesus.
That's how he ended up on a cross.
Some said yes, and most said, no, no, no, no way.
I'm not giving up the way I want to live, doing my thing.
I'm not giving that up to follow where?
Follow and live a different kind of life
not knowing that when he says, Come
if you'll come
you'll have the best life you ever dreamed of.
And when you die
you'll be with him forever and ever.
So imagine by saying no to Jesus
imagine what we bring on ourselves.
And he kept saying, just come.
Not bring a lot of money
not fix up your life.
No, come exactly the way you are.
Just come to me.
I know, but let me get this fixed.
No, no, you'll never get it fixed.
Just come with the mess and let him bless.
And he'll change everything.
But you gotta come
just you gotta get there.
So this free will which has made the possibility of evil in the world.
How can a good God have a world with so much evil?
That's because God won't violate our free will.
That's the way he's chosen in his sovereignty to run this world.
But I ran into something, congregation, this week
that has me thinking about another kind of uh come, come back.
So you remember um you remember
when Peter and the disciples were with Jesus at the Last Supper, and Jesus said
I'm gonna be betrayed tonight
and they started arguing about who was gonna betray him
and um it was a lot of confusion there at the table.
And then Jesus said this to Peter
in it's found in Luke Simon, Simon
Satan has asked to sift all of you.
I like the way the NIV puts in all of you
because some of the other translations just has you
but the you is in the plural.
Like we could say, come, you know
could could you come
meaning a whole family
could you come to my house?
Or individual, come you, you, you and you.
I don't know how it is in the Anga language
but it could mean plural
it could mean uh one person.
So the translation added all of you.
Satan has asked to sift all of you as wheat.
It's a time of testing coming.
But I have prayed for you, Simon
that your faith may not fail.
And when you have turned back, strengthened your brothers.
And that word turn back in the in the Bible we're most familiar with
a lot of us King James, it says
and when you are converted, strengthen your brothers.
Well, how could Peter be converted
when he had been with Jesus three and a half years?
So there's a double meaning.
Some of you have never come.
You've never come to the Lord.
You've never let him totally change your life.
You could be in a family of a minister.
You could be a deacon in a in some church watching
but you've never had that come to Jesus moment of new birth
and a change in your life.
And she made me think of that.
Because you know, she grew up with some experience of the Lord.
So the Lord says to Peter, now Peter
I know you're full of yourself right now
and you think this and that.
But listen, when you mess up
because I know you're gonna mess up
uh when you can get converted
when when you rethink everything
when you come back to me
strengthen your brothers and sisters because they go through things.
Haven't any of us
since we started our Christian life
haven't some of us gone down a wrong trail?
Is it isn't it true that some of us are not like it once was with the Lord?
We need to get converted.
Not like converted, like we don't know the Lord
but converted like this.
Come back.
So the Lord not only says, Come unto me, all you that labor and heavy laden
I'll give you rest.
Anyone thirsty, let him come and drink of the waters, right?
He not only says that, he says, Come on
once you come back up there in the balcony
once you come back.
It's not like it used to be, come back.
He's got stuff for you to do.
He has people he wants you to bless
but how can you bless them unless you come back?
In other words, come back.
Come back.
Not just come the first time
but after you drift
remember he's always saying, Come back.
And the amazing thing about the Lord I've learned from my own life
and you see it in the Bible
is no matter how many times you stray
he's still saying, Come back.
He never says, Oh
it's gonna be like that?
You're gonna be like that?
Then get out of here
I never want to see you again.
He never does that.
He's always saying, Come back.
Do I get an amen?
Because drifting is a very, very dangerous thing.
You drift, you drift
and the next thing you know
you don't sense his voice anymore.
Your conscience gets hard.
Now you're doing things you never dreamed.
Right?
When uh when Shireen was growing up
you think she'd say, Yeah
one day I'll live with this guy, not my husband, a drug addict
I'll have my kids there, and no
she never thought that's what happened.
Everything is gradual.
When you grow in the Lord, it's gradual.
You don't grow overnight, you grow gradually.
Same thing about drifting.
You drift gradually.
And the next thing you know
you find yourself so far out, so far gone.
Maybe some of you
if you just think back
how was it ten years ago, five years ago?
Or way back when you were a kid
and tender and your heart was virgin
and now the Lord is saying to us, Come, come back.
No, I'm afraid of you.
No, I love you, come back.
You the answer is not there
the answer is here.
Come to me, come back.
So the very last thought in the Bible goes something like this in Revelation.
Just look.
The Spirit and the bride say, Come.
And let the one who hears say, Come.
Let the one who is thirsty come
and let the one who wishes
the one who wishes take from the free gift of the water of life.
So the last thought in the Bible is a double thought of this word come.
It's the coming of the Lord.
The Spirit, Holy Spirit, and the bride, the church, says to the Lord,
Come, even so, come quickly, Lord Jesus.
Come in here looking forward to
when the Lord comes back
and we get out of here.
Maybe you're happy here.
Mazeltov, I am not happy here.
I want to do what God wants me to do
but I would like to get out of here today if it was possible.
Do I get a hand clap of praise from anybody else?
So the Spirit, Holy Spirit, and the bride, the church, says, come.
And then John turns it around.
And anyone, anyone who's thirsty
the one who's thirsty, come.
Let the one who wishes.
Come on, just come to Jesus.
They mocked that today.
They I don't like that.
You hear it uh in politics
you hear in sports, even like, oh
he had a come to Jesus moment.
That means like there was a dramatic moment in his life.
But that that profanes something sacred.
The most beautiful thing that can happen in your life today is to come to Jesus.
And I grew up a little bit like her, Shireen
where it was always you gotta get things in order, then you come.
No, you come the way you are.
But I'm a match.
I don't know why this thought comes to mind
to tell you I have a my late friend David Wilkerson
who founded Teen Challenge.
He was a character.
When you handed him the microphone to Great Man of God
you don't know where what could happen.
What he might say.
So he's in Poland one day
and he was at that time he wasn't pastoring Times Square Church.
We was on trips
and he would we would talk
and have lunch together and
and um have a lot of good discussions.
So one time he was he wouldn't go on a mission trip unless he found some new sermons.
He didn't like to re-preach sermons.
So but he w at with this time in his life
he was reading way too much in the old testament
and not enough in the new
and I would tell him that.
Like, you know, Dave, you're famous.
You know, Jesus loves you
Nikki Cruz gets saved, and all this.
And he was into a lot of this uh prophetic uh old testament bringing out good truths
but you gotta be careful of that
as he found out.
So he was reading in the Old Testament somewhere where it says this.
All the men in Israel the law says you have to come to Jerusalem three times a year.
You have to come to Jerusalem three times a year to worship at a certain holiday.
But don't come empty-handed
it says in the law.
Either Exodus or Deuteronomy, or maybe both.
Don't come empty-handed.
You have an offering.
You bring something.
God's been good to you.
You come with something.
So he told me this himself.
Maybe he's listening.
Certainly, God is listening.
So I'm telling you exactly the way he told it to me.
And I checked because it was so crazy that what he told me
I checked with the translator who was a friend of mine before he knew Brother Dave Wilkerson.
So he's preaching in in in Warsaw, Poland.
And he's preaching this message about you gotta come.
See, God, you know what the problem is with a lot of you
and he's preaching for about fifteen minutes already.
And the problem with a lot of you is you don't bring anything when you come.
You have no offering, you have nothing,
you're selfish, you you this, you're that, but you come
you gotta come with that.
Was the point he was making.
And then as God is listening to me
we were sitting at Snooky
we were sitting in Snooky's restaurant on Seventh Avenue in Brooklyn here.
It used to be a place we ran into a lot.
And uh he said, Jim, I'm preaching
and the Holy Spirit speaks to me and says
Your sermon is totally wrong.
This is happening while he's preaching.
Your sermon's wrong.
Tell the people they don't have to bring anything.
Just come with their mess.
Come with their sin.
Come with their confusion.
They don't need any
I don't want
I don't demand anything.
You just come.
I'll fix things up.
So he's getting this conviction.
So he turns to the translator and he says, Listen, don't be afraid.
Just translate every word I'm gonna say.
So my friend Paul Chestler says yes, and he goes.
Okay, everyone, the Holy Spirit just stop me in this message.
Everything I've said is wrong.
I want you to delete everything in the last 15 minutes.
Here's what God wants you to know.
You don't have to come with anything
you just bring yourself just as I am without one plea
but that thy blood was shed from me.
Oh Lamb of God, I come.
I come just the way I am.
And my friend Tesla Paul told me people started running to the front.
Because God loves us so much
he doesn't say, come with this, come with that,
fix up this, fix up that.
He says, just come
I'll do all the work.
You just come.
Can we praise God for that truth?
So let's close our eyes.
Anyone here just needs to come, maybe to come back.
Or just to come.
Look, look what he says.
What he promises you.
He will not violate your free will.
You can totally turn your back on what I'm saying
and walk out of the church and say
that was a joke.
What was that about?
But if the Holy Spirit is speaking to you
I plead with you, come.
Let us pray for you.
Just come to Jesus.
Not to the church, not to me.
I have no power.
I uh the church is not where the action is.
Jesus is where the action is.
What he did for Sharem.
He won't do it for you.
Well, of course he'll do it for you.
Your situation's different.
But he'll get you out of whatever emptiness you're in
trouble you're in
depression you're in, aimlessness, bitterness, uncleanness.
He'll fix it if you'll just please,
for Christ's sake and your sake, just come.
Anybody want me to pray for them?
Or to come back?
You've drifted?
Can you be honest enough to say, I have drifted?
Instead of growing from glory to glory
I'm I'm going from glory to less glory.
I want to come back.
Whether you come or you come back.
Just stand so I can pray for you.
Just stand.
Stand right where you are.
We're talking good news.
We're talking come to Jesus.
We're talking come back to Jesus.
No, no, no, no.
I know back 20 years ago, 10 years ago
when you were in the Caribbean
or Puerto Rico or Poland or wherever you come from.
It was, oh, you had these sacred memories.
What's that got to do with today?
The Lord is saying, come back.
Come on, come back.
Step forward right to the edge.
If you don't come
he will not violate your free will.
Didn't you say in your word
if we would just come
you would do everything?
Just humble yourself and come.
Admit you need forgiveness.
Admit you need help.
You need cleansing.
You need strength.
You need wisdom.
You need things to be fixed.
I'm standing next to a woman, Lord
who came to you and you turned the world upside down for her to get her out of trouble.
What an awesome God you are.
Folks here in the front
with your eyes closed
just repeat this prayer coming from my heart, my mouth.
But I want you to repeat it
and claim it as your own.
Make it your own.
Talk from your heart.
Dear God.
I'm coming home.
I'm coming to you.
I shouldn't have done it a long time ago.
But now I'm tired.
I'm coming home.
Fix what's broken.
Please what's dirty.
Take away my confusion.
Fill my emptiness.
I'm living, I'm striving, I'm working
I'm saving money
and I'm empty.
Without you.
I'm coming home.
Should have never left.
Thank you for sharing.
And the word of God.
I'm coming home.
I'm gonna rest.
With my hand on your breast.
Encourage me.
You know how hard it's been.
But now I'm whole.
I believe in you, Jesus.
I claim you as my Savior and my Lord.
I believe you are the Son of God.
You died under Pontius Pilate.
But on the third day
you were raised from the dead.
You're alive.
You're here.
You're with me.
You love me.
You're for me.
You're not against me.
That's the good news.
That's why I'm coming home.
Now lift up that right hand.
Just lift that right hand up.
Sing.