Stand with us.
Praise the Lord.
Amen.
Are you ready to lift your voice today in praise?
God is so worthy to be praised today.
Has he been good to you this week?
Has he been faithful to you?
Amen.
Open your heart today.
Let's sing with everything that we have to the audience of one.
The Lord is here today.
He loves you today.
He's with you today.
So let's lift up his name.
He inhabits the praise of his people.
We invite you here today, Jesus.
Hallelujah.
Let's sing it together.
He is exalted.
The king is exalted on high.
I will praise Him.
He is exalted forever, exalted on high.
He is exalted.
He is exalted on high.
I will praise Him.
He is exalted forever, exalted on high.
He is our Lord
forever His truth shall reign.
Heaven and earth rejoice in His holy name.
He is exalted, He is exalted on high.
He is exalted, the King is exalted on high.
I will praise Him
He is exalted forever, exalted on high.
He is exalted, the King is exalted on high.
I will praise Him.
He is exalted, forever exalted.
I will praise His name.
Jesus the Lord.
Rejoice in his holy name.
He is exalted.
The king is exalted on high.
Come on, lift your voices and sing.
He is exalted.
The king is exalted on high.
I will praise him.
He is exalted forever.
Exalted on high.
He is exalted, and He is exalted on high.
I will praise Him.
He is exalted, forever exalted.
I will praise His name.
He is the Lord
and forever His truth shall reign.
Hallelujah!
Come on, sing it again!
He is exalted forever, exalted on high.
He is exalted and he is exalted on high.
Praise his name.
He is the Lord
for ever His truth shall reign.
Heaven and earth rejoice in His holy name.
He is exalted, he is exalted on high.
Oh, he is exalted
he is exalted on high.
I will wear any sin
he is exalted forever, exalted on high.
Come on, lift up their name.
She is insulted.
He is insulted.
I will not praise him.
He is insulted forever.
And I will praise his name.
He is.
Let's rejoice in his calling man.
He is exalted and he is exalted on high.
He is the Lord
forever his truth shall reign.
is is They'll rejoice in his calling name He is exalted
the King is exalted on high He is exalted
and he is exalted on high.
Hallelujah.
Come on, exalt his name.
That's why we're gathered here.
Exalt the name of Jesus in this place.
We worship you, Lord.
We exalt your name, oh God.
Hallelujah.
Blessed be your name, Jesus.
Blessed be your name.
Blessed be your name, Lord.
All of your people worship you today, God.
Receive our praise, Lord.
Receive our praise, Jesus.
Oh, let it be so sweet to you today, God.
We open our hearts to you today.
You deserve all the praise of God.
You have been faithful, Lord.
I love you, Lord.
Your mercy never fails me.
All my days I've been held in your hands.
From the moment that I wake up until I lay my head
I will sing of the goodness of God.
Come on, lift your voice.
All my life you have been faithful.
All my life you have been so, so good.
With every breath that I am able
I will sing of the goodness of God.
I love your voice.
You have led me through the fire In darkness night You are close like no other
I know you as a father I know you as a friend
I have believed In the goodness of God.
Come on, this is our testimony.
All my life you have been faithful.
All my life you have been so, so good.
You can't regret that I am faithful.
I will sing of the goodness of God.
All my life you have been faithful.
All my life you have been so, so good.
With every breath that I am able
I will speak of the goodness of God.
Your goodness is running out.
It's running out of me.
It's running out to me With my life laid down I surrender now I give you everything
Your goodness is running out
It's running out to me Your goodness is running out
It's running out to me
This is running after
it's running after me.
With my life laid down, I surrender now
I give you everything.
Your goodness is running down
It's running down to me With my life vacant
I surrender now I give you everything.
Your goodness is running out.
It's running out to me.
All my life you have been so, so good.
Every breath that I am able
I will sing of the goodness of God.
Come on, sing it again.
All my life.
All my life you have been faithful All my life you have been so
so good With every breath that I am able Come on
as the instruments play
can you just lift your voice
and thank God for all that he's done in your life.
Recount the faithfulness of God today.
Encourage your heart today.
Remember, remember, remember what he's done.
Remember what he's pulled you out of.
Remember what he saved you from.
Remember what he's brought you through.
We thank you, Jesus.
Come on, get down to your place today.
Lift your voice and demonstrate.
Oh, Lord, we thank you.
You have been so good, God.
You have been good.
Oh, you have been good.
Continue to worship me.
Give me the fruit of your life.
Oh, lift your voice and sing.
All your goodness is running out.
It's starting out to be.
It's running after me.
With my life laid down, surrendered now
I give you everything.
Your goodness is running after me.
Lord, when is this coming out?
It's running out to me.
All my life you have been faithful All my life you have been so, so good
But every breath that I am able Thank you, Jesus.
Hallelujah, Lord.
Thank you, Jesus, for every answered prayer, God.
For all of your faithfulness to us, Lord.
We take time, God, to remember.
We take time to consider, Lord
how good you've been to us, Lord.
We shake off discouragement.
We shake off fear and anxiety.
You have been good, Lord.
You have never failed us.
You have never failed us yet, Lord.
So we give you praise.
We give you glory, Lord Jesus.
We worship you, God, today.
You have been good.
You deserve all praise, Lord.
We love you today, God.
Hallelujah, Jesus.
Let's sing this together.
Oh, and great is thy faithfulness.
Oh, love of my Father.
There is no shadow of turning with Thee.
Thou changest not, thy compassions they fail.
Sing it out.
Oh, great is thy faithfulness.
Great is thy faithfulness.
For thee, my heart, ye do worship.
Thank you.
and the peace that endures.
Thy holy presence to cheer and to guide.
Stay for today and my hope for tomorrow.
Come by with ten thousand free stars.
Come on, sing it out.
Great is thy faithfulness.
Morning by morning, you must be at thy seat.
And come on, sing it again.
Oh, praise thy faithfulness.
Thank you.
Come on, just your voices.
Praise thy faithfulness.
Morning by morning, new mercies I see.
Oh, I am deep in thy hand, God, oh, I am.
Amen.
Praise the Lord.
How many of you can say he has been faithful?
Amen.
And he will continue to be.
Hallelujah.
So we can be at peace today in this service.
God is with us.
He is faithful, right?
Amen.
Hello, church.
How many can say the joy of the Lord is my strength?
Amen.
I've got joy in the struggle.
I've got peace in the storm.
I've got strength in the battle
I don't fear anymore.
I'm a child of heaven
my hope is secure.
I've got joy cause I've got Jesus.
He gave me beauty for ashes
he turned my life around.
He broke my chains and now I dance on solid ground.
For all he's done to save me
I will raise my voice.
I've got Jesus
so I've got joy.
Hallelujah, we praise you.
He bore all of my burdens.
Yes, my debt has been paid.
Then he said to my dry bones, rise up out of that grave.
He has all of my worship, all the honor and praise.
Oh, I've got joy because I've got Jesus.
Yeah.
He gave me beauty for ashes He turned my life around He broke my chains
and now I dance on solid ground
For all he's done to save me I will raise my voice I've got Jesus
So I've got Joy like a river Running through my soul
Joy all around me, everywhere I go.
Even in the desert, still it overflows.
Oh, I've got joy.
Yeah, I've got joy.
Glory never-ending, closing all my days.
Every breath I breathe, just a bit of amazing grace.
Oh, hallelujah.
everything has changed oh
For all he's done to save me
I will raise my hopes.
I've got Jesus
so I'm not alone.
You're like the wind
running through my soul.
You're all around me
everywhere that I go.
Even in the dead of night.
Still the old world knows I've got Jesus.
Oh, I've got joy.
Oh, I've got Jesus.
Yes, I have Jesus.
I've got joy.
hallelujah praise his name that joy that is our strength
in the midst of the struggle in the midst of the lies of the enemy
when we're tempted to look left
or right we fix our eyes on jesus
and we say no the joy of the lord is my strength
in this situation the joy of the lord is my strength
and nothing can steal that away Let's praise his name.
Sing it with us if you know it.
Joy like a river.
Running through my soul.
Joy all around me.
Everywhere I go.
Even in the desert.
Still it overflows.
Oh, I've got joy.
Yes, I've got joy.
Joy never ends.
Oh, hallelujah.
Everything comes great.
Oh, I've got joy.
Yeah, I've got joy.
He gave me beauty for ashes.
He turned my life around.
He broke my chains and now I'm there on God's ground.
For all he's done to save me
I will raise my voice.
I've got Jesus.
So I've got you.
Lord, like a river running through my soul
joy all around me, everywhere I go.
Even in the desert
still it all comes close.
I've got Jesus.
So I've got trust.
I've got trust.
Hallelujah!
We praise you, Jesus!
Thank you.
Jesus is all I need.
Oh, when I'm tired and I'm weary.
When I'm on my journey home.
Oh, when the road is rough and long.
I feel so all alone.
And when my strength is all gone.
I can't carry on.
That's when my Jesus is all that I need.
Jesus is all I need.
is all I need.
I need no other friend.
I need no other one.
Jesus is all that I need.
Oh, and when life has let me down
And peace cannot be found
When all my hopes and all my dreams
They lie scattered on the ground
Oh, and my joy Turns to sorrow
and there's no hope for tomorrow.
That's when Jesus is all that I need.
Jesus is all I need.
I need no other friend.
He's all I need.
Oh, is that your testimony today?
Lift up your hands and sing.
He's all I need.
Jesus, He's all I need.
Oh my Jesus
He is all I need that
I We're all gathered here in your presence, Lord
with our hearts open wide.
With lifted hands and with open hearts
we welcome you to abide.
Oh Lord
We need your spirit Your holy spirit
Right now Oh Lord Give us your spirit Your holy spirit
We can't do nothing until you come, dear Lord.
For we are so unworthy to even call your name.
And don't let our coming be in vain.
Give us your Spirit, your Holy Spirit, right now.
Spirit, Spirit of Christ.
On me Oh spirit Spirit Spirit Oh spirit On me Oh fall down
Fall down Fall down Holy Spirit, fall down.
Fall down.
Holy Spirit, fall down.
Fall down Fall down Fall down
We need the Holy Spirit right now.
Spirit of Spirit of Lift your hands.
Close your eyes.
Lord, we love you.
Come in me, God.
Oh, rest on me.
Come on, break me, melt me.
Break me.
If you're hungry for more of the Spirit of God
just stand up where you're sitting and sing break me.
Just stand and sing.
Everyone, sing.
And break.
to live freely with you to live freely with you to live freely with you Lord
there's people standing who are hungry to be used by you.
Will you send them in full-time ministry?
Will they be missionaries?
They have some function in the body of Christ, Lord
and we're hungry to be used by you.
We want to be blessed so we can be a blessing.
We don't want bless just to be blessed.
We want to pass it on.
We want the overflow to go to others, Lord.
So although we have the Holy Spirit
we need the Holy Spirit.
Fill us, Lord.
Fill us.
Move among us.
Tenderize us.
Take away pride and selfishness and get us focused.
on the harvest fields that are ripe, Lord.
Use us all.
We pray this in Jesus' name.
And everyone said, amen.
You may be seated.
Let's thank God for the choir.
Can we put our hands together for the choir?
So remember in your giving
remember in your giving
We have offering baskets out there
but those of you giving online who don't live near here
and we're going to give you more information soon about our prayer.
We're not calling it the prayer band
but it's our prayer team.
It's made up of people who are watching online
who can't get out
or for whatever reason they feel involved here.
But you should find a local church where you are.
But if you want to be part of the prayer team
we're going to give you a way.
A way to, you'll get requests from us and you just pray for
just like the prayer band people pray.
That'll be a good thing.
It's always good for people to pray.
Amen?
Men ought always to pray and never quit, give up.
Men ought always, and women ought to give
because God loves a cheerful giver.
And the truth is
the work of God goes on through the giving of God's people.
Not by millionaires and billionaires.
They can sometimes come and do something special.
But it's the regular giving of God's people
that helps God's work go on all throughout the earth.
How many believe, as the Bible teaches
that everything you have comes from God?
Just lift your hand.
Lift your hand if you believe that.
Everything.
Your clothes?
Your house, your apartment you live in?
The bed you slept in last night?
The food you ate today?
It all came from God.
So we should honor him back with a portion of that.
And I encourage you to do that.
My wife is a giver.
I married a giver.
My mom, my dad was a little bit until he started drinking.
And then he was an alcoholic for 22 years
so he didn't think about giving anything.
He was just out of control.
But I had a mom
no matter what was going on with my dad, she kept giving, tithing.
Oh my goodness, what an example she was to me
and my older brother and my younger sister.
So be an example, be a giver
and you'll get happy.
Oh, you're trying to psych us.
No, no, I'm quoting the Bible.
It is more blessed to receive.
You know why a lot of people are depressed?
They don't give anything.
They're cheaper than a crab.
They're tighter than a crab or whatever that saying is.
But when you give
it frees you up.
You can have the joy of the Lord.
Amen.
So please, as you leave or as you give online, help us.
So today we were blessed this morning.
I just want to honor him.
Speaking for us this morning was a dear friend and his wife, my wife and I
, Pastor Ken Witten and Ginny, his wife.
They live in Florida, and on March 10, 2020, uh carol
and i went down for five days ostensibly to stay in florida real quick
we got a call the next day do not move don't get on an airplane
covet has hit big time they're shutting everything down the church can't meet publicly shutting the offices down
schools down
everything's down people are being brought to hospitals ventilators you know that nightmare we went through
so i was in florida the the pastors
and the board called me stay
where you are Stay in place.
For how long?
No one knows.
You remember back then, right?
No one knew what was going to happen.
So my friend, Ken Witten, who I knew
called me that next day.
And after they had talked to me and said
what are you going to do, Jim?
I hear you're here in Florida.
I said, yeah, I'm stuck.
I don't know how long
and what we're going to do.
So he said, no, listen
you got to keep your Sunday services
even though you're not open.
So take my auditorium, a massive auditorium
and I'll give you my videography team, more important.
And you come during the morning day
and then you let them tape you
and you preach a sermon for the church to be played on Sunday.
Then my wife took and gathered worship songs
and worship times from previous meetings.
So every Sunday for 16 months.
We were shut for 16 months.
How many remember that?
Anyone remember?
16 months.
And it was all made possible by that.
But he did more.
He was prophetic.
He said, I have a feeling New York's going to need this more than just a Sunday.
What you should do is
after you tape your sermon
go up to this other studio we have.
Same three, four guys.
These are professional videographers.
And do some daily devotions.
You know, seven, eight minutes long.
And just try to stay in front of the people every day.
It's going to be hard up there, Jim.
And I was like
thank you so much.
So it started.
It went on for 16 months.
It continued since I've come back.
Because now there's a following
and people watching from around the country and the world.
And now, as I tape five more this week
I'll have hit the milestone.
I've done 1,500 daily devotions.
And we thank God just for his faithfulness.
So it all started with Pastor Ken Whitten
that church where he was pastoring then.
And you think he would take any money?
Nope.
I tried every angle.
No, let us give you.
No, no, no, no, Jim, Jim, Jim, Jim.
It's our donation.
It's our gift.
Someone has said to me what he gave you in labor and in services.
at least $250,000, $400,000.
Because when you make videos
you have to pay people big money, right?
And he preached this morning with such a blessing.
And Pastor Ken and Jenny
would you just stand up?
I want the church to give you the loudest welcome.
Come on.
Come on, let them hear it!
Brooklyn!
So let's go back.
So while I'm in Florida there
they have more religious channels than we have.
And my wife and I are watching NRB, the National Religious Broadcasters Network.
And there's a guy preaching
and it says Pacific Garden Mission, Chicago, downtown.
Any of you familiar here with the Bowery Mission?
The Bowery, okay.
So you have street people, people hurting, people very transient.
And there's this guy.
I liked him immediately when I saw his name, Kwiatkowski.
That's Polish.
I'm half Polish.
Our people have to stay together
the few of us that are left.
But my goodness, my wife said, Jim, listen to that.
That's such a good word.
Am I right, Carol?
She said, why don't you try to contact him?
Would he ever come to Brooklyn?
I said, I don't know.
Then I saw him again.
Then I saw him another time.
And every time he blessed me.
So I got the courage up to reach out
because I'm shy to call people I don't know.
And I called him.
We finally connected.
I said, would you come on a Sunday
and feed the people the word of God?
And I don't know how long he's been down doing that down in Chicago.
But he is going to give us, like this morning
how many want spiritual steak, potatoes, gravy?
Come on, how many want a good meal?
Put your hands together loud for my friend, Pastor Philip Kwiatkowski.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Well, praise God.
What a blessing.
How many people are familiar with the Pacific Garden Mission?
Anybody in here?
Amen.
Let's hear an amen for PGM.
How about Radio Unshackled?
Well, that's at Pacific Garden Mission.
We still tape it live every Saturday at 3 o'clock.
A live audience has come.
And those are stories of lives that have been changed by the gospel of Jesus Christ.
So it's an amazing ministry.
And I'm here with my wife of almost 38 years.
Ann, stand up if you would.
Ann, come on.
I met her when we were students at Moody Bible Institute in 1987.
I met her in, I think, March of 87.
I married her in December of 87.
I said, she's so pretty
I can't let her change her mind
so we did it quick.
And here we are, four kids, and 38 years later.
Let's go ahead and look to the Lord in prayer
and then we'll get into the Word.
Father, thank you for this opportunity to be here.
And I pray, God
as we open up your Word
We are not here to hear from Phil or any man.
We want to hear from you.
There's people in this building this morning that need to hear from you.
Jesus, may you be glorified in all that's spoken
I pray in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Years ago, I was sitting in a board meeting at the Pacific Garden Mission
and we were gathered around a table
and suddenly water began to drip down on the table that we were seated at.
Oh, we didn't know what was going on
so we ran upstairs and there was an old mail room up there.
And one of the sinks, slop sinks
was overflowing and the faucet was running.
But the guy that was there monitoring the mail room
he had a mop bucket out.
He was mopping up the water.
But somebody said to him
why don't you turn the faucet off, man?
That always stuck with me.
Because I think of what we do
and I think there's so many of us
That we spend our life with a mop bucket.
We go relationship to relationship.
We go to this church to that church.
This job to that job.
We go to this podcast to the other.
We're always looking for answers
but we never really deal with the heart of the issue.
You know, when I first came to the Pacific Guard Admission
I was a young man
as I said at the time.
Out of Moody Bible Institute
1988 is when I came.
And to me, the answers were so much more simplistic.
My wife and myself did a lot of street ministry.
We'd go around and witness on the street and share the gospel.
And I came to the mission.
That was a great joy.
But when I got there
and saw the lives of the men and women
my eyes were opened up.
Because it was so much deeper than just seeing people come to Jesus.
And hear me this morning.
It's not just about getting saved.
There's many people in here.
You've made decisions to accept Christ.
You've repented of your sin.
You've accepted Jesus as your Savior.
But man, you struggle.
You struggle with issues in your life.
And maybe on the outside you look great
and you know how to smile and play the game
and you can do everything the right way.
But inside, internally, you are absolutely crying out because you are struggling.
Why do I do the things that I do?
And I saw men and women that were like that.
I saw people come out of jail and penitentiary.
People that were living in the streets
and struggling with cocaine or heroin addiction and now fentanyl.
I've seen so many overdoses.
We have Narcon and have to train our staff on how to administer Narcon and all these things.
But when you scrape away all the issues
and get down to the core, hear me
there's a hurting person.
I had a driver one time who was telling me
and this guy was just struggling and he was always angry.
And it's a phrase that many of us heard
but when he said it to me
it just spoke to me.
He said, Pastor, hurting people hurt people.
And I always remember that.
Hurting people hurt people.
What do you do?
I remember years ago
there was a man by the name of Thomas.
He came to us and he was on drugs and incarcerated.
He had tattoos all over his body.
In the story he told me, He said
my father gave me heroin
when I was two years old to shut me up from crying.
How do you process that?
What do you say?
Praise God, let's sing this hymn today.
This is a great song.
What do you tell somebody that tells you something like that?
One of our counselors came to me out of the day room
and he said there was a man in the day room and he showed the counselor
he said his mother dipped him in boiling water as a child.
He had scars from his waist down.
And he's sitting in a homeless shelter
and there he is and the world is going by him.
It's not just, you know
get yourself up by your bootstraps, buddy, and just go get a job and stuff.
He is trying to process the pain.
You know, that's a phrase I've heard from so many people.
I use drugs.
Because I'm trying to dull the pain.
So this morning as we're here
I want all of us
and we are in church, praise God.
We are where God wants us to be.
Maybe somebody brought you and maybe you have to be here, whatever it is.
But I want you to listen
because I believe God wants to say something to you.
And some of us this morning
we don't know why we do the things that we do.
Outwardly speaking, we might look great
say the right words, do the right things.
There's a story of a man I want to look at tonight or this afternoon.
His man's name is Ahithophel.
Ahithophel was a successful man.
He was a man that people probably wanted to emulate.
A man that was a counselor to the kings.
From all outward trappings
this man was a success.
But inside of him
he had something going on.
Some unresolved issue that he never dealt with.
He did not know how to process the pain.
And so though he lived his life
he really didn't know how to do it or how to handle it.
What happened to Hippothel?
Well, one day he went home.
And he hung himself.
Now let me read this to you from 2 Samuel 17, 23.
When Ahithophel saw that his counsel was not followed
he saddled his ass and rose
and he went to his house, to his city
and put his household in order
and hanged himself and died
and was buried in the sepulcher of his father.
Could you imagine if you were in Israel at the time
and The whispers that people would say
what in the world happened to a hippophile?
Listen to what the Bible says about a hippophile when he would counsel people.
The Bible says in 2 Samuel 16, 23, In the counsel of a hippophile
which he counseled in those days
was as if a man inquired at the oracle of God.
So was all the counsel of Ahithophel, both with David and with Absalom.
And Ahithophel was the king's counselor.
You talk about a position of prestige
and honor and dignity for you to be the counselor to the king.
Oh, I'm sure when that man walked into family gatherings
he was met with much fanfare.
Here comes Ahithophel, counselor to the king.
You know who I am, all right?
There he is.
But what in the world happened
where this man got so desperate
that he hung himself and took his own life?
Well, Ahithophel made some interesting decisions
and let me read this to you.
2 Samuel 15, verse 12.
And Absalom sent for Ahithophel
and some of you know the Bible story.
King David's son Absalom wanted to have a coup
and take over the throne from his father.
So he gathered together a bunch of individuals that went to Jerusalem and David had to flee.
So when Ahithophel wanted to know what to do
what is the course of action he should take?
What person do you think
that he called and asked advice?
Ahithophel.
Man, that guy's smart.
That guy knows his stuff.
So it says here
and this is Absalom sent for Ahithophel, the Gileadite
, David's counselor from his city, even from Gilo
while he offered sacrifices.
And the conspiracy was strong for the people increased continually with Absalom.
And one told David, saying
Ahithophel is among the conspirators with Absalom.
And David was shocked.
David, this is your guy.
Your guy, Ahithophel, now he's supporting your son.
And I'm sure the news struck David's heart.
What in the world?
This was my guy.
This was the guy that I was with that I sought his advice and counsel from.
And now he is with my son
and he's gathering together and giving counsel against me.
And listen to his counsel here.
Terrible, terrible stuff.
2 Samuel 16, 15.
And Absalom and all the people, the men of Israel
came to Jerusalem and Ahithophel with him.
Then Absalom said to Ahithophel
give counsel among you what we shall do.
Absalom says to him
what shall we do?
What counsel do you advise?
What course of action shall I take?
And Ahithophel said to Absalom
Go and unto thy father's concubines
which he hath left to keep the house.
And all Israel shall hear
that you are abhorred of your father.
Then all the hands that are with you shall be strong.
Go ahead and violate David's wives.
I mean, where did this advice come from?
You are not only doing this to David
a man that you serve
you are ruining the lives of these women.
But not only that, moreover
Ahithophel said to Absalom
and listen to this
let me now choose out 12,000 men
and I will arise and pursue after David this night.
And I will come upon him while he is weary and weak-handed
and I will make him afraid.
And all the people that are with him shall flee
and I will kill the king only.
I mean, think about that.
You're a counselor.
Your advice is you personally want to go out with a group of men
and you personally want to kill the king.
Seems like there's another dynamic going on here.
As I said earlier, this man
from all outward trappings
seemed to have it all.
But inside of him there was something going on.
Some of us, again
as I said earlier, outside, we look good.
We can say the right thing
do the right thing
but inside of us
things that we have never told some of our closest friends
that we have never confided in anybody about, Man
we are struggling with
and I don't know how to process the pain.
That was happening with him.
How do you know that?
What happened to Ahithophel?
Why did he do this?
Let me read you from 2 Samuel 11, verse 3.
And David sent and inquired after the woman, this is Bathsheba.
And someone said, is this not this Bathsheba, the daughter of Iliam?
the wife of Uriah the Hittite.
So Bathsheba's father's name was Iliam.
Well, let me look at 2 Samuel 23-34.
And Iliam, the son of Ahithophel.
Bathsheba was Ahithophel's granddaughter.
And I believe when that issue happened to Bathsheba
that's something that a hippophile never forgot.
He didn't know how to process it.
He had my grandson-in-law murdered coldly, brutally.
He took my granddaughter and he violated her
and he busted up this relationship.
And then he took her to himself into the home.
And that's something that he never knew how to process.
And for years, I'm sure he struggled with it.
He went to bed with it.
He thought about it.
And finally, when the time arose.
When Absalom rose up and says
I'm going to defeat David, Hippothel said
you count me in.
Matter of fact, you go ahead and violate his wives as he violated my granddaughter.
Matter of fact, when you send somebody to kill him
I'm the one that's going to go out there.
Let me slay King David.
And then all of a sudden
when those things didn't work out
he didn't know what to do.
So he hung himself.
And he died.
What in the world happened to this man?
He was bitter, angry, and frustrated.
Hear me tonight, or this morning.
I usually preach at night at the mission
so I say night.
But there's a lot of us here this morning that are struggling with issues in our life
and there is a distinction between salvation.
We've made the decision to accept Jesus Christ.
Maybe there's some here that have not done that
and I would encourage you to do that
because that's where it starts.
It's not about religion or church.
It's about you coming to Jesus Christ.
But if you've done that, still inside now
it's the process of growth.
What do I do with certain events that have transpired in the past?
Now listen to this.
Matthew 18 is a tremendous story.
We won't read the whole story.
About a man that was forgiven much
but he held a grudge against somebody else.
Listen to this quickly.
Matthew 18, 32.
Then his master, after he had called him, said to him, Oh, you wicked servant
I forgave all the debt because you desired me.
Shouldest not thou had also compassion on your fellow servants
even as I had pity on you?
And his Lord was angry
and delivered him to the tormentors
till he should pay all that was due him.
So likewise shall my heavenly Father do also unto you
if ye from your hearts forgive not every one his brother their trespasses.
Powerful!
If you, and it doesn't, again
when we talk about forgiveness
and we're going to deal with this in a moment
forgiveness is not about you jumping down
and singing kumbaya with somebody that hurt you.
It's not holding their hand like pretending something never happened.
It did happen.
There's things that have happened in this room to people that is incredibly painful.
One of our workers upstairs told me, it's either, she said, 95% or 100%
of our women at the shelter have been abused in some form or fashion.
And there they are at a shelter trying to process having their innocence taken
their personhood violated by somebody they trusted and they held so dear.
Trying to make sense of a world that fell apart around them.
And the question is
what do you do?
And Jesus comes along and says
you need to forgive people from your
what does it say?
Heart.
Because if you don't
it says you'll be handed over to the tormentors.
See, I like when you talk back, amen?
I don't believe if you're born again you lose your salvation
but I believe what that is
if we live a life of unforgiveness, plainly speaking
If we have not resolved some of those issues that have happened to us
there's going to be consequences.
If we have never learned how to process the pain, dull the emotion, deal with the situation.
If we walk away
I can't stand that person.
And all of us know people like that.
When you hear uncle such
and such is coming to the Christmas party.
thoughts about this guy.
Class reunion, I can't stand that guy.
I just don't like them.
Let's just be honest.
And some of us can dredge up memories of things that transpired and we struggle with it.
But hear me, there are consequences.
And Jesus said you'll be handed over to the tormentors.
There's consequences to not forgiving.
Quickly, some of the tormentors might be relational.
I think if a man say I love God and hates his brother
he's a liar.
For he that loves his brother whom he has seen
how can he love God whom he has not seen?
So relationally, I'm going to struggle.
If I can't stand somebody else
how can I say I love a God that I've never seen?
So maybe the issue
like the illustration that I talked about when we opened up
you're mopping up relationships with a bucket.
Man, I'm on my... Third marriage.
You know, I can't keep a relationship straight.
Person to person.
And we're looking for answers
but the answer is not in the mop bucket.
It's going to the source.
Maybe those are some of the tormentors
and the reason that I am doing what I am doing
that God wants me to deal with today.
Not only relational, emotional.
Check this out.
Ephesians 4.31.
Let all bitterness.
It's powerful.
Bitterness, I believe, is the main river from
which the rest of these tributaries flow from.
Let all bitterness and wrath and anger
and anger is interesting.
There's people in here this morning
we struggle with anger.
There's a guy I'd known from the mission
and he said when he first got married, and hear this advice.
Him and his wife got into it one day
and he looked at his wife and he said
you make me so angry.
Anybody ever hear that before?
It's your fault.
You make me angry.
And she calmly looked at him and said
I don't make you angry.
She said, you are angry.
You've been angry your whole life.
That didn't make him angrier.
You'd think that it would.
But he went and thought about it.
He said, you're right.
I'm angry because of my lot in life.
I'm angry because of what happened in my family.
And he lists all these
I'm just angry at this and angry at that.
And maybe some of us this morning, you say
this person makes me angry.
This situation makes me angry.
This boss is no good.
I can't stand all this stuff.
And maybe it's not all this stuff that makes you angry.
I have to ask the question instead of mopping all this stuff, go to the source and say
why am I angry?
And that's what the Bible says.
Let all bitterness and wrath
and anger And loudness and evil speaking be put away from you with all malice.
And I love God's remedy.
Be kind one to another, tenderhearted for forgiving one another.
See, when we look at this mop bucket
we try to take medication.
We go to therapy.
We go to all these different things
but we never really get to the source
because all of a sudden when the medication wears off
All of a sudden
we are still there with the problems that we always had
and God wants us to get to the source.
And he says, emotionally.
There's people you've struggled with your emotions, relationally,
personally, vocationally, in every area of your life
and you wonder why.
And so you get a mop bucket out.
If I just listen to this podcast
if I just buy this book
if I just take this drug over here.
And some of us
we like to go ahead
and maybe we dull ourselves with drugs that we shouldn't be using.
Why do I do what I do?
The answer there is forgiveness.
That's what Jesus said.
And he says, not only that, it's spiritually.
Mark 11, 25, and when you stand praying
forgive if you have anything against any
that your Father which is in heaven may forgive you your sins.
So what are the tormentors?
I believe the tormentors are relational, emotional, spiritual
maybe there's other ones.
And there's some of us in here this morning
those are the things we struggle with.
Man, Christmas is coming, Thanksgiving is coming.
I don't want to be at my family party.
I don't want to be around people.
That uncle's loud.
I don't want to do this over here, that.
And we just struggle with stuff.
And we're wondering, God
what's the answer?
Could it be something transpired
that you yet have never processed?
And here's the heart of
where I want to go this morning.
Ephesians 4, 26.
Listen to this.
Be ye angry and what?
So it tells me anger is normal.
I mean, as Christians
let's not pretend.
We drive, we get angry, amen?
I mean, anger happens.
And some of us have been angry at what happened to us.
You were violated.
Your innocence was stolen.
Your parent maybe picked your sibling as their favorite.
You were overlooked.
Injustice happened to you.
There's real situations that happen in your life
and you were angry.
You were mad.
What do you do?
It says, be angry and what?
Sin not, but hear.
Let not the sun go down upon your wrath.
It tells me there should be a completion date to anger.
And that's the problem.
Some of us went to bed angry.
Don't let the sun go down upon your wrath.
But when we let the sun go down upon our wrath
what do we begin to do?
We begin to nurse it.
Man, we think it over in our mind.
I can't stand that person.
Why'd they do that to me?
I'll never go around that person again.
I'll never trust them again.
And we rehearse it.
So we go to bed angry.
And then the next verse says, neither give place to where?
To where?
So if you go to bed angry, scripturally speaking
you are giving place to who?
Now the word place means a spot, location, position, home, a room.
Think about that.
You are giving the enemy a room.
Inside, you are ceding ground to the enemy.
That violation that happened to you
that you don't know how to process
that you're trying to mop up your whole life, running everywhere to and fro looking for answers
and now that you've given the devil a place
and then I think of 2 Corinthians 10, 4
for the weapons of our warfare are not carnal,
but mighty through God to the pulling down of strongholds.
That's ground you've ceded to the enemy.
How did you cede ground to the enemy?
By going to bed, what?
Angry.
And you gave him a place.
And now he operates out of that place.
And all these things come from it.
Relationships, addiction, drug, promiscuity, and all these things.
And I'm saying this to you this morning
because as I talk to people every day
that's what I've seen.
There was a guy a number of years ago.
His name was Michael.
Incredibly talented pianist.
Classically trained.
Unbelievable.
But man, he could never get it right.
In the mission, out of the mission.
On drugs, off drugs.
Same old thing.
And I finally asked him about his background and he said, well, what happened?
He was raised by his mother initially
and then his mother had a new boyfriend.
So the boyfriend gave the mother an ultimatum.
It's either him or me.
And the mother chose the boyfriend.
And he said, now my auntie raised me.
And my auntie was kind of like a Cruella de Vil
and she was mean and overbearing.
She'd make me play the piano day and night.
I'd look out of the window
and see all the other kids playing football and basketball.
But I was never allowed to go with the other boys.
I was forced to sit into this room to play piano.
And now at the time
he was an older man.
He's still asking questions about his childhood.
Why in the world did my mother choose the boyfriend over me?
And you look at his life from outward, like a hippophile, a success.
What's wrong with you?
You're articulate.
You're smart.
You have a skill.
You're a great piano player.
Why can't you ever get it together?
You can mop it up by going to a drug treatment program, going to this program
talking to this counselor, doing this.
You need to get to the source.
And the source, I need to process what happened to me.
And I need, by the grace of God, learn how to forgive.
That's what happens there.
I think of Hebrews 12, 15.
The Bible says, looking diligently
lest any man fail of the grace of God, lest any root of bitterness spring up trouble you
thereby many are defiled.
Hallelujah.
Think about that.
Bitterness defiles people.
And so how does bitterness happen?
You go to bed angry.
They give the devil a place.
This place becomes a grudge.
This grudge becomes unforgiveness.
Unforgiveness becomes bitterness.
And now I'm bitter and I just hate everything.
Do you ever meet people that just hate everything?
Not nice people to hang around with.
That's no good.
That stinks.
It's too hot.
It's too cold.
It's no good.
And just bitter.
No matter what you talk about.
They're just bitter people.
And bitterness defiles you.
And that's where it has its source.
Somebody once says unforgiveness.
is like drinking poison and waiting for the other person to die.
Think about that.
Some of you can't stand somebody for what they've done to you
but they've moved on with their life.
And you are seated here dealing with the consequences of their filthy, vile actions.
And I want to tell you this morning
by the grace of God
it is time for you to move on.
They've already violated you once.
They shouldn't do it a second time.
Real quick, I asked some of our folks in our drug program before I came here last week
and I asked about forgiveness.
This one says, I had a problem with forgiving
because of what was done to me at the time from this person.
I was constantly in misery.
Why are you miserable?
You need to get a happy space, a time out
go to the fun zone
whatever you want to do.
No.
The reason I'm miserable is
because of what somebody has done to me.
And they sit today in Chicago on a drug program trying to process the pain.
Somebody else wrote down
I had a very hard time forgiving my father who was abusive.
He was an alcoholic and abused my siblings.
And I frequently, physically, all the time and verbally.
And he says, it stole my joy for years.
Somebody else says, I still have a lot of work to do.
The emotions are powerful.
I need a lot of help.
The pain runs dry
deeper than I can control.
Listen to this.
The pain gives power to my addiction.
And as I read that
I was thinking about that.
How many of us in here
does the pain that we have been through
Really give what we're struggling with the power to have mastery over us?
You know, so again
when we deal with this topic of forgiveness
and bitterness as we wind up
forgiveness is not a feeling.
You're not going to feel warm fuzzies about a certain person.
Yay!
There's no yay.
Forgiveness does not mean pretending you were not hurt.
You were hurt.
You were violated.
What was done to you was wrong.
The hurt was real.
The pain exists.
And it happened.
Forgiveness is not condoning what they did.
It doesn't mean when you forgive
that it means everything is okay.
Somehow that they get a free pass.
They don't.
Forgiveness does not mean reconciliation.
Joseph did not reconcile with his brothers.
Read that story in the book of Genesis later on.
Great story.
It's a whole other sermon.
We're not going there.
But think about this.
Joseph sold into slavery by his own brothers.
They come back to visit him and Joseph sees them.
He doesn't run down and say, Kumbaya.
Hey, guys, all good now.
I'm second to Pharaoh.
Hey, look at my chariot.
Well, now he has go back.
It's Benjamin.
And he singles out Benjamin and he singles him out.
He recreates what happened to him.
My friend, as we're closing
I want to give an illustration to you as we close.
When I think of the whole story of forgiveness.
In South America, there's a group of individuals that want to catch these monkeys.
And what they do is they have these canisters.
And they put these candies
and treats on the bottom of these canisters.
So when the monkeys put the hands down and grab the treats
they can't get their hand back up again.
They're caught.
Everything would change if they simply did what?
What?
Everybody, let's say it together.
Let it go.
And there's some of us here this morning
the devil has had a field day with you.
Relationally, emotionally, spiritually, you are struggling because you are violated
you are in pain
you don't know how to process the pain
and you sit here this morning.
It's not another therapy session you need.
It's not another podcast that you need.
What you need to do, plain and simple this morning, is hallelujah, let it go!
It is time.
God maybe brought you here this morning for you to hear that.
You've been in pain long enough.
You've rehearsed that long enough.
This morning you need to let it go.
Let's have every head bowed
and every eye closed as we close the service.
Every head bowed.
Maybe as you're here this morning
and the prayer counselors are going to come down
Maybe you've never accepted Jesus Christ as your personal Savior.
Somebody brought you to church and you said
I've been in pain.
You need forgiveness.
I'm not saying join a church.
It's not good people that go to heaven
and bad people that go to hell.
It's forgiven people.
It's sinners that cry out to a holy Savior.
Say, Pastor, this morning
I need to be forgiven.
I need Jesus.
Raise up your hand all through the auditorium.
I need to be born again.
I need to be saved.
A number of hands.
Hallelujah.
Maybe that's why you're here.
You've been trying to process the pain.
And the answer is as simple as Jesus.
Those of you with your hands raised
I want you to pray with me in the quietness of your heart.
Say, Dear God, I know that I am a sinner.
I believe Jesus Christ died for my sin.
And this morning I repent of my sin
and I accept Jesus Christ as my Savior.
In Jesus' name, Amen.
We're going to sing a closing hymn.
It's called Just As I Am.
It's a hymn that I always close
when I close a service at the mission.
But if you're here
why don't we all stand
and we'll sing this together.
The front is open here.
Again, hear me this morning.
So we just don't play church.
We walk out the door.
Some of you were spoken to this morning.
You know who you are.
God spoke to your heart.
You need to let it go.
And as we sing this song
just as I am
Why don't you come down here, pray with somebody, come to the altar.
This is your time.
The devil has had a field day with you.
And what you need to do, let it go.
So why don't you come on down, let's sing.
Why don't you come down today?
Come on down, come on down.
You know God has spoken to your heart this morning.
Hallelujah, hallelujah.
It is time this morning, hallelujah.
Come on down, come on down.
You've lived with the pain for too long.
You don't know how to process what happened to you.
You struggle.
I want to tell you there's a God who loves you.
There's a Savior who shed His blood for you.
Hallelujah.
Come on down.
Anybody else tonight?
Just as I am, day and night.
Maybe some of the balcony
maybe you're wrestling with it.
Why don't you come to Jesus today?
Come on down, come on down.
My soul, I want my life to be.
Come on, others coming down.
I'm going to have a prayer for everybody after the word.
And I want you to come if there's others who are struggling.
This is your moment.
This is your time.
You've held on to it too long.
Time to let it go.
Let it go.
I come, I come.
Let me pray for those that are down here.
When I look at those that are here
there's a lot of pain that's here.
There's a lot of uncertainty.
But I want to tell you this morning
there's a Savior that can heal.
Let the healing process begin today.
It might not be instantaneous
but you took the first step.
Let me pray.
Father, I pray for every man
and woman that's before me.
God, you know their hearts and you know what they've been through.
You know the healing that they need.
And I pray tonight that you would give them the supernatural strength
to go to bed for the first time in years not angry with that issue gone.
Because you told us from our hearts to forgive.
You know the issues, pain.
Bless those.
Guide those.
Give them your strength.
I pray for each and every one.
In Jesus' name I pray.
Amen, amen, and amen.
Amen, Pastor.
You know what?
That hymn is so beautiful, isn't it?
Just as I am.
Did you hear those words?
Go to the first verse.
Let's close the meeting by singing that hymn.
Listen.
As I am, without one plea, no excuses.
I've been wrong
but that thy blood was shed for me.
That's my only hope
is what you can do for me
not what I can do for you.
Let's sing it in closing, shall we?
Amen?
Here we go, sing.
Just as I am without one plea
but that Thy blood
it was shed on me
and that Thy I come to thee
O Lamb of God, I come, I come.
Lord, we ask for all of us
especially here in the front
give us today the spirit of a lamb.
We follow Jesus, who was the Lamb of God.
Not angry, not yelling, not screaming, not holding on to stuff.
He even prayed, Lord
you prayed for those who crucified you.
We cannot do that.
You have to give us the grace to do that.
But we let it go today in Jesus' name.
We're not going to let those tormentors torment us again.
It's in your hands now, God.
Thank you for everyone who's here.
Thank you for everything that's happened.
Thank you for Pastor Phillip being here and being such a blessing.
You've given us a beautiful day, those little babies.
Just bless the offering now, the fellowship with the 40s, the downstairs with the first timers.
Just give us a beautiful end
we pray in Jesus' name.
And everyone said, turn around and hug somebody.
Give someone a hug and a handshake.
My choir is going to sing one more time.