Thank you for every person, God, in this building right now, Lord.
Thank you for bringing us together, God.
Lord, we pray this would be a blessed time, God
meeting in your name, Lord.
And we invite your presence into this place, Jesus.
We glorify your name this morning, God.
Be exalted in this place, Jesus.
Come on, lift your voice and sing it.
He is exalted, he is exalted on high.
I will pray.
I will pray him.
He is exalted forever
exalted I will pray.
Forever is true, shall we ever we thought his holy death
He is exposed and he is faulting on high Come on sing again?
He is exalted and he is exhausted on eye.
I will say him
he is exalting forever, exalting on eye.
He is exalted and she is taught him on eye.
I will praise him
he is exalting forever
causing his eye room, raising the Lord forever to share.
And I will say, forever
it's called him on eye.
Come on, sing it to the Lord!
He is exposing, he is exposed from heart Our Christian
he is exposed forever, exposing on heart.
He is explosive and he is exposing on heart.
Our grace he is exhausted forever.
He is closing, he is exclusive
He is a long time
the kids exult the king is insulting.
Amen.
Bless the Lord this morning, amen.
We exalt you, Jesus.
We exalt you, Lord.
Hallelujah.
We gather here to lift up your name, Jesus.
We don't want to spectate, oh God.
We want to enter into worship of the King of Kings and the Lord of Lords
the one who reigns on high.
We bless your name, God.
We don't spectate, Lord.
We enter in, God
we join our voices with the redeemed today, Lord.
And we bless your name.
We lift up the name of Jesus.
We glorify the Lord.
You are worthy to be praised, O God.
There is no one worthy without God.
Hallelujah, Jesus.
We open our hearts to you today, Lord.
Receive our worship today, God.
Let's sing that verse together.
You love me.
You deserve the glory.
Come on, sis again.
You are you of early up in the world for time you are of me
and to you are of east you deserve.
And she walked me.
And to you are peace, you deserve me.
And to you are of peace to deserve the blood Jesus.
We give you praise.
You are Jesus.
We bless you.
Come on, lift your price.
Lift your hands and sing with me.
It just dawned on me
sit standing over there and singing with you
that the shepherds came the night Jesus was born and they worshiped him.
He hadn't died yet for one of them.
He was just a baby.
And they exalted him and they praised.
The wise men came sometime later.
They brought gold, frankincense, and myrrh
and they laid it down there before the baby.
He hadn't died on a cross yet.
He hadn't shed his blood.
He hadn't done everything that he's already done for us.
They didn't know salvation.
They were never born again like we are.
And if they praise God like that
how ought we to praise God this morning?
No, I mean really.
Can we put our hands together?
How ought we to praise God?
I don't know how many wise men we have.
I think we have a lot, but at least all the men.
Come up out of your seat.
All the wise men, come on up.
Come on, every man on the blower level.
Come on down.
You want to come down from the balcony?
We saw.
And we so be Come on, men, stay.
And we saw Come on, men, say Jesus
lift your hands and your voice sing, and we Yes, we just the man, just the man
every man in the building say We Come on, man, just the man.
We saw Jesus, we exalted Lord.
We have everyone now, ladies.
Open your mouth, men
and praise him out loud.
Come on.
They gave both frankincense in her.
He doesn't need that.
He needs your voice today in your heart.
We praise you, Lord.
We bow before you, Lord.
Our hearts bow before you, Lord.
We bless your name, Lord.
We pray.
We're not embarrassed.
We're not ashamed to praise you.
We don't care who's looking at us.
We praise the King of Kings and the Lord of Lords.
Just the men, let's sing.
Come on, men.
Amen.
That's all God.
We bless you.
Jesus shut rejoicing.
Now let us see.
Let's live on them before the king.
Come let us come before him.
Now let us pray.
Let's give all God to the stay.
Some let us shout before me.
Now let us see.
Let's be darkness before me.
Now let us play.
Let's give up for you.
It's stronger than darkness and do everyone.
Our sins they are many.
His mercy is able.
How many are thankful today?
Hallelujah.
Well love could remember the wrongs we have.
Homies home only He counts not this thrown into the sea without bottom or so there are many.
His mercy is oh praise the Lord
his mercy is on the darkness into everyone as his day already
his mercy with ancients we wait as we constantly wrong.
What father soul center is calling us all she will come to east the violence the poor many his mercy
so goodness is mercy is mercy is more His mercy is so much more My riches of kindness
He lavishes His blood was the fate His life was the cost we could be dead
We could never A stay to Bang His Mercy
I begin His Mercy is more six Day I'm getting His Mercy
You have my soul You have honor Your Less Jesus
You have filled me with your wheel as my last name I've I say amen to that.
Amen.
And now we want to mention the offering.
Would you please help us?
Usually, as you know, at Christmas time.
Oddly, churches suffer in their giving
because people are buying presents
and paying off credit cards and running around spending money
and that's all good.
Do as you feel led
but we can't forget Jesus at Christmas.
Is the microphone on or no?
You turned it off again.
We can't forget Jesus at Christmas time.
That would be bad.
So his work, his kingdom.
And um we're helping other people who are presenting the gospel in different parts of the world.
So your giving makes so many things possible.
We have extra expenses here with the Christmas show
but um God's gonna help us.
We're gonna see great fruit from this.
We want to harvest.
We're praying and join with me this Tuesday.
The most important service of all uh this week will be the prayer meeting.
We're gonna pray, God, God
send the Holy Spirit and embolden us, draw people in
help us to witness so
that your name might be praised.
Amen.
Let's just pray for a moment, Lord.
Help us to be filled with faith
and liberality that comes from you naturally.
We're not full of faith just by ourselves
we're not liberal.
But you can put that in our heart, Lord
to make us joyful, happy givers.
For you love someone who gives with a joyful spirit.
Help us to copy you.
You, Father, gave your son.
Help us this Christmas not to forget that and be givers.
And we know you will take care of everything we need as we honor you with our substance.
And we acknowledge today everything we have comes from you.
Everything, all our clothes, all our money, our jobs, our house, our apartment
everything comes from you.
It's a blessing.
So we share with you this Christmas season.
Amen.
Well, today is good news Sunday.
And oh, do we have someone that you want to listen to?
I know more about this person than most people get up here and uh speak
which I'll share when she's through with her testimony.
The long, long, longtime member of the church has now moved to Staten Island.
If you move to Staten Island
you need a passport.
You need you're another you're in another country.
No, she lives in Staten Island
and now I just learned, is soon gonna be moving down to Tennessee
where we'll get to see her a little less
but we'll always stay in contact with her.
How she came to this church
how she grew up right here in Brooklyn
you're gonna hear it right now.
Give me a loud welcome to my friend Sylvia Glover.
Come on, put your hands together.
Praise the Lord.
It's always good to be home.
This is home.
No matter where I go, this is home.
So my name is Sylvia Glover, and in 1991
I walked into the old building on 290 Flatbush Avenue
broken and thinking that I was beyond repair.
I grew up the youngest of five, and you know
never really experienced love
never heard our parents tell us that we love us
that they loved us.
So, you know, when I when we turned around 11
I was 11 years old
my parents bought a house on East 58th Street
and it was there that I met some friends.
I think one of them is here, Leslie.
Um, we would hang out
we would start going to house parties, and you know
because I used to hear my father say
out of all the five
that I will turn out to be nothing.
So when you hear that from a father
that has a really negative effect
and it kind of sets a course for your life.
Planted a seed of rejection, a seed of insecurity.
And forget about low self-esteem.
I had no self-esteem.
I really thought that I had no value in life
and that that kind of shaped a course that I took years, you know, following that.
So moving to East 58th Street, hanging out, going to parties.
We used to go to um house parties back then.
And I was like, you know, 11, 12, 13, everybody's drinking.
I started drinking alcohol.
And you start out, you know, small.
I was, you know
you're gonna tell my age
I was drinking like pink champagne
which is like a light beer.
And you know, as it began, you know
as you begin to grow, you know
it doesn't get you drunk anymore.
You need something stronger.
So I started drinking, you know, harder alcohol.
And I learned at a young age
that alcohol can mask the pain of rejection
it masks the pain of the insecurity
and the no value that I had.
But the nature of sin is that it always demands more.
So I didn't I didn't stay with alcohol.
I started smoking marijuana, you know, 12, 13, 14 years old.
And you know, again
I I couldn't function without alcohol.
I couldn't function without without drugs
because I thought I had no esteem.
If I met you on the street
and I didn't know you
I and you would speak to me
I would freeze because I couldn't speak
because I didn't think that I had value
I had nothing to say
I had no voice.
And you know, now looking back
I realized it was like the enemy trying to steal my identity as a child.
And that's exactly what he did.
So now we're going to house parties, I'm drinking
and I'm I'm smoking marijuana.
We progressed from house parties to nightclubs in the city.
We used to go to this club called Level 21
and I was nowhere near the age of being allowed into these nightclubs.
I was like 14, 15, 16.
But because I was tall
no one asked me for ID.
I was able to get in.
And I'm hanging out with adults.
And again, I couldn't function without alcohol
because I would be sitting in a corner
I would have nothing to say.
You'd ask me to dance
and I would freeze.
But under the influence of alcohol, I metamorphosized.
I was the life of the party.
I would dance until the last song was played.
I was the last one to leave the club.
And again, I you know, really functioned under alcohol.
So as the years went by
I graduated from high school.
They probably wanted to just get rid of me
so they graduated me.
And I went to college
I was in a nursing program
believe it or not.
But because I was so busy hanging out and drinking
I would never show up to class.
I would cut class like Pastor Simble always talks about.
I used to cut class all the time.
So I would show up to class
and it was a test
and I didn't know what to what to do
so I would fail.
I got kicked out of the nursing program.
So now somehow I got a job at a brokerage firm and I started working
I don't know, in all the all the chaos
I always had a job.
That was the grace of God.
I started working at a brokerage firm
and it was there that I met one of my colleagues who introduced me to Washington Square Park.
And back then, Washington Square Park was full of drug dealers
and most of them were Rastafarians.
And you see, the thing that I longed for all my life,
that love, that family, that community
I found it in Washington Square Park.
All the drug dealers loved me.
I got to know every one of them
hung out with them
and now I don't have to pay for drugs
it's easily available to me.
So I started dating this guy.
His name was Carlos
he was Puerto Rican
and he was one of the first people that was selling crack cocaine back then in Washington Square Park.
And I had no idea what crack cocaine was.
And I remember he had rolled a joint
and it was rolled prior to me
so I had no idea what was in it.
But I noticed as we're getting high
it's a different feeling, you know.
And I'm like, what is this?
This is great.
You know, marijuana kind of makes you mellow
but cocaine makes you kind of like speed.
So this was a joint laced with crack cocaine.
So I'm down
and I'm up
and I'm like, wow, this is great.
This is a new way, really
to just mask the insecurity
and the hurt that I was feeling on the inside.
Well, that boyfriend, he progressed from smoking crack to heroin
and he was found dead in an abandoned building.
And you know, when I look back on my life
I can see the grace of God now because by God's grace
I never did heroin.
But that could have been me dead in that abandoned building.
There was no reason for me not to progress to heroin
because I was progressing from alcohol to marijuana.
Now I'm smoking
they call it a woula.
It was marijuana, you know, laced with crack cocaine.
And you think that that would wake me up?
No, I just moved on to the next drug dealer
and that was life.
I would work every day after work
I would go to Washington Square Park
and hang out with all my friends.
It was like my family.
Weekends, I lived in Washington Square Park.
We would go from hotel to hotel
because we were hiding from the cops.
You know, the cops were always looking for them
so we would spend, say
a Friday night at one hotel
we'd have to go to another hotel, you know, to evade the cops.
And it was on that job that I had a boss
thank God for my boss.
She would invite me to church every Sunday.
And every Sunday I would tell her
there's no way I'm walking into a church.
There's no way I'm gonna waste my time and go to a church.
And, you know, I had believed that
and I told her this
if I walk into a church
the building will collapse because God would know that I was there
and all of you people will die
because I showed up in church that Sunday.
That was the lie of the enemy.
So every Sunday, you want to come to church?
No.
I started trying to get her to come to the nightclubs with me.
I would tell her, you know, save your Sunday, Saturday night
let's go to a nightclub
and I can show you a good time.
But of course, you know
thank God she never came
but I didn't come to church.
But now I realize, you know, afterwards
she began to pray for me.
That's why the power of prayer.
If you're praying for someone that don't know the Lord, don't stop praying.
Now I'm dating another drug dealer
and he was a lot older than me.
So he was like that father figure
that I didn't have growing up
and so I idolized him.
And to be honest
he was a horrible drug dealer.
He kept getting arrested.
I'm like, you need to go to drug dealing school because you can't, you can't
you can't sell drugs in jail.
You gotta be out to sell drugs.
You can't make money in jail.
And he just kept getting arrested and arrested and arrested.
So one labor day on Eastern Parkway
I was there with him
and we're selling Heineken on Eastern Parkway.
And he gets into an altercation
and he gets arrested because he has a gun.
So, you know, again
he's in jail again, not making any money.
And I'm going back
and forth visiting him in pr in jail
and my boss is praying for me.
And, you know, I remember nights laying in bed and saying
Maybe you should go to church.
And then I'll say, Nah
on my 80th birthday
I'll show up.
I'm gonna live my life and enjoy my life
and when I turn 80
I will go to church with her.
Well, that boyfriend came out of jail eventually and we broke up.
And remember, he's in he's like a father figure to me.
So us breaking up, I'm devastated.
I'm absolutely devastated.
So my boss asked me again another Sunday
do you want to go to church?
And I said, Yes
I would go to church.
She was shocked.
She didn't, she didn't, you know
think she expected me to say no.
Because all my life, you know
all the time that she would ask me
I would always say no.
So this Sunday we go to church.
Now, mind you, I'm afraid to come into church
because I don't know what God is gonna do with me.
I know my life.
And even her, you know
she knew how I lived.
I used to curse like a sailor.
I couldn't have a conversation, a full sentence without a curse word.
I smoked, I drank
I dressed very promiscuously, and you know
life was just a party for me.
So here I am now, standing outside, 290 Flatbush
I'm smoking a cigarette
waiting for her to come.
And I don't know what's gonna what I'm gonna encounter
when I get into the Brooklyn Tabernacle.
And I remember we walked in
we didn't even get all the way into the building.
We were in the lobby before you got into the sanctuary.
And it was like my my spirit recognized the spirit of God that was in the building.
And something began to stir in my heart
and I didn't know what this was.
I I had no understanding.
I was used to rejection.
So coming into a place
and experiencing the the the welcoming of God
it was foreign to me.
I didn't know what was taking place in my heart.
And we sat in the balcony
and the choir began to sing.
And I wept like a baby the whole time.
I cried and I just cried and I cried.
And then Pastor Simbala got up
and he began to preach the gospel.
And it was like he knew who I was.
He knew all the things that I did
he was reading my mail.
And at some point
it was like I remember sitting in the balcony
and it was like the building was empty
and it was no longer Pastor Simbala preaching.
Now it's God.
God is speaking to me and He's drawing me
He's calling me
and I don't know what to do.
And he made an altar call, and my friend
who has no confidence that I was gonna get saved, again
she knew my life.
She she
I I saw her every day, five days a week.
She knew who I was
she didn't think that I could get saved.
And I said to her
Whatever that pastor is talking about, I want that.
And that Sunday, I gave my heart to the Lord.
Yes, praise the Lord.
And can I tell you no one had to tell me, stop cursing.
No one had to tell me you can't smoke cigarettes.
No one had to tell me you can't, you know
smoke marijuana laced with crack cocaine.
Nobody had to tell me that alcohol was no longer acceptable.
Nobody had to tell me how to dress.
I dressed very promiscuously.
I was tall, I was very skinny
and I knew how to dress in a way that was prerogative.
No one had to tell me that those things were changed.
That day I encountered Jesus and my life was changed.
And that's why I love Romans 1, 16.
He says, I am not ashamed of the gospel
for it is the power of God for salvation for anyone who believes.
And that day I was confronted with the love of God.
And see, this is a small part of my testimony.
This is a very small part.
This is years.
I've tried to condense years of drugs and hanging out and partying
all the different things that I've done.
This is a small part of it
and I know what I did.
And more so, God knew.
He knew what I did
he knew the life that I lived.
And instead of coming into the building
and experiencing the judgment of God
I was confronted with the love of God.
And it was overwhelming.
Again, I was used to rejection
I was used to people saying no
I was used to not being acceptable.
And now here I am in a building
and a pastor that's preaching about a God who loves
and a God who is mercy.
Like the song says
Mercy is even more.
How do I deal with this?
I had no idea
but that day I gave my heart to the Lord.
And can I tell you
my life has never been the same.
Never been the same.
And I can honestly stand here and say
I love the Lord.
He is everything.
He is everything to me.
You know, it talks about, you know
your mother and your father may mistake you
but he will never forsake you.
He will never forsake you.
And if he can change me, again
this is just a small part of my testimony.
There's no life here that God cannot change.
Amen.
God bless you.
I told you.
Is that a story or is that a story?
You know, uh what she would let me just review uh
because I know a lot about her
and apply this to us today.
One of the things that she was totally mistaken about
uh poor Sylvia back then
was she thought that when she came in here
or or when she heard the word God, she thought
and a lot of us are still like this
we think God wants to judge us and punish us.
He wants to save us.
He loves us so much.
Yeah, but you don't know what I did.
Well, what did she do?
I think she left it out.
Uh wasn't it true, Sylvia?
She had a lot of stuff going on.
Wasn't it true that your picture was in a department store?
Am I correct or not?
Yeah.
And she was afraid when she started coming here
that if my wife and I
or someone went to this store
we would see her picture for shoplifting or whatever she was doing.
She was praying, take that picture down of me on there.
But she thought God wanted to judge her.
And maybe that's what you think
what's holding you back
is you don't see God as loving and wanting to help you.
Did you know that God
I don't care what you did
everyone here in this building
God loves you in a way you can't even comprehend.
You think you love your children
or you think you love your spouse
or you think you love anyone.
That's nothing.
A billion times more
God loves you and he wants to help everyone here in the building.
That's why he gave Christ to die for our sins
because the sin thing was blocking us from fellowship with God
who wants to be in our hearts and be in our lives.
But that sin was blocking her and me and you.
So God loved us so much.
He gave his son to die on the cross for you
and me when we didn't even know him.
We weren't asking for anything.
That's how much God loves you today.
That's what she was mistaken about.
I remember when I first met her
she would tell me that.
Pastor, I thought when I walked in that building
the ceiling would come down and kill everyone.
Because God knew, what are you doing in that building?
You so-and-so.
How many are happy?
God loves us and wants to wave your hand at me.
I don't care what you're going through today.
And Christian, listen to me.
He wants to help you with whatever you're going through in life.
He wants to help you because when you love people
you want to help them.
God is our helper.
But number two, and she found this out early.
That was unusual how her conversion happened.
Most people think when they find the Lord, the question is
what can you do for Jesus?
But the real thing is not what can you do for Jesus?
What can Jesus do in you?
You can't do anything for Jesus.
You can't live a different life until Jesus comes in and works in you.
Did you hear what she said?
Everything changed.
Why?
The Bible says in Philippians
for it's God who works in you
both to will and to do according to his good pleasure.
When you receive Christ and the Holy Spirit comes in you
he starts rearranging everything.
All the furniture gets fixed and changed.
And if you're here today and you're struggling, like, oh
how can I change?
How can I change?
No, you're on the wrong road.
I know that road.
Good.
Because I grew up at the opposite of her.
I grew up in many ways.
I grew up around legalism and rules and regulations.
So I thought Jesus was just someone, oh
I got to obey him every day
or he's going to do pow-pow.
But that's not Christianity.
Christianity is Jesus not only forgiving your past
but now working out to make you the new creation he wants you to be.
Ladies and gentlemen, don't you understand?
You have no concept what you can be unless you say yes to Jesus working in you.
And a lot of people say yes to what he did on the cross to wipe out our past
but they struggle with saying not only yes to that, but yes to the living Christ.
Yes, he died, but he rose again.
And now he lives in us through the power of the Holy Spirit.
And he wants to rearrange everything in your life.
You know the struggles you're going through, that same old, same old, nothing changes.
The change happens not when you try harder
but when you just give it up and say, Lord, work in me.
She learned that very early.
She did.
But she had no concept.
You know, she's going to move
she tells me now, to Tennessee
where she's going to be a part of a prayer ministry that works down there
getting pastors and churches to pray together
because God raised up a real woman of prayer when he saved Sylvia Glover.
But she had no concept.
Imagine she was afraid of coming in our building
and lived the kind of life you heard her say.
But let me tell you something.
What God can do.
God can transform.
Do I get an amen?
No, but beyond just delivered, you know,
out of, you know, weed and all that other stuff.
I noticed she always said marijuana.
We don't say marijuana in Brooklyn.
We say weed.
Am I correct?
She's Staten Island.
She's a little higher than us.
She is marijuana.
Yeah.
We talk weed here, right?
So one day back in that other building
I didn't know who she was.
Did I baptize you?
Yeah, I baptized her.
But I didn't know her personally.
I knew nothing of her testimony.
And I'm in a Tuesday night prayer meeting.
And it used to be the building was smaller than this one
that we had seats for the choir on the risers.
And when the building filled up for the prayer meeting
they would come and put people on the on the seats on the platform.
But we had to be careful that it was people we knew
because we had some people who were stalkers
and someone else who was could disrupt a meeting.
So the prayer band was up there
and people we knew, deacons, deaconesses
and they would sit up there
and we would have a meeting and pray
like we're going to do Tuesday.
So one night we're praying, and I said, All right, everyone
if you have to leave, you can leave.
But if you want to stay
just sit where you are and let's pray
and you can just linger.
And I was going through some things
and I was not in a good fatigue spiritually and whatever was going on.
So what I did was rather than go
I just went and sat with the prayer band people who I didn't know all of them
and I just sat with them.
And sometimes I would just, you know, tell them,
hold my hand, pray with me, whatever.
So one Tuesday night I'm up there and I'm praying.
And uh I said to the people around me
would you pray for me?
I need prayer, I need the Lord to help me.
How many here ever hit spots in life
where you need the Lord to help you big time?
Quick, right?
So I said that.
So they began to pray like collectively, and then maybe the lady next to me
she let out in prayer
and suddenly I heard a voice behind me starting to pray for me.
But this was unusual because she read my life.
She knew everything that was going on.
And she started to pray against it.
And she started to pray and intercede for me.
And I mean, I didn't turn around.
It was in a situation where easily turn around
but somewhere behind me
someone was putting their hand on my shoulder and praying for me.
I let it go
and I just thank God
because when the prayer time ended
and I lingered for a while
when I turn around, nobody was there.
Maybe four or five weeks later, similar thing happened.
I'm up on the risers
and I'm just sitting there at the end of the service
and people start praying for me, and again
there's that voice.
I don't know that voice.
And someone's praying for me, and once again starts quoting verses
and praying for me and building me up.
You know it's a beautiful thing when someone prays for you
and when the Holy Spirit is leading them
it really is unusual.
Because you know this is not a typical prayer.
This this is something special.
So this time the meeting ended.
Again, I look, nobody's there.
So I say to one of the prayer band people who was on my side
Who's the person that prayed for me tonight that was let out?
Oh, that's Sylvia Glover.
So I'm thinking
Sylvia Glover must have gone to Bible school
when she was five years old, brought up in church,
sanctified, knows all the verses in the Bible.
And uh we we got a saint.
What has she been on the mission field or what?
And then I meet her
and she tells me her story
what you just heard.
Look what God can do in someone's life.
Can we praise God for that?
Let's give God more applause.
Let's give God praise for that.
So she has found her niche.
She's the postmaster general
or whatever her title is in Newark.
That's why she lives in uh Staten Island now.
You see her commute.
And she's retiring at the end of January
and she's going down to do ministry.
But see, her job
I've known this for many years
her job just keeps her body and her soul together.
Her job is nothing to her.
I mean, she does it, she witnesses
she's she does a great job.
Obviously, she's been promoted, promoted.
Her picture probably be on stamps now
when we get letters at Christmas time.
But that's not what she's about.
Could you tell what she's about?
She's about Jesus.
What do you want me to do?
Where do you want me to go?
Where do you want me to be?
Now someone says, No
you have to have this kind of training and this kind of background.
We just heard her background.
So what God is saying through Sylvia to us today is I can do anything in your life.
I can do things you can't imagine if you'll just say yes.
Not everyone says yes.
So here's my final word to you.
John one says about Jesus.
John doesn't give the the Matthew
or the Luke account of the birth and the manger.
John starts a different whole way.
In the beginning was the word
and the word was with God
and the word was God, the logos, the thought of God.
Embodied in Jesus in a way we can't comprehend.
But as it talks about Jesus coming into the world, it says this
if you would play, Jeffrey.
He came unto his own
but his own would not receive.
How could you not want Jesus in your life to change you?
That's the mystery.
There are people who say yes
she said yes to that conviction.
And then there are people, am I correct?
The Bible's full of examples.
When Jesus went about
did everybody get converted?
No, they crucified him at the end.
When the apostles went out and spread the good news, did every town, everybody got converted?
No.
Christianity's always been a minority.
Always been.
Because people tend to say
I don't want them.
Like there was no room at the end?
There's no room for Jesus.
Room for houses, lands, and pleasures
room for things that pass away
but for the one who reigns forever
there's no room today.
I just want to say to you
whether you've never been born again
you don't have to live a background like her.
She's here to tell you not, you know
she's only speaking to people who are out there with a kind of wild lifestyle.
No.
You could be a churchgoer every single Sunday and never be born again.
And never be changed.
Never say yes to Jesus.
Notice what happened there, all these changes
and no one was reading her riot act about don't do that, change that, change that.
No, God was working in her.
God wants to work in you.
Say yes to Jesus, not in the manger, not even just on the cross.
Say yes to that.
His mercy is more.
Our sins there are many
but his mercy is more.
Stronger than darkness, new every morning.
Our sins there are many
but his mercy is more.
Not only say yes to that, say yes to Jesus alive today.
Say, Lord, do what you want to do in my life.
It's why there's so many half-depressed Christians.
They say yes to Jesus on the cross and resurrected
but they don't say yes to Jesus right now, today.
Like she not only did
but she continues to do it.
I've admired her walk with the Lord.
She's serious about this.
And look what God has done.
And look what the blessing she's in my life.
I don't count like I've been a blessing to her.
And I didn't know
when she was up in the balcony.
And I didn't know anything about her
but she's been a blessing to me
because she's a prayer warrior.
She will pray and pray and pray.
Look what God can do.
She's hanging out in clubs at 1415.
And now she's praying for pastors.
And you can't make this stuff up.
Only God can do this.
But what does God want to do for you?
That's the question.
Yeah, let's applaud.
Look what God did for Sylvia.
But how about you?
How about you?
Up in the balcony, how about you?
You're here today
but that doesn't mean God's working in you.
Let's close our eyes.
We're gonna sing that song.
Jeffrey's playing called I'll Say Yes, Lord.
And there's some of you need to
she's come out later.
Sylvia, she'll pray with you.
There's some men and women here that need to say, Senor, yes.
Yes, wash my past away and cover my sins with the blood of Jesus.
But yes, right now to you, Lord.
I say yes to your will.
Where you leave me, I will go.
She's not retiring to some spot, notice
where she can just chill for the rest of her life.
She's going to another place
where she can be involved in the ministry God's given her.
Because when you're with the Lord
there's no retirement.
No retirement plan.
Nothing.
We work till Jesus comes.
And some of you need to say yes
because you have no idea the potential you have if God would just hear you say yes.
Say yes to him.
Who knows where you'll end up
what you'll be doing?
If the Holy Spirit is speaking to you to say yes
in some way like you've never said it before
you want to receive Christ as your Savior
and have that experience she had
why should she be the only one to have a new creation going on inside of her?
No.
God wants it for everyone.
Whether you need to say yes to that thing God is trying to do in your life now
this is what's holding you back.
This is why the peace
and the joy aren't flowing.
Because you're half yes, half no, half well
I don't know.
I gotta control my life.
But oh, I don't want to go to hell.
Thank God he died on the cross.
But there's more.
There's more, much more.
Just stand where you are so I could pray for you.
If you want to say yes
you don't have to tell me what you're saying yes to
but God will know.
Just stand where you are and say, Pastor
I need to say yes to the Lord.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
Just stand right where you are, no embarrassment, up in the balcony, just stand.
As many as received him
he gave them the power to be things they never dreamed they would be.
Whether it's two of you or two hundred
just stand and say, Pastor
God brought me here today for this whole meeting and this moment.
I say yes to him.
Anyone else, just stand?
Those of you who are standing, come on forward.
You're coming to say yes.
Not to a church.
Come on, Sylvia, if you could come out here and stand next to me.
Sylvia will pray for you.
I'll pray for you.
We're gonna see God do a miracle in you like he did in her.
Why not?
That's why he came.
Come down from the balcony.
I am waiting for you.
Come on, come on down.
Just don't stand up there.
Come on down.
Come on, fire, single.
Anybody else just come on while we're singing?
Come on.
Come on, congregation, single.
See this part where you leave.
Father, we thank you for every life that is represented here today, O God.
I thank you that you know every detail about their lives, oh God
and you love them beyond, oh God.
As the song says
your mercy is more.
That if it was just them
you would have died on the cross for them, oh God.
So, Father, I pray today that the revelation of who you are
will invade their hearts and their mind
that they would walk out of this building knowing Jesus
knowing what you've come to accomplish
knowing that your power is here to change, to deliver
to set them free
that you have a plan
and a purpose for every life here today
that they will know your will
and they will surrender to your will,
oh God, because your will is good.
You are a good father
and you desire to minister to your people.
You desire to fill us with good things, oh God.
You desire to change us into the image of Jesus Christ.
So God, you know every name that is represented here today.
May their life never be the same from this day forward, oh God.
Let it be recorded in heaven what Jesus has accomplished at this altar today.
That the transformation, oh God
that is being accomplished here is lasting.
It is eternal, oh God.
That is not just the here and now
but our eternity is being transformed, oh God.
From death to life, from hopelessness to hope,
from discouragement to joy, unspeakable and full of glory, oh God.
What you do is above
and beyond what we can ever imagine or speak of, oh God.
So minister to your people today, oh God.
We present ourselves to you, Lord, under the lamp of the Holy Spirit.
Come, search us, cleanse us from everything defiles, oh God, purify us
give us a hunger
give us a thirst, oh God
give us a desire to serve you and to seek you, oh God.
You said, Those who hunger and thirst after righteousness
we will be filled, oh God.
Give them that thirst for righteousness, to long for you and to hunger for you, oh God.
Oh Jesus, we thank you, Lord.
You said where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is freedom.
There is liberty, oh God.
Thank you for shackles being broken.
Thank you for mindsets, oh God.
Oh God, no longer under the influence of darkness.
But oh God, that the that the revelation of Jesus Christ,
oh God, is bringing freedom into the house of God today, oh God.
So we thank you for freedom.
We thank you, Lord, for restoration.
May you redeem every life
may you restore what the what the cankerworm has robbed
and redeemed and restore all that has been lost
all that has been broken.
May the redeeming power of Jesus Christ bring restoration, oh God,
to every life here today, oh God.
We thank you, Father.
Holy Jesus, the power of the gospel
the power of the cross today that accomplishes above
and beyond what we can expect or imagine.
That the new life in Christ from this day forward
let it be recorded in heaven December 7th.
That this is the day that they encounter Jesus.
And their life will never be the same.
In Jesus' name.
Amen.
I'll say.
Lift your hand up here in the front.
Lift up a hand.
I'll say, sing louder.