We're so happy to have with us people who have helped Carol
and I and the leadership here over the years.
Phillips, Craig and Dean have been here so many times.
They travel around the country.
They travel around the world.
They're going to sing for us
but they're going to lead worship today.
So I want a loud welcome.
Come on, let's welcome Phillips Craig and Dean.
Good morning, church.
God's grace was new this morning.
His mercies are new every day.
So let's sing about the grace of God today.
Let's sing about his goodness.
This is amazing grace.
This is unfailing love That you would take my place
That you would bear my cross
You laid down your life
That I would be set free
Oh, Jesus, I sing all that you've done for me.
Come on, put your hands together.
Who breaks the power?
Who breaks the power of sin and darkness?
Whose love is mighty and so much stronger?
the King of glory, the King above all beings.
This is who shakes the whole earth with holy thunder
and leaves us breathless in awe and wonder,
the King of glory, the King above all beings.
This is amazing grace
This is unfailing love That you would take my place
That you would bear my cross
You laid down your life
That I would be set free
Oh, Jesus, our Savior
all that you've done for me.
Sing of all you've done.
Who breaks our chaos back into order?
Who breaks the armor of sun and daughter?
The King of glory.
The King of Glory
who rules the nation with truth and justice
shines like the sun in all of its brilliance.
The King of Glory, the King of the Holy.
This is amazing grace.
This is our favorite glove.
That you would take my place.
That you would bear my cross.
You laid down your life.
That I would be set free.
Oh, Jesus our Savior
all that you've done for me.
All that you've done for me.
Sing worthy.
Worthy is the Lamb who was slain.
Worthy is the King who conquered the grave.
Worthy is the King who conquered the land
Worthy is the Lamb who will stand
Worthy, worthy, worthy,
oh this is amazing grace
This is a very slow
that you would take my way
that you would tear my throat.
You ain't got no lie
that I would be set free.
All that you've done for me All that you've done for me
Come on, praise him today.
He's worthy of praise.
Lord, you're worthy this morning.
Thank you, Lord.
Bless the Lord, O my soul.
O my soul.
Worship his holy name.
Sing like never before.
O my soul.
Worship God.
You're rich in love.
You're rich in love
and you're slow to anger.
Your name is great and your heart is kind.
For all your goodness I will be on singing.
Ten thousand reasons for my heart to rise.
To bless the Lord.
Bless the Lord, O my soul.
O my soul.
Worship his holy name.
Sing like never before.
Oh, my soul, worship your holy name.
You're rich in love.
You're rich in love
and you're slow to anger.
Your name is great and your heart is kind.
For all your goodness I will keep on singing Ten thousand reasons
Ten thousand reasons for my heart to provide So bless the Lord,
oh yeah
Bless the Lord, oh my soul
Oh my soul Worship his holy name Sing like never before
Oh my soul Worship your holy name
And on that day And all that I take when my strength is flaring.
The end draws near and my time has come.
Still my soul will sing your praise, love and peace.
Ten thousand years and then forevermore.
Bless the Lord.
Bless the Lord, oh my soul, oh my soul.
Worship his holy name.
Sing like never before, oh my soul.
Worship your holy name.
Bless the Lord.
Oh, my soul, worship his holy name.
Sing like never before.
Oh, my soul, worship your holy name.
One more time.
Bless the Lord.
Worship.
Let's do something that only human beings can do
and that is to express with our words
and our voices How great and how wonderful he is.
Would you just join me this morning?
Just lift up some praise to the Lord.
Your own words.
God, we love you.
We worship you.
We bless your name this morning.
We're not ashamed of the name of Jesus Christ.
Your name is worthy.
This morning we're amazed.
Make us amazed again at you and your grace to us.
Lord, I'm amazed by you.
How you love me.
How wide.
How deep.
is is Is your love for me?
Come on, lift your hands and sing it.
Lord, I'm amazed.
Lord, I'm amazed by you.
how you love me lord I will love thee.
Just the ladies.
Lord, I'm amazed.
Lord, I'm amazed by you.
All right, gentlemen, it's your turn.
Lord, I'm amazed by you Lord
I'm amazed by you Lord
I'm amazed by you How you love me Lord
I'm amazed by you How you love me Lift your hands and sing how wide.
Everyone.
How wide.
How deep.
We worship you Lord.
How great.
Come on, everyone sing.
Amen.
The words that are used in the Old
and New Testament when we worship God is
worship, adoration, love, thanksgiving
There's just a whole lot of feelings
and emotions that we express to God
because he's been so good to us.
So last Tuesday we had a prayer meeting.
The children had already gone up to Camp Champion,
284 children, ages 9 through 13.
They got up there safely.
They were there safely
when some terrible things were happening
in other parts of the country.
Let me know what I'm talking about.
Unspeakable things.
God not only kept them
they not only had fun.
I've talked to two
and I said to my wife after talking to two,
one 10-year-old, one 9-year-old, Carol
they met God at that camp.
And I found out from counselors and people who were there, God came.
touched those children, anointed those children.
They met God.
One came back and all she wants to know is
you got to get me a devotional.
I got to start reading every single day.
So God is working.
We prayed very intensely for that.
And I am very thankful.
You can't go on to the next problem.
You have to thank God for what he did.
We also prayed that night.
Because on Wednesday morning, about 15 of the people behind me
some pastors and security people
we went to Angola Prison in Louisiana and near Baton Rouge.
And we were there.
They did two concerts.
I spoke twice.
And we got a chance to visit.
There's 4,200 inmates there.
Average sentence, 91 years.
We went on death row.
And now it's new.
They open up the cells.
So that they can come out
and mingle on the tier
and you can talk to them.
We met someone who had just received Christ a couple months before
and just gotten baptized.
Some didn't want to talk to us.
Some stayed in their cell.
But we visited all kinds of men that were there.
And we had these two jam-packed meetings where the gospel went out.
And God gave us
of all the times I've been there
that was the most blessed time we ever had.
Why?
Because among other things
Pastor Burgos stood right where I'm standing on Tuesday night
and he prayed an anointed prayer
just like an anointed prayer was prayed for by the children, by,
I believe, Pastor Luke.
And it was, God
please bless us so we can be a blessing.
And I'm telling you
I am so thankful today
because I was speaking
I had a Sprained ankle.
I had all these distractions.
But I had freedom.
I felt the Lord helping me when I spoke.
When that group sang
they sang like angels.
And the way they were received by the inmates.
And, you know, oh, God.
Come on, put your hands together.
Dios ha sido bueno.
Yeah.
Maybe you have a Thanksgiving, a special one.
Mine is fresh.
A fresh Thanksgiving.
And maybe God this very week did something for you.
Answered a prayer.
Lifted you out of a pit.
Helped you on your way.
And when I met the Christians on death row
we met one Bobby Hampton
who's been a friend of mine now for a long time.
And he's been in death row a long time.
And he has a great voice.
He began to sing.
It was a great thing that he did for me.
And he was full of thanksgiving.
He's on death row.
But he has Jesus.
And when you have Jesus
you're on life row every day of your life.
Amen?
You're not on death row.
You're on life row.
So if the Lord's been good to you and helps you
come up out of your seat
and we're going to teach these southern people how to sing in Spanish.
This song means God has been good.
Oh, Dios ha sido bueno.
They'll hear it once and sing with us.
But you come up with your thanksgiving.
Come on, let's sing.
Dios ha sido bueno.
Come on and thank the Lord.
Let the church sing now.
God has been good God has been good
God has been Let your hands sing louder now, everyone.
Gracias, Señor.
Last time, sing.
You have been so good.
Gloria to all persons.
Last line.
We praise you, Lord.
Let's praise them together.
Thank you for every blessing.
We thank you for the blessing today
that there's breath in our lungs
and that we're alive today.
Not everyone's alive.
We are alive because of your grace and mercy.
Bless the meeting.
We give it to you.
Lead us, guide us
do whatever that needs to be done today.
But God, I pray in Jesus' name
let the people go home
and leave this building with the name of Jesus on their lips
praising and thanking him.
Thank you for all you do for us.
In Christ's name, amen.
When you feel your life's a battle
and you're headed for defeat, Oh, remember
Jesus promised that you would have everything you need.
So don't you dare give up on him.
Keep on holding on until you win.
The Lord is with the little of it.
He's working it out for you.
Now it can feel like Satan busy
trying to take your joy.
Oh, remember, all the devil wants is to steal, kill, and destroy.
So don't you dab on the towel
and keep on fighting until you win.
The Lord is in the middle of it.
He's working it out for you.
So stay with God and don't give up.
Be of good courage.
He's working in our lives.
Now if you feel like Satan's busy trying to take your joy, oh
remember all the devil wants is to steal, kill, and destroy.
So don't you dare throw the towel.
It's people fighting.
You're going to win.
He's working it out for you.
So stay with us and don't give up.
We have good courage.
He's working it out for you.
It's working it out God is working it out
Don't have no doubt God is working it out
He's working it out.
He's working it out for you.
Now, if you're like me
and you need to know the Lord is working it out
I need you to stand up
and praise him before he works it out.
Because he will, because he is faithful.
He's working it out.
The Lord is working it out.
Don't have no doubt.
He's working it out.
The Lord is working it out.
Oh yeah,
he's working.
Working.
In the morning.
He's working it out
he's working it out.
So don't you doubt
cause the time will end.
Keep on fighting, you're gonna win.
He's working it out for you.
Praise the Lord.
He is working for our good.
Amen.
Hallelujah.
Thank you, Jesus.
Come on, let's put our hands together for Jesus.
Oh, we praise you, Lord.
I've been walking to a city I cannot see.
Through the depths of the valley
where the sun can't reach.
I've been high and I've been low.
I've been looking for the river that can fill my soul.
I've been walking to a city I cannot see.
Fill my cup Lord, run it over.
Give me love, give me joy, give me peace.
I am a child in need.
Fill my cup.
I've been walking over the line
standing in my way.
They can say what they want
I don't want what they say Cause I was born far from home
And I've been thriving in the wonder of the great unknown
Cause I'm drinking from a well from another place
Fill my cup, Lord
and run it over Give me love, give me joy
give me peace Fill my cup
Lord, because I am your child
oh Lord I need tears.
Fill my cup Lord
because I am your child
oh Lord I need tears.
Fill my house up with hope.
Fill my chains up with purpose.
Fill my wounds up with need.
Oh, I need you.
Fill myself.
Fill my chains up with need.
Fill my future with vision.
Goodness, grace, and provision.
Oh, I need you.
Fill my heart with love.
Fill my cup, Lord.
Run it over.
Would you give me love?
Give me love.
Give me joy.
Fill my cup, Lord.
Run it over.
I am your child.
Fill my cup, Lord.
Run it over.
my god
oh oh
oh um to the hills
knowing my help is coming from me in time of the storm
you are the source of my strength you are I live my life.
My eyes to the King.
Though my health is coming from you.
In Thee Is I My Love's Door
You Are The Source Of My Strength
I lift my hands in total praise to you.
You are You are the strength of my life.
I lift my hands in total freedom.
ah ah You are the source of my strength.
You are the strength of my life.
Amen.
you know what i love these three guys
because they are absolutely natural they love the lord
and they have helped giving honor to whom honor is due
they have come here over and over and over
and they just reminded me they haven't been here since the pandemic so
just before we open god's word
come on how many are ready for a little phillips craig
and dean let's hear it I want to be close
close to your side So heaven is real
and death is a lie I want to hear voices of angels above Sing as one.
Hallelujah.
Holy, holy.
God almighty.
The great I am.
Who is worthy.
None beside it.
God almighty.
The great I am.
I want to be near
near to your heart, loving the world, hating the dark.
I want to see dry bones living again, singing as one.
Hallelujah, holy, holy.
God Almighty, the Great I Am.
Who is worthy, not beside me?
The Great I Am.
The mountains shake before you
the demons run and flee.
At the mention of the name, King of Majesty
there is no power in hell
or any who can stand before the power
and the presence of the Great I Am.
The grave I am
the grave I am, yeah, yeah, hallelujah, holy, holy, God almighty
the grave I done beside thee, God Almighty
the great I Am.
Hallelujah, holy, holy, God Almighty
Who is worthy, done beside thee, God Almighty, the great and whole.
He's the great and whole.
Yes, you are, Lord.
Sing it with us.
Hallelujah.
Holy, holy.
God Almighty.
The great I Am.
Who is worthy.
None beside Thee.
God Almighty.
The Great I Am.
Oh, you sound so good.
He's the Great I Am.
Yes, he is.
The Great I Am.
This is a song we'll sing in heaven together.
I'm sneaking into that Brooklyn section in heaven.
I'm sneaking over there.
It's so good to be home.
To your wonderful pastors, Pastor Semblem,
Ms. Carroll, the leadership of the church,
and all you wonderful, wonderful saints of God.
We haven't been here since the pandemic.
I've just been sitting at home pouting
because we wanted to be here.
We wanted to be here.
You have impacted our lives in so many, many ways.
The song we're about to do
we recorded on several albums ago.
The record company said
we don't want you to do this song.
We don't want you to put it on the album.
The song has already been recorded.
It's too long.
And just don't think you need to do it.
Take up a space.
Well, that didn't sit too well with us.
But we wanted to respect them as the record company.
Unfortunately for them, we came to Brooklyn.
And we sang this song.
With that great choir
when we left this stage
when we left this platform
the very first call on Monday morning was
we're doing the song.
And this is the song.
Worthy is the Lamb who was slain.
Holy, holy is he.
Sing a new song to him who sits on heaven's mercy seat.
Worthy is the Lamb who was slain.
Holy, holy is He.
Sing a new song to Him who sits on heaven's mercy seat.
Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty who was
and is and is to come.
With all creation I sing praise to the King of kings.
You are my everything
and I will adore you.
Oh, I will adore you again.
De en arco iris estás vestido.
Tu voz resueno como los reinos.
Recibe honor y gloria, poder y majestad, a ti el único Rey.
Hey! Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty
who was and is and is to come.
Yeah!
With all creation I sing praise to the King of kings.
You are my everything
and I will adore you.
You are holy.
Fill with wonder, sing it
all struggle wonder at the mention of your name.
Jesus, your name is power, breath and living water.
Serve the marvelous mystery.
Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty Who was
and is and is to come
With all creation I say praise to the King of kings.
You are my everything
and I will adore you.
Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty who was
and is and is to come.
We sing holy.
With all creation I sing praise to the King of kings.
You are my everything
and I will adore you.
you are holy Amen.
Let's hear it for Phillips, Craig and Dean.
Amen.
You may be seated.
Last Sunday, you got to tell it like it is when you're the pastor.
I think that was the lowest offering we've had in like six years.
That's the truth.
Why?
I don't know.
Do you?
I've never figured it out.
All I know is that God is faithful.
So he's going to bring us back.
Would you help us?
Watching online, we're falling behind here.
It's called the Summer Doldrums.
And there's an offering basket as you leave
but most people give online.
Would you please be a part of that?
and and help us because all these things we're doing
and a lot of them involve money
and you pay out and we need to see god supply
that through the giving of his people
lord i pray publicly in front of the people
my eyes are not on the people my eyes are on you
you have been faithful over the decades
would you show your faithfulness again
You've been good to us personally.
Help us to be good now to your work.
In Jesus name.
Amen.
Forgive the personal reference
but I was a kind of off the wall kid growing up in Brooklyn.
Because of my father's drinking
I tried to get out of the house as much as I could.
Played a lot of sports, especially basketball.
Got good enough to play at the biggest high school in the country,
Rasmus Hall High School at that time, 7,800 students.
And all in one year, a lot happened.
And I made an all-city game in Madison Square Garden
and was recruited by some schools.
And one of the schools was the Naval Academy at Annapolis, Maryland.
And they sent me to prep school
because I had skipped a grade.
But my mom and dad thought in a military kind of prep school
and then at the Naval Academy
I would be under lock and key
and I would not be able to be goofing off.
So when I went to the Naval Academy
there was a lot of apprehension because when you go in
you're called a plebe, P-L-E-B-E, a plebe.
Upperclassmen are sophomore, juniors, and seniors
but they're called third, second, and first classmen.
And they haze you when you're there.
They try to break you down.
I'm just speaking
it was way worse before I went there.
And they still haze
but it's lighter now from what I understand.
But they can make you do anything.
They try to break you down, pressure you, pressure you mentally,
emotionally, physically.
And all the upperclassmen could just walk in your room at any time
take a white glove that you had to keep out
and start touching anywhere in your room.
And if there was dust
you were in trouble and had to march the next day
or run from five to six in the morning.
And then shine your shoes
and make sure you're ready for inspection.
So it was constant pressure
and a lot of the stuff I'm leaving out.
Because I was there
they dummied up a
you need to go to the academy today.
A recommendation, I'm not using the right word, but from a congressman
or from somewhere, an appointment
they have to recommend you.
So they got one from some congressman or someone in Utah
and they got me
and I was there to hoop it up and play ball.
But that's not what everyone else was thinking.
They didn't care how I played basketball.
They were out to get me, like all the other plebs.
You're assigned when you go there a first classman, a senior
who is a person who you can talk to.
You don't have to call him sir.
You can call him by his first name.
And he's there to kind of walk you through things
and protect you a little bit.
I got a guy who was an athlete
and four years ahead of me.
So he was the guy who I could go to hide out in his room a little bit.
But he couldn't protect me from everything else that was going on.
So what he did was
since he had been through everything
every midshipman has gone through plea beer
so they know the deal.
So he took me aside and he told me, all right
this is going to happen.
One day during your plea beer
Someone's going to come at you at the dining hall
and start yelling at you
and hope you spill stuff on yourself and lose your composure
and then they're going to make you...
sit under the table and say that you're a gross animal
and you don't deserve to be with human beings.
And sure enough, that happened to me.
And I ended up eating with everyone's shoes down there under the table
and march extra or just hassle you, just hassle you.
And he told me
so this could happen and that could happen
but don't worry about it.
You're going to get through that, that, that, that.
So for all journeys that we take
it's good to know some of the things that are going to happen to us.
Like a GPS will give you
there's traffic up ahead, there's this
there's a detour.
And the Bible gives us that, too, in our journey to heaven.
By the way, how many are planning to go to heaven for all eternity
because of faith in Jesus Christ?
Well, along the way
there's stuff that's going to happen.
And some of it is taught
just outwardly it's taught.
and uh and then other way
other times it's included in
what you would almost call extraneous talk
that's in the bible
you wonder if the bible is inspired i get i am the good shepherd
i get that the lord is my shepherd i get
that the judge shall live by faith i got
that that's inspired by god
but there's a lot of other stuff in the bible
and yet all scripture is inspired by god
so what is this other stuff in there for
sometimes it takes a little digging or watching
So, Paul is about to die.
This is the last letter the apostle Paul is going to write.
And the end of his journey is there, is near.
And he's writing to a younger minister that...
And he's talking to Timothy.
And this is the last chapter.
There were no chapters in this letter
but this is the end of the last letter he's ever going to write.
So he says, for I'm already being poured out like a drink offering.
He saw his life as a sacrificial gift to God.
And the time for my departure is near, not my death departure.
I'm leaving here to go there.
Do I get a witness here?
That's a good note.
We're not dying.
We're departing.
We're going to another place.
I have fought the good fight.
I have finished the race.
I have kept the faith.
So he's saying the Christian life is about a good fight.
If you're not into spiritual warfare
if you don't want to resist other impulses
you can't be a Christian.
To be a Christian
you have to be able to know
that someone's coming at you
but that you're going to be able to fight back.
Use the word of God as the sword of the spirit.
Resist the devil and he will flee from you.
But I don't want him to come at me.
Well, then wake up.
He's coming at you, right?
And they have to know how to resist him.
I have finished the race.
I have kept the faith.
Now there's in store for me the crown of righteousness.
which the Lord, the righteous judge
will award to me on that day.
And not only to me, but also to all in the Brooklyn Tabernacle
who have longed for his appearing.
And now it totally changes.
Go.
Do your best to come to me quickly.
Paul's in prison
and he's telling Timothy
please come and visit me.
Get to me, please.
Demas, an associate minister that traveled with Paul
because he loved this world
he's deserted me and has gone to Thessalonica.
Crescens has gone to Galatia and Titus to Dalmatia.
Only Luke is with me
a Gentile doctor who had gotten converted.
Get Mark, that's the one who wrote the book of Mark.
Get Mark and bring him with you
because he's helpful to me in my ministry.
I sent Tychicus to Ephesus.
When you come, bring the cloak
that I left with Carpus at a place called Troas
and bring my scrolls, hold this one, especially the parchments.
That's always been interesting.
When you come, bring the cloak that I left.
I'm in the prison
and it's getting cold
and they don't supply clothes here.
This is not Angola.
This is not Rikers Island.
This is a Roman dungeon.
with rats running all up and down your grill.
So would you please bring the cloak?
I have a cloak
but I left it.
Could you bring it to me so
that I can make it through the winter?
And by the way, bring the scrolls, especially the parchments.
Why are you still reading?
Why are you still studying?
You're at the end.
Why are you still digging and searching?
You've written a good part of the New Testament.
No, he never stopped digging and searching and reading.
It's a good lesson for all of us.
Do I get a witness here, myself?
You never stop studying.
When ministers, pastors, Christians stop reading the Bible
every day and digging
they go cold and they go backwards real quick.
You got to keep on keeping on.
So now he says
Alexander the metal worker did me a great deal of harm.
The Lord will repay him for what he has done.
You too should be on your guard against him
because he strongly opposed our message.
Here's a warning about Alexander the metal worker.
At my first defense before the judge there in Rome
no one came to my support
but everyone deserted me.
They, listen, they got frightened.
Paul was going to be called in front of a judge,
probably get the death sentence.
And if you stood there and vouch for him, they might say
we'll take you too.
Take that guy.
So Paul knew what it was to be lonely at that moment.
They deserted.
May it not be held against them.
But the Lord stood at my side.
And gave me strength so
that through me the message might be fully proclaimed.
And all the Gentiles might hear it.
And I was delivered from the lion's mouth.
The Lord will rescue me from every evil attack.
And will bring me safely to his heavenly kingdom.
To him be glory forever and ever.
Amen.
How in the world can you say that's inspired by the Holy Spirit
when it's a bunch of personal directives
and inside talk between Paul and this young minister, Timothy?
Well, what it is
it's reminders to us about tips for the journey.
All three of these things are going to happen to you and me.
They've already happened to most of us.
The rest will happen to us.
Number one.
I just want to point out three people.
Paul says to Timothy
come to me quickly.
He says, by the way
Demas has forsaken me, having loved this present world.
There's a guy named Demas who's mentioned in the book of Colossians.
And Demas was an associate, shall we say
minister who traveled with Paul.
This was the real deal.
This is not some fly-by-night guy.
He said, he's deserted me.
Having loved this present world.
Not only do I have problems
I've been busted
I'm in prison, I got persecution
I got all of that happened
but Demas has forsaken me.
Having loved this present world.
So I want to tell all of you
don't get shook
don't get all riled up
don't get all fit to be tied
when people desert you and disappoint you and leave you.
How many have had it already happen in your life, okay?
Folks are going to do that.
Demas has forsaken me.
Personal disappointment.
I thought he was my man
part of my posse
a guy who would stick with me.
No, no, no.
When the pressure got hard, Demas said, adios, muchacho.
I am out of here.
But it didn't make Paul explode.
It didn't get him crazy
because his eyes were never on Demas.
His eyes were always on Jesus.
Brothers and sisters, look at me.
Never take your eyes off of Jesus.
Put it on any man, any minister, any musician, any anyone
and you might get really disappointed.
But if you keep your eyes on Jesus
you will never be disappointed.
Can we say amen for that?
When I was younger, before the ministry
I would see ministers in my future in-laws' house.
And Carol's dad was a pastor.
And I would see them in the pulpit.
And then they were staying at this house
or would be over there for a meal.
And then I'd get close to them.
And when I got close to them, I was like, what?
That's the guy that was preaching?
He's totally different.
That's not good
when a minister acts different in a pulpit than he is in real life.
You know?
I've seen extreme cases where, you know
the minister will be
and the Lord said, oh.
And Jeremiah said, oh.
So I was eating with one guy like that who was a friend.
And we were in juniors.
And I said, you know, you would
if you want my opinion
you would reach a lot more people if you were just more natural.
Because people can see through that.
Am I correct or not?
And he said, what do you mean?
I said, well, I've been eating with you.
I never heard you say to the server, bring the ketchup.
You just don't talk like that.
Well, why would you do that in front of the pulpit?
Am I correct or not?
So...
Demas personally disappointed Paul.
And people will personally disappoint you.
Fail you.
Sometimes turn on you.
Sometimes put a knife in your back
and turn it once or twice.
Metaphorically.
You can't get all hyper about that.
It happened to Paul.
It happened to Jesus from what I read in that book.
He had one disciple who betrayed him.
So don't get all sideways when people act nasty.
Jesus said in one place
your enemies will come from your own household.
I have been doing this long enough
to counsel people who cry that in their own family
they're discouraged to be a Christian.
So, But notice what it says here.
Demas has forsaken me, not just personal,
having loved this present world.
So now we're getting the back story.
Somehow he got tempted and drawn away by this world.
You know, the world is a thing.
It's not a globe.
It's a spirit, the world.
And the Bible says anyone who loves the world can't love God.
If you want to fit in
and be hip and know who's hot
and who's not and just kind of flow with everyone here
even though they hate Jesus
you can't love God.
No, no, no, no.
You can't serve two masters.
Listen to what John says in 1 John.
John says, do not love the world.
or anything in the world.
If anyone loves the world
love for the Father is not in them.
And that's important now
because in the church of Jesus Christ in America
instead of us evangelizing the world
and making them change and follow Christ
the world has evangelized us
and brought the church out into the world so
that the people know more about the world than they know about God.
They know more about whatever than they do the Bible.
They know more about movies
or sports than they knew about the Apostle Paul.
But when trouble comes
that other stuff won't help you.
You need to be grounded
and rooted in the Word of God.
Come on, say amen to that.
That's the truth.
So, for everything in the world
what's in the world?
What's the world made up of?
The lust of the flesh.
Look at the advertising for a car.
They don't have a 75-year-old Dominican guy with a cane.
Buy this car.
I really like it.
No, no.
They got a blonde lady about 23 years old.
Am I correct or not?
And you're looking not at the car.
You're looking at something else, too.
Because they know exactly how the lust of the flesh work.
So it's the lust of the flesh.
The lust of the eyes
I want more and more.
Why should she have that and not me?
I want it.
And the pride of life
showing off who you are and what you have.
That's what the world is.
Lust of the flesh, lust of the eyes, and the pride of life,
strutting around, look at me, I am somebody.
All of that comes not from the Father, but from the world.
And Demas got hooked by the world.
You know, it's like crack.
Crack addict will tell you it has a voice.
It's going to call you.
That's what an addict told me once.
Pastor, it's not when it calls you, you're coming.
It's just how do you get the money for it?
It's not the question of you're going to say no to it.
You can't say no to it.
It's in you.
And that's the way the world can be.
It calls us back to that old way of living, the lust of the flesh,
the lust.
of the eyes and the pride of life.
How many have decided to follow Jesus?
No turning back.
Come on, lift your hand.
Wave it at me.
No turning back.
We're not turning back.
By the grace of God
we're not turning back.
Is that world out there?
Is it attractive?
Does it have a pull?
Absolutely.
Don't lie and say it doesn't.
But I have decided to follow Jesus.
So we learn that there will be people, ministers
I had minister friends who are no longer not in the ministry.
They've come out and now they're full blown
in another lifestyle and boasting about it.
And they used to preach the word of God.
And when I was a younger minister, I said
what's going on there?
How did that happen?
It's going to happen.
Don't get excited by it.
We weep over it.
We can pray for the person.
But don't go crazy.
What is going on?
It happened to Paul.
Paul said, look, I'm writing this in scripture to Timothy.
So you'll know Demas has forsaken me.
People will disappoint you.
And some are going to jump out of the boat
before we get to the other side.
I mean, they're still going to serve him and follow him.
Say amen.
So that's a good lesson for us.
Now there's another one.
Maybe, sister, you could find that one
with Alexander the metal worker.
We go back to Timothy, 2 Timothy, and it says
Alexander the metal worker, thank you
did me a great deal of harm.
The Lord will repay him for what he has done.
Just hold that.
Paul says, I'm working for the Lord.
I'm serving Christ.
I'm anointed.
I'm so anointed I'm writing part of the New Testament.
And yet God permits Alexander the metal worker
to come up and really mess me up.
When I was growing up, I was taught, no, praise God
we have the victory.
Nobody can touch us.
Touch not my anointed.
Do my prophets no harm.
Well, Alexander the metal worker did him a lot of harm.
So you got to get your Christianity according to the Bible,
not American adventurism.
See, life is real when you're a Christian.
Paul lets us know that whatever you go through
he's been through, and then some.
Alexander, the metal worker
did me a lot of harm.
The Lord will repay him for what he has done.
So now here's a question.
If you're anointed and you're serving God and you're a Christian
why would God permit somebody to come and hurt you?
Because that's the way life works.
If we suffer with him
we will reign with him.
Do you get it?
To be a Christian doesn't mean you're trouble free.
Come on, do I get a witness here from people?
I want you to know this
because there's a lot of, ask Phillips, Craig and Dean.
In fact, some of them live out there
where a lot of these charlatans are.
That if you serve God
and speak the word and confess the faith
you'll have no problems
and you'll drive a Mercedes at all time.
What do you got that pickup truck for?
Get out of that
get in that Mercedes that God has.
You're one of the king's kids
and you will walk and never have a need
and that's all a lie.
God does bring blessings.
How many say amen?
But God permits enough trouble that we need to keep holding on to.
Alexander the metal worker did a number on me.
He did me great harm.
So in the Christian life
here's a tip for you.
There were people not only would disappoint you, turn on you.
Some people would be sent.
Alexander the metal worker was never a believer that we know of.
They're just going to come to attack you.
And you can't say
there must be sin in my life.
Where's my faith?
It's part of the journey, my friend.
Like when I was a midshipman
they could break into my door, open that door.
I'd have to stand at attention.
One guy didn't like anyone from New York City.
And he found out where I was from.
And made me stand in front of the mirror
and a hundred times look in the mirror and say, I am ugly.
I am from Brooklyn.
I am ugly.
And he just sat there
and listened to me say it.
After about 50, he left
but he told me
you better keep saying that.
I'll hear you from the hallway.
Well, he shouldn't be able to do that.
He could.
And he did.
And that's the way life is.
And if you're a little snowflake that doesn't want any trouble
you can't be a Christian.
Men are born to trouble as the sparks fly upward.
Show me one person in the Bible,
in the New Testament or in the Old Testament
who didn't go through trouble.
Show me one.
I'll be happy to be converted to your position.
Moses, his own people tried to kill him.
They were going to stone him.
Jeremiah got thrown in a jail of sorts.
The prophets were all persecuted.
When you stand for God
as the New Testament says
those who live godly lives will suffer much affliction
and persecution.
If you want to fit in with the world
you'll get a little bit less.
But if you really stand for the Lord
they're going to come for you.
They can pick up the scent that you belong to Jesus.
Jesus said it this way.
If they hated me
they're going to hate you.
I know this is different for some of you
but bear with me watching and check your Bible.
You'll find I'm speaking truth.
If they hated me
they'll hate you.
If they persecuted me
they will persecute you.
No servant can be greater than his master.
But if we suffer with him
we will reign with him.
In 2 Corinthians, wait
in 2 Corinthians 11 and 12
Paul gives a list of all the stuff he went through as an apostle.
And he talks about outwardly we're decaying
but inwardly we're getting renewed every day.
But he said, oh, man
I've been beat three times, 39 lashes
I think it was, thrown in the open sea, spent a day in the open deep.
in trouble in the cities in trouble in the country
thrown in prison stoned flogged
suffer hunger i know it is to suffer thirst
well where's your anointing
no don't you get it brothers
and sisters i want you to have real christianity
not american christianity i don't want perversions of the scripture
i want to know the truth
because the truth will set us free
listen there's trouble in life that's why that other place is called
Where there's no more tears.
But here on earth
there's some tears.
How many have ever been attacked by someone
and they're out to hurt you in life in one way, shape or form?
Just lift your hand, right?
It wasn't because you weren't a Christian.
Sometimes it's because you are a Christian.
So Paul says these things to Timothy.
God puts it in the New Testament.
So we've learned the real deal.
Instead of just triumphalism
shouting God is good bump all the time.
He is good all the time.
But you go through some trouble down here.
And if you're going through some trouble today
lift up your head.
Your redemption is drawing nigh.
Don't get all discombobulated by it.
It's not over.
Don't give up.
God is still there.
But there's Demases who will disappoint you,
having loved this present world.
And there's also Alexander the metal worker.
But notice this.
This is a key.
May the Lord repay him for what he's done.
The temptation with Alexander the metal worker is this.
They get inside your craw.
And you get bitter because they're so nasty.
And now you're a double loser.
I'm a double loser.
They not only hurt me
now I got bitterness inside of me which poisons my own spirit.
May the Lord take care of them.
The Lord's going to take care of Alexander the metal worker.
No, come on, Pastor Simba, come on
let's get Alexander the metal worker.
We're fighting cultural wars.
We're going to kill everyone who disagrees with us.
That is not the spirit of Jesus.
Let the Lord take care of people.
How many want the Lord to take care of people?
Come on, wave your hand at me.
Those who are against you
let the Lord do it.
He does it, if you would come, in such a better way than us.
You've heard me refer to this from the Old Testament.
Moses marries a black woman.
And even back then
a lot of people were sideways with race.
And he marries a black woman, probably from Ethiopia, Kushite.
And his brother and his sister
who's the high priest, and Miriam
who let everyone out dancing
they don't like it.
So they get up at his grill.
What are you doing?
You're not the only one anointed.
You have no business marrying that woman.
We didn't approve.
By the way, just a side note.
When someone is dating someone else
Don't give your opinion
because it's none of your business.
Listen, listen, listen again.
When someone seems to be going out with someone
and they might get married
why do you have to have an opinion of that?
Are you God?
Are you Solomon?
Are you the wisest person?
It says in Philippians, in the NLT
mind your own business.
They did not.
They got into it with Moses.
And you know what Moses did?
This is the worst thing that can happen.
This is what Paul is doing.
If you're criticizing someone
or they're criticizing you
and you don't fight back
you know what Moses did?
He fell to the ground.
I belong to you, God.
You see what they're saying.
I'm not even going to answer them.
When you fight and attack someone
and they fall to the ground and say, God
take care of me.
If I were you
I would get a ticket out of town very quickly
because you're in a very bad place.
And suddenly the cloud moves from above the tabernacle
and it hovers over Miriam and Aaron.
And God speaks and says
who are you to talk against my servant Moses?
So here's the thing.
We can fight our own battles
or we can let God fight our battles.
How many want God to fight your battles?
Say amen.
So Paul says, yeah, Alexander
the metal worker is a bad dude.
There are evil people out there.
Education isn't going to change people.
Education is helpful.
But the whole liberal idea
that the more you educate people
we're more educated now
than we've ever been in the history of mankind.
And we got more evil going on.
Just make smart, evil people.
So, on the journey
we're going to have Demas forsake us, love the world, jump ship.
They're not a Christian anymore.
Okay, I feel bad for you, Demas.
I will pray for you.
Turn to Jesus, please, Demas
but I'm going to keep my eyes on the Lord.
They'll be Alexander the metal worker.
They will.
There's coming a day
where you'll run into him.
He's everywhere.
In one way or another
he's out to do harm.
Let the Lord take care of it.
But don't get shook up.
Lastly, Paul says, at my first trial, everyone deserted me.
And there I was in the court.
With not one person standing with me.
All these converts I've made.
All that I've gone through for the ministry.
All the sermons I've preached.
All the letters that I've written.
And here I am in front of the man, the judge
and I got nobody with me.
It reminds me of somebody else.
Who does that remind you of?
Jesus.
Sometimes you're all alone.
It shouldn't be that way, you say.
I know, but it is.
They're weak.
They were weak.
Don't you get it?
People have fears.
Not maybe everyone is as strong as you.
You got to take into account people's weakness.
Yeah, but they should have been there.
Listen, they weren't there.
They were afraid.
Doesn't mean they're not Christians.
They just were afraid.
Not everyone has the same boldness, same faith.
And he said, everyone forsook me.
So here's what I want to leave you with.
But the Lord didn't forsake me.
He stood by my side.
Nobody could see him but me.
But he was right there.
And he adds this little note, so gracious, so kind.
Everyone forsook me.
May the Lord not account it to their charge.
Right to the end
he's having mercy and patience with people.
Because he has God's spirit within him.
God's spirit doesn't make us vindictive.
We show grace to people.
And the Lord was there.
And he brought me through it.
This last word I want to leave you.
Singers, if you would come up here quickly.
He said this.
And he delivered me and he's going to continue to deliver me.
So here's my word to you today.
The Lord has had to apply it to me many times in the last few years.
What you're going through is not forever.
It's just a season.
You're going to come out of it.
The Lord is with you in it.
And then at the right time
he's going to take you out of it.
But it's not forever.
Enemy wants to suggest to us when we have trouble.
See, that's it.
That's the end of your life.
He's a liar.
When he speaks, he's lying.
He's the father of lies.
Paul says, no, the Lord brought me through that.
He's looking back now.
Timothy, I want to tell you about that.
I stood in front of the judge.
There was nobody there.
He could have thrown up his hands and said, oh, judge
before you say anything
could I vent a little bit?
Yo, where are my supporters?
Have I not done enough for you to help you serve Christ?
No.
He accepted it.
Don't punish them for it, Lord.
But one thing I know
they might forsake me.
You'll never forsake me.
I want to tell you today
the Lord is with you.
I don't feel him.
I know, but he's with you.
Have faith.
Forget feelings for a second.
The Lord is with you.
He's invisible, but he's with you.
He's going to fight your battles.
You know what you need to do?
You need to turn your eyes upon Jesus.
Look full in his wonderful face
and the things of this earth will grow.
strangely dim in the light of his glory and grace.
Demases come and go.
Alexander the coppersmith,
we're all going to meet characters like that.
And sometimes we're going to feel all alone
but you are not alone.
Jesus says to us, fear not
I am with you.
Please bow your heads.
Anybody here just going through a demas,
an Alexander the metal worker moment
or just You're going through a season
like you've never had in your life.
And you feel like no one understands.
No one knows.
No one can feel what you're feeling.
You just stand up where you are.
We're going to pray over you.
That God's going to give you a spirit of faith.
Just stand up right where you are, Pastor.
That message was for me.
It had my name on it.
How would you possibly know what I was going through?
That was written for our encouragement.
So that when the trials of life come
we won't explode, go sideways, give up,
quit, get bitter, get frustrated.
Oh, God, help us to grow up so
that we can stand firm and strong.
While we sing, while this choir sings this song, you just listen.
Anyone else wants prayer
just stand up where you are.
Turn your eyes upon Jesus.
If you're standing, come here to the front.
Come on.
Come on to the front.
Come to the front if you're standing.
Everyone standing, come to the front please.
The balcony too.
Everyone sing now.
Looks for it in his wonderful face.
And the deeds of life will grow sweetly there in the light.
If you're here in the front
lift up your hand.
Sing as a testimony now.
Turn your eyes upon Jesus.
Look forward.
Everyone stand.
Everyone in the building stand up and sing with us.
Sing.
Turn.
My Jesus My Jesus Lord, I ask you, first, Lord, increase our faith.
We go by feeling and sight too much.
Me included.
Give us the maturity that sees the invisible.
That sees eternity.
When those demons moments happen
and we feel stabbed in the back, disappointed.
What's happening?
Look, they're not serving God anymore.
Steady our eyes on you, Lord.
And hold our hands tight.
Don't let the enemy win a double victory
not only pulling someone away but discouraging us.
When we have our Alexander the Metalworker moments
when some mean demonic person comes to harm our reputation
or our name or hurt us financially or just mean
like they were with you, Lord
when they spit on you.
and cursed you, hung you on a tree.
Help us to have the spirit of Jesus.
Help us not to fight back and get mean ourselves
but help us to leave it with you, God.
Fight our battles, Lord.
In the name of Jesus
we give you our battles today.
Fight the battles for us today, Lord.
Vindicate your servants.
And finally, Lord, when it seems like no one understands
No one's around.
Just the way you held the Apostle Paul up, hold us up.
Make your presence and closeness known to us.
No one ever cared for me like Jesus.
Help us to sing that song.
And it's only a season.
What we're going through is only a season.
It's not forever.
Heaven is forever.
What we're going through now is just a little
it's not even worthy to compare with what's waiting for us.
Make us strong, mature Christians.
Someone here, Lord, and is not a Christian.
I pray that they will repent of their sins
and put their faith in Jesus Christ.
But for the rest of us, Lord
we lift up a hand and we sing.
Come on, sing with me.
Lift your hand.
Turn your eyes upon Jesus
who was born in His wonderful face,
and the peace In the light of His lovely light.