We worship you this morning, Lord.
We are suffer to worship you, God.
You are worthy today.
Come on, with all your heart, let's sing.
Who brings the power of sin and darkness?
Whose love is sighting and so much stronger than King of Glory, the King of the Lord.
Who shakes the water with holy laughter?
And these are friends with holy water, the king of glory, the king of the lady.
This is amazing.
This is a very brother
that you would take my days
that you would wear my books.
Who prays the order?
A spot in the order, the king of glory
the king of glory
who rules the nations with truth and justice
shut by the sun, all its brilliance, the people
the people of holy be.
Oh she possessing voice all that you come for me.
Come on, sing it again.
Worthy is the Worthy is the lamb who said Jesus Worthy is the thing who conquered the prey.
Worthy is the lamb who said Worthy is the thing who conquered the turnout.
Worthy is the thing who conquer the place Worthy is the lamb who slay Worthy.
Close Jesus I sing for
that you tell me we come up
this is a face we're taking my day.
Hallelujah!
That you would have my boy Thank you, chair and beast.
Amen.
Thank you, Jesus, for all that you've done for us, God.
For all that you've done, Lord.
You have done so much, God.
Remind us today, Lord
of everything that we have in you.
Everything that we have, God.
What a gift you are to our lives, Jesus.
How we love you today, Lord.
We're so thankful for you today.
Thank you for the hope that we have in you, God.
Where would we be without you today, Jesus?
How lost would we be, God?
How broken would we be?
But you have bound up our wounds, oh Jesus.
You've bound up our brokenness, oh God.
You've made us whole in you, oh God.
You've cleansed us from all our unrighteousness, Jesus.
You've given us a new name, oh God.
We thank you, God.
We thank you, Jesus
for every promise that we stand on.
Because you died and you rose again, Lord.
We thank you for the victory that we have in you today, God.
We bless your name, Jesus.
You are worthy of our praise.
You are worthy, Lord.
Open our mouths to worship you today, God.
That it would never grow old, oh God.
Oh God, that it would be fresh and new, a new song, God.
That it rise up within our soul today, Jesus.
We bless you, Lord.
Hallelujah.
I cast my mind to count
where Jesus led and I want me.
I see his rooms his head.
I say the wrong enterprise
and transition seeks they make sure he has transition by so come on, sing it together.
Oh praise, oh praise
we will see the place of the Lord.
In roads of wise
the place itself shall give
and I will rise among the savings.
My case is on Jesus.
Just worship the Lord.
Hallelujah, Jesus.
We praise you, Jesus.
Come on, declare it today.
We bless your name.
Come on, just bless the name of Jesus today.
Lift up the name of Jesus in this place.
We lift up your precious name, God.
We worship it.
We worship you, Lord.
We bless you, Lord.
We give you praise, Jesus.
Oh, bless the name of Jesus.
What a wonderful name.
The only name by which men are saved.
We bless that name.
We worship you, Lord.
We praise you, Jesus.
Your name above every other name.
Hallelujah, Jesus.
Hallelujah, we love you, Lord.
We give you praise, Jesus.
Hallelujah, Jesus.
Oh, we love you, Lord.
We love you, Lord.
We all die today.
Don't worship God.
We see our grace.
We give you our love.
We give you our hearts.
We glorify your name, Jesus.
We worship and adore you, Lord.
We honor you in this place, O God.
We exalt you, Lord.
We extol you, God
we lift you up, Lord.
We bless you, we bless you, we bless you, we bless you, God.
Hallelujah, hallelujah, hallelujah, Jesus.
Be glorified, Lord, be glorified in this place, oh God.
Where others might curse your name, God
we reverence it today, Lord.
We honor it, God.
We proclaim your goodness.
We proclaim your faithfulness.
We proclaim your great love.
We proclaim your great power, Lord.
We worship and adore you, Lord.
Hallelujah.
Thank you, Jesus.
We give you this meeting, oh God.
Be glorified, God.
Be glorified.
Be glorified in this place, Lord.
Let it not just be a meeting of people, God
but let it be a meeting with you, Lord.
With you, Jesus.
You are alive, God.
You are alive, Lord.
You are living.
And you meet your people, God.
So we wait upon you, Lord.
We expect you, Jesus.
As we gather in your name, Lord, visit us, Lord.
By your spirit, God.
Speak to us.
Encourage the hearts of your people today.
Strengthen us, Lord.
Let your strength be perfected in our weakness, God.
We empty ourselves that we might be filled with you, Lord.
Filled with your spirit.
Filled with your strength, God.
So we open our hearts, God.
We humble ourselves before you and we wait upon you.
Have your way in this meeting, God.
And let your will be accomplished.
We pray in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Praise God.
Praise the Lord.
I don't know about you
but I have so many things to be thankful for.
God has been good
He has been faithful.
He has never failed me yet.
Amen.
Tragedies are commonplace.
All kinds of diseases.
People are slipping away.
Economies out can get in the way.
As for me, all I can say is that home without holes, people out in the streets.
We just can't beat Burgers and robbers.
No place seems to be safe.
But you mention my protection every step of the way.
And I want to say back for me.
I love Jesus.
I worship and glory just once tell you
for I love you more than anything.
I love Jesus.
Just want to tell you
for I love you for an Jesus.
Just one of the things that we don't have to do.
You know, I love the Lord today.
Because he first loved me.
Because he's just so good.
Even when you think you've fallen short
he's not holding it against you.
Because he knows from the beginning to the end.
You say he didn't save you
because you're good or anything like that.
He saved you once before all.
So he already knows.
So we pick ourselves up
and ask for forgiveness and we go along our way without beating up on ourselves
and falling in guilt and falling away.
It happens.
But the great love of Jesus keeps pursuing us and calling us.
Where would we be today without that love?
And if I can just tell him in this song, Lord, I love you.
You know, and I ask that you sing along.
It's an old song.
Oh, how we love you.
Praise you, worship you because he's been so
Our heart cry in this your holy temple, in this your holy place
and we to praise and glorify, unify
oh how we praise you,
oh how we watch you,
oh how we're gonna be able to do that.
We give you all the praise and worship you always.
Oh, thank you, Jesus.
Thank you, Jesus.
Oh, how we love you.
Jesus, we love you.
Hallelujah.
Oh, we praise you, Lord.
Pastor James, come up here for a second, brother.
Pastor James heads up our BTYM ministry
and we need a prayer for our giving.
Giving was it's typical, thank you, brother.
Um giving around the holiday season can fluctuate.
People are shopping and uh Amex, MasterCard Visa
that can just draw you right in, right?
And then sometimes imagine around the Lord's birthday
his work suffers because people are busy spending money elsewhere
and the work of the Lord actually gets hurt.
So those watching online who give online, gracias por todo
thank you so much for what you do.
Those of you here
you can give in person as you leave.
There's gonna be baskets
or you can give online.
Most do give online.
And um we're so thankful for your giving.
But please do not forget
you know what I was thinking today.
Uh because I get so uh self-conscious taking offerings thousands of times now over the years
that uh it'll sound mechanical.
Just ask the Lord what you should give.
Is that fair?
I'm not telling you.
Just uh contemplate how he's blessed you and then ask the Lord
based on how you bless me
what should I give today?
How should I systematically give?
Let's pray together, James.
Jesus, as we uh uh come to the close of the Thanksgiving weekend
we uh have been saying all morning long
that we have so much to be grateful for, God.
And God, we know as Christians
we don't have to wait for uh a Thanksgiving holiday to give you praise.
We worship you because you are so good.
You have been so good.
We thank you for your faithfulness
we thank you for your love
we thank you for your mercy
we thank you for your joy, for your strength
we thank you for your provision, for your protection, oh God.
Father, I can go on and on about things for which we're thankful.
God, so it's out of that heart of grateful, of gratitude, that heart of praise
that heart of thanksgiving that we give to you, Lord Jesus.
We ask right now, oh God
that you would help us, oh God
to give because you have given to us, oh God.
Everything that we have, oh God
is been given to us by you, Lord Jesus.
And God, you don't ask us to give 100% back, oh God.
You only ask for a tithe, oh God, a love offering, Lord Jesus.
So God, we give, oh God
because you've given unto us, Lord Jesus.
And we ask, God
that you take what we give, Father
and that you would bless, oh God
that you would use it for the furtherness of your kingdom, oh God.
We're not giving to a church of God
we're giving to the work of the Lord, Father.
And we thank you, God, that for some reason, oh God
you include us in your master plan of God of being a blessing to other people, God.
We're grateful that we can be a part of someone's salvation story
to be a part of someone's provision,
to be a part of buildings going up, churches going up, schools going up
what feeding programs of God
all the things you allow us to do, Father.
And God, we do all these things, oh God
that the name of Jesus might be spread.
That people everywhere in this city, in this country, and around the world
might know about the faithfulness of Jesus Christ, oh God.
Father, we will never get tired of singing your praise, of worshiping you, oh God.
And Father, we thank you, God
that we can give as an act of worship, oh Father.
So receive our giving, oh God
and we do give it with a grateful heart.
We give it, oh God
because we are so blessed, Lord Jesus.
We give, oh God
because we are so grateful, Lord.
Father, we love you.
We praise you, God
and we thank you for in a way to express, oh God
our thanksgiving through our given, Lord Jesus.
And God, for those who are here
and they're not able to give, Father
those who are looking out for work, oh God
we pray that you would bless them, oh God.
That even this week, oh God
when people are worried about the economy of God
you look out for your children, oh Father.
We pray that you would open up doors, oh God, of employment,
oh God, even this week, oh God.
So that they too, oh God, might be able to give
to the work of the Lord, Father.
And that their testimony might be
Jesus has been faithful in my life.
In your precious and holy name we pray.
Amen.
Thank you.
Close your eyes.
Let's just close our eyes.
If you don't have a job right now, you're unemployed.
Stand up.
We want to pray that God will help you.
Anybody here without a job, just stand up.
Seeking employment.
Just stand up right where you are.
That's rough to be in that situation around the holiday season.
Those who are standing
just lift up your hand to the Lord, one hand, Lord
help my brothers and sisters to get employment.
Open a door that nobody can shut.
Don't let them be discouraged.
Guide them, lead them, and help them, Lord.
And as they get that job that you have for them
they will give you all the praise and honor and glory.
We thank you for that in Jesus' name.
Amen.
You may be seated.
Um you know, as James
Pastor James was praying for those who can't give
let me just give you uh a tip and a suggestion.
Um no matter how little you have, give something.
I don't care if it's a a quarter, a dollar.
Um, none of us probably are in a place
where we can't give something.
And a lot of times
when we're short and things are harder
we think that we have less
so we shouldn't give at all.
That is not the time to stop giving.
We should always be giving.
Amen.
And uh remember that as you as you uh participate in the offering.
Well, for about eighteen years now I haven't preached with notes
uh just uh just something personal that happened I felt between me and the Lord, him directing me.
But there there's so much to cover here today.
I I have a little guide sheet, not notes
but uh I'm gonna give you a lot today
because this is a very, very important message.
Uh um I have a library upstairs.
I went in the ministry without going to seminary or bible school
so I was turned on to godly good literature uh early on
and I collected um a library
which is I'm still collecting, of books, commentaries, sermons,
uh doctrinal studies, systematic theologies, biographies, autobiographies.
I have everything uh you can imagine.
And they have been my instructors
because I never had a chance to go to seminary and sit in a classroom.
And I thank God for that.
Um but it's amazing now as I look back
I don't want to exaggerate
I don't want to be melodramatic
but as I look back
and uh the books I've read
and uh have and have seen and sermons I've heard
that there's all kinds of theological subjects that are been written about and preached about.
Obviously, God, the Father, the Son, Jesus
who is our uh Savior
the Holy Spirit being sent.
There's less books about him historically.
Uh the Holy Spirit, in fact, from the Protestant Reformation 1517
until really the eighteen hundreds, all the way through the eighteen hundreds
there's hardly any classic books on the Holy Spirit.
He's been de-emphasized and kind of lost in the shuffle of things.
But there's books about the second coming of Christ
there's books about the love of God
there's books about the power that's in the name of Jesus
there's books about what happened on the cross
there's books about apologetics
there's books about prophecy
and about what's going to happen
and the mark of the beast
and and the book of Revelation
and there's books about the hope of Christ's return
there's books about what deacons should be doing
and who's qualified to be a pastor
and there's books about every every kind of thing, and multiple books.
I would say without exaggeration
there's not one
I don't want to go overboard
there's not one book for every 500 that's on this subject that I want to bring to you
and yet it's the most important at all of all in certain ways.
When I present it to you
you're gonna say, Wow, that's true.
Look at these verses.
Hardly ever talked about, hardly ever discussed.
I would imagine today in America and around the world, thousands and thousands
hundreds of thousands of sermons are gonna be preached.
There probably will be just not even a cursory reference to this subject, which is
as you're gonna see
it's like foundational.
It's like if you don't
if you and I don't get this
we don't get it.
In fact, sitting in front of me today
and in the band are all kinds of people.
We're Christians, but because we don't understand this subject
we don't think about it
we don't pray about it, uh
we lose out with God
we lose all kinds of blessings.
Uh if you don't concentrate on this
and you get infected by the negative side of it
it actually gives a terrible testimony to Jesus Christ.
The church is ruined, you have tension, you have fighting
you have people wandering around
they read their Bible and they don't get it.
They read the Bible
why don't they get it?
Why don't they see more from the Bible?
It's because of this subject.
They come to crossroads in life
and they need direction from the Lord
but they don't get cross
they don't get uh direction from the Lord.
Um there's fighting in the choir
there's fighting in the congregation
there's fighting among churches and denominations
and and it's all because of this subject.
It just overwhelms me when I think of it.
So let me just throw these verses at you
and uh let's just look at them
and it kind of summarizes what I want to start with.
Pride brings a person low
but the lowly in spirit, they gain honor, the Lord says.
Proverbs 16, 5.
Next.
Proverbs 29, 23.
Do you see a person wise in their own eyes?
There's more hope for a fool than for them.
You see somebody who's clever and they think they know
they have that disease called I know.
You ever talk to people who they know?
They know what?
Anything and everything.
They know.
There's more hope for a fool
and fool in the Bible has a moral connotation.
It's a it's a person against God.
There's more hope for a fool than for someone who thinks they know a lot of stuff.
Then it says in Proverbs 16, 18
pride goes before destruction or haughty spirit before a fall.
You know, you start to get chills
and someone says to you, you know what?
I think you're coming down with something.
We're so smart about weather
and what's gonna happen next because we see the signs.
And here God says
Will you see someone pride
they will be destroyed.
Notice how quiet it got here?
Just think of that.
We think sin is about doing drugs
and robbing and living a degenerate kind of life
but here God says
before a destruction and a fall
there will always be a haughty spirit.
Before a Christian gets in trouble
before a person is brought down, either in this life or for sure by God
there'll be haughtiness.
I'm better than you.
I'm superior to you.
My race is superior to yours.
My intelligence is superior to yours.
My culture is superior to yours.
My opinions are superior to yours.
The food I eat
my royalty is better than your royalty.
That's how deep it can go.
Am I correct or not?
But it's not done.
Oh no, we're just starting here.
Then in James 4, verses 6
here's the New Testament.
But he gives us more grace.
God's always ready to give grace.
What is grace?
Grace is God's love in action.
Look at me, everyone.
Grace, when you receive grace
you're getting something you don't deserve.
But it's God's love in action.
It could be wisdom, help, encouragement, strength, a healing, uh, a job.
It could be anything.
But he gives more grace.
That's why scripture says God opposes the proud
but he shows favor, hold that, to the humble.
The word opposes there.
Imagine God opposing something.
You know, if you tell me you don't like something
I don't like something
that's one thing.
When you hear that God opposes something, you say
I want to stay a million miles from that.
Am I correct?
The word opposes there is he sets himself like an army general
with full battle array, every angel, all his power.
And he sets himself against a proud person.
And you don't have to be wealthy
some of the poorest people in the world are the proudest.
And rich people can be proud.
It's interracial.
Pride just sticks to anything.
God sets himself and swears
I will bring you down.
That's how he feels about pride.
You think we would be talking about this all the time?
God opposes, not the whoremonger, not the drunkard, not the drug addict.
No, no, no.
It doesn't say God opposes them.
He opposes the proud.
Who does he give grace to?
The humble.
In other words, there's only one channel through
which God pours out all his blessings.
Salvation, blessings, financial healing, guidance, the anointing of the Holy Spirit
being used by God, the Christmas production.
There's only one channel that God uses to send down his blessing
and that channel is called humility.
His blessings only go down
they never go up to the people who think they're all that.
Never, not once.
He resists the proud.
But he gives grace to the humble.
And then finally, in 1 Peter, kind of, oh no, James, thank you.
Humble yourselves before the Lord
and he will lift you up.
How many want to be lifted up by God?
Wave your hand at me.
You want God to actually lift you up.
Then the simple thing is this go down.
But if you go up
you're going down.
But if you go down
you're going up.
It's that simple.
No, but I'm a minister.
I've been serving the Lord 40 years.
I grew up in the church.
I know so much in the Bible.
It doesn't matter.
You go up, you're coming down.
Because pride can live on anything.
It's like those chickens I see in South America sometimes in these rural places.
A pastor pointed out to me
that pigs are known to be kind of like filthy
but uh Pigs will pass by certain stuff on the ground, but not a chicken.
Chicken will eat anything.
That's the way pride is.
Pride can take the blessing of God and wreck you.
Because you get proud of the blessing that God gave you.
You start out as a young couple, you have nothing.
You cry to God, oh God
supply my needs and help us.
We're getting married.
Now you have children
you have an apartment
you have furniture you never dreamed of
and that's your ruin.
Because you're so proud of all you have.
But God gave you everything.
Do you give him the glory?
No, you walk around like it's yours.
Look what I got.
Look what I earned.
Look what I'm able to accomplish.
Look at my degree.
Look at my whatever.
In traveling around the country
and around the world last number of decades
I run into this all the time.
It's amazing.
I talk to pastors
and I'm so happy that we have been so blessed.
The pastors will tell you this with deacons
and deaconesses that are not like that.
Pastors tell me all the time
you know what messed me up, Jim?
There was a good brother in the church and his wife
and they've been serving the Lord
and we said we're going to install deacons.
Paul's letter to 1 Timothy talks about qualifications of a deacon.
The minute I named them as a deacon
and introduced them to the church
they turned into Genghis Khan.
They started strutting, they started walking a different way.
They started acting like they were in the Gestapo ordering people around.
I'm a deacon.
They just had this little badge.
He said, I just gave them this little badge.
It was tiny.
They wanted a laminated and put it across their forehead.
I am a deacon.
Just the title brought pride.
But isn't that title in the Bible?
So see, pride will live on anything.
God, you can write a book and it's a blessing.
You get proud of your book.
Proud of your sermon, proud of your church.
Churches, church pride is the worst.
Like our church's special people are taught.
Pastors feed that because they know we gravitate toward pride.
There's other churches
but then there's, you know.
God has raised us up for such an hour as this.
I've been hearing this since I was little.
Well, everybody is nothing without Jesus.
But how many would lift their hand and say
we are nothing without Jesus?
We're nothing.
We have nothing.
Only thing we have that's good comes from Him.
Amen?
But you wouldn't think that.
There's church brands.
Oh, I hear that all the time, especially with younger pastors.
You gotta sell your brand.
You gotta let people know that how you're different.
I was in a church in New England ten years ago.
No, in Canada, in Montreal
and they were telling me that a certain group, a brand of churches in that city
they only sing songs written by people in their own church.
I mean, how ridiculous is that?
We're not singing Amazing Grace.
We're not singing Jesus
we didn't write it.
We only write sing what we write.
I mean, get a life.
How many say Amen?
But see, that's what pride will do.
We're proud we're white.
Why are we proud we're white?
Because we're white.
We're proud we're black.
Black is beautiful.
You never hear white people say that.
You only hear black people say that.
Why?
Because they're black.
Asians are special.
Latinos are think of the pride that's built into our culture.
Our whole culture here today is get your swag on.
Am I correct or not?
Humility is looked at like
what are you kidding me?
You were humble?
That's a joke.
That's a weak person.
But look what God says about it.
It's the only way to get his blessings.
Go down.
I'm proud I'm a Republican.
I'm proud I'm a Democrat.
Why?
Because that's what I am.
Don't you get it?
Anything associated with me is special because I'm special.
What?
My opinion is special.
You dare disagree with something I hold?
What's wrong with you, by the way?
You're probably a devil.
Because you disagree with me.
Think of the pride that's in so much of it
and we're raised that way.
We're raised that way.
I was in a street meeting in 40 years ago,
35 years ago in Lima, Peru, in downtown Lima
near El Palacio de Justicia
and we were having a crusade there with Nicky Cruz
and we had a hundred people there
and they had a street meeting going on.
We were going to start one
but they had a big crowd gathered
and there were some people from Peru uh stirring up the crowd.
So I didn't understand much Spanish than I came
and I started asking
what's going on?
What are they saying?
And they were saying, Oh, listen
the Ecuadorians are gonna come and rape all the women.
And they're gonna take and kidnap our children.
And I said, Where's this from?
They said, No, you learned that from the beginning.
We Peruvians are better than the Ecuadorians.
Of course, the Ecuadorians are learning in their schools we're better than the Peruvians.
Why it's quiet here is you know that's all true.
You know it's all true.
America is superior.
Who says?
God hates when anything is lifted up in comparison to him and his goodness.
Everything we have comes from the Lord.
So the Bible constantly is saying things like this.
What do you have that you didn't receive?
And if you received it from someone else
why do you boast like it's yours?
Any of you smart?
Well, that was not a good answer.
If you are, God gave you those smarts.
Are you healthy and strong?
Did you wake up this morning and put your clothes on?
God helped you to do that.
So how can you walk around?
And with us, I want to ask a question
to all you who we we feel we're so smart.
Tell me just one thing.
I know you got degrees and all that.
What day are you gonna die on?
No, no, come on
you must know that.
You don't know that?
You don't even know the day you're gonna die
but you walk around like you know a lot.
It means you could be gone tomorrow.
You could be gone tomorrow
but you want everybody to know how smart you are.
Just think of the madness of this.
In heaven's sight.
Little ants we are on the earth, the Bible says.
We're strutting around boasting
talking about tomorrow we're gonna do this.
Next week, I got my retirement set.
You know what, Pastor?
When I retire, you know how it's all set?
You don't even know if you're alive next week.
And anything you have comes from God.
So the Bible is full of these kinds of warnings.
Imagine the loss that we have of teaching
not understanding the Bible better
because the Bible says I won't put it all up there.
He will teach the humble what they need to know.
Who does God teach?
To be a good student in his school
you've got to be humble.
You have to be childlike and want to learn.
If you come to the Bible
and you think you know everything
you'll never get anything out of it.
He resists the proud.
Paul says somewhere, let everyone know that anyone who thinks they know something
they don't know it like they ought to.
We see through a glass darkly.
We're just getting up little images.
So ministers and Christians who act like they know everything and have figured everything out, they're deluded.
We see through a glass darkly.
Ah, but when we see him
then we're gonna understand it better.
Think of the guidance that some of us have lost
because the Bible says he will guide
and lead the humble in the way they should go.
Who will he lead and guide?
Only the humble.
Oh no, proud people who think they know everything.
Go ahead and do it.
Go in your own way.
Some of you possibly right now, because of the pride of your mind
and how you've been brought up and your personality
you're making all the decisions.
They're gonna run you into a brick wall.
And God Himself can't stop you.
Because He only leads the humble in the way they should go.
Think of the power we miss of the Holy Spirit.
The grace.
That deadly virus of pride gets in us.
You know, you can't even have uh why why why don't more people pray?
Because they're proud.
Proud people never pray.
Because they don't need to.
But if you're humble
and realize you need everything from God
you'll be praying a whole lot.
Do I get a witness here?
No, I don't mean to condemn you
or I'm I'm speaking to all of us here.
Why is there so little prayer in churches
or hardly a prayer meeting to be found?
Because they can do it without God.
Don't you get it?
But if you're humble
and you see things the way they really are
you've got to call on God.
You've got to cry out to God.
But pride.
You know that story about the Pharisee
and the publican sinner who went to the temple to worship
and the Pharisee got up, you know, self-righteous.
That's another form of pride.
So God, I thank you.
That I'm not like, you know
I'm not like a drunkard or this one or that.
I'm not, I'm thank God
I'm not like this guy over here.
And then the publican
the tax collector who was looked out
he looked down on
he was humble and he just went
have mercy on me, oh God.
Jesus said, He went home justified.
The Pharisee, totally rejected by God.
When you compare your when we compare ourselves with others
and think we're superior, God says, bye-bye.
I'm only I've been sent to lift people up.
And if I don't lift you up
I'll see who's up so I can bring you down.
Wouldn't you agree?
How many sermons have you heard on this subject?
It's referenced.
How many books are there?
Go to a Christian bookstore.
See how many there are on pride and humility
and yet it's everything, it's everywhere.
So let's define what is the proud?
It's not just a boasting buffoon who's bragging about everything and puts everyone down.
No, you can be quiet and proud
you can be poor and you're proud.
But you feel superior to people.
I've been around some of the poorest cultures, poorest people in the world
and what a stinking pride they can have
like we all can have.
I'm just better than other people.
They're okay.
I don't
I don't mind them, but not like me.
Not like how I grew up.
No, not my island.
Are you kidding?
My country?
My neighborhood.
No, in in Argentina
they have pride between the provinces.
The provinces fight with each other.
Which province is better?
You'll say to someone, you know, in Spanish
what province are you from?
And they say it, they go.
The guy was born there.
How could he control where he was born?
But he's going to be mocked
because you have to link something to you that makes you feel superior, better.
So the proud have a sense of superiority.
They have an independence of God.
They can manage without God.
Hey, I don't mind praying if there's emergencies
but I got this thing figured out, Pastor Jim.
You know, just relax.
That's so proud.
You have nothing figured out.
Well, how many have found walking with Jesus?
You need them every day.
How many have found that, right?
Every day.
Every moment, every day.
I'm finding out more and more now
after all these years of serving him.
But this sense of independence
I can make it without God.
Self-confident.
And making, getting proud about anything and everything.
How many times have I watched that
and just seen people start out with nothing, nada, nothing.
They had nothing.
And now they have a little something
and they won't even come to church
because they're strutting around so wrapped up with all they have.
Braggadocious, bragging, looking for fishing for compliments all the time
dropping names of people important that they know
all so that they can be exalted.
But you know, God has a pin for every one of us sometimes for our balloon.
Have you ever had your balloon
put a little pin in your balloon?
I was walking 15 years ago in a mall in Florida
and I was walking down this pathway and stores on either side
and a lady walked by me and she went,
wait, wait, wait, wait, I know you.
And I went, No, ma'am
you don't know me.
I don't live here.
She said, No, no, I know you.
I know you.
I've seen you on TV.
And I'm thinking, no, ma'am
you made a mistake.
Um, you don't know me.
And uh she said, No, no, no
don't say that.
I know you.
I've seen you.
Let me think now.
Where do I know you from?
I've seen you on TV.
And I was starting to think to myself, wow
someone knows me in Florida?
That's not bad, right?
Just walking in the in a mall, someone, you know, knows me.
I'm thinking maybe they showed a video
maybe something the church had done, or uh
I think I had already written my first book.
Maybe she saw something on that
and and and all of that.
And I was starting just to feel a little bit like,
oh yeah.
Come on, yeah.
Maybe you do know me.
How about that?
And she said, I know you.
You're the weatherman on channel 10 every night.
I watch you.
How many know God has a pin for every balloon?
You have a balloon?
He has a pin.
The weatherman from channel 10.
Now the humble are the opposite.
The first thing Jesus ever said when he preached
the first sermon he ever preached
the first words he ever said, was
Blessed are the poor in spirit
for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
Whatever heaven has, it's yours if you're poor in spirit.
The humble get everything from God.
And they live isolate, they live self-content.
Proud people are very uh prickly
and irritable because they never know
when their balloon could be looked at.
Or they someone else could have more
and then they take a lesser position.
So they're always on edge.
They have to defend their ego, defend their image, and all of that.
So they're never at rest.
They have an inner chaos that never stops.
But the humble, they don't care.
They don't care.
They realize everything they have comes from God
everything they'll need will come from God.
And when life is over
they're gonna go to God
and it doesn't matter if people applaud you
or they boo you as long as Jesus is smiling at you
you're good to go.
How many say amen to that?
They're just they live in another world.
They're like, they're not going around
and do and and condemning themselves
and doing false humility like I have nothing, I am nothing.
They're not always just downing themselves.
That's not humility
that can be a false humility
which is a form of pride.
They just live looking to God
and wanting God to get all the glory.
They don't want the glory
because they know they don't deserve the glory.
How many are following me?
Say amen.
They don't want the glory
because they know if people knew who I really was
they would not applaud me at all.
Isn't that the truth for all of us?
Don't we have another side that hardly anyone knows about?
That amen wasn't too loud
but we all have another side, right?
And the humble just want God to get all the glory.
They remind me of this
when David was getting another blessing from God
and God was talking about how King David's uh descendants would go on forever
and that God would let him uh plan at least the temple.
Uh look what it says here in uh 2 Samuel.
Then King David went in and sat before the Lord.
By the way, if you want to get humble
here's uh every day, just sit before the Lord.
Just sit in God's presence.
No, put your back end in a chair for 15 minutes every day,
and just sit maybe with an open Bible
and open your heart to God
and you will find humility will run after you.
Because when you see yourself in God's eyes
and you realize what he's done
why are you chafing?
Why are you competing with anyone?
Why do you have to impress anyone?
So he sat before the Lord and he said, Who am I?
Sovereign Lord, and what is my family
that you have brought me this far?
Now that's the humble person.
That's why David meant so much to God
because he was humble.
His blessings came not like, thank you
I was waiting for this.
He said, Who am I?
Come on, brothers and sisters
be honest with me.
How many know in your heart of hearts all that God has blessed you with?
You could sit in his presence and say, Who am I?
Come on, lift your hand up.
I mean, who am I?
I personally am the least of my mother and dad's three children.
Trust me.
Didn't even serve God strongly in college.
What I'm doing in the ministry
how I'm blessed to stand in front of you folks every week.
By the way, join us this Tuesday.
We're gonna have a wonderful prayer meeting.
We're gonna bring a lot of needs to the Lord.
He's gonna help us.
I say all the time, Who am I?
God knows.
I sit there and I say to him, Who am I?
What should I be here?
I'm not special
I'm not specially gifted.
Just purely the blessing of God.
How about you?
How many have had a lot of blessings from God you didn't deserve?
Amen.
Can you strut around
or you rather just give him all the glory and praise?
Give them all the glory and praise.
So the humble person is dependent on God
wants to exalt God
and after that they want to serve others and they put themselves third.
Proud people are me, myself
and I. They hardly give God any credit and praise
and other people they don't have time for
because they're so occupied with themselves.
How can you love other people
when you're in love with yourself?
If you're dating yourself
it's very hard to have another girlfriend or boyfriend.
But that's the way we are.
Me, myself, and I. That's all we're preoccupied with.
And we think everything everyone's interested in our little minutiae of our lives.
Why?
Because it's my life.
You're not interested.
So listen, I went to the diner
and I had a tuna fish on on toast.
But you know, they didn't toast it the way I like it to be toasted.
I sat recently and heard a discussion
which made me just my hair start to go on fire.
People just talking about themselves to you just want to go, stop it!
Ask a question about the other person.
Find out what they're going through.
Why are you preoccupied with yourself?
But that's what pride does.
Pride makes your whole world your little, narrow, little, small life
which all of us have a narrow, small
little life compared to all the needs that are in the world.
So with the proud person is me, myself, and I. And with the humble person
it's God first, all the glory.
Not unto us, but unto you, God.
Be all the glory.
Not unto us.
The psalmist says that, not unto us.
I know, but you won the battle.
Not unto us.
God gave us the victory.
I know, but look how he supplied God supplied.
But look what you did over there.
No, God did that.
Thank God he used me
but God did it.
God did it.
And when God sees that, he says
get some more blessings.
Send it down.
Right over there one.
Send that down over that person.
I will exalt.
I'll lift that person up.
Why?
Because they're humbling themselves.
But the one who's strutting around in their own quiet, smug way
feeling better than other people
I will bring them down.
You know, there's something about that.
I I don't have the verse here
but in one of the proverbs it actually says, God hates pride.
He detests pride.
And many have wondered
what is it about pride that sets God off?
Because like he never says he hates a drunkard.
And some people think
if you read in Ezekiel
and Isaiah and you take it prophetically
uh speaking of Lucifer
that when God created Lucifer as the most beautiful of all his angelic creation
before the world was made
before there was planet Earth, the sun, the moon, the stars,
in heaven is seemingly in charge of worship.
And gifted and the most beautiful of all his creation.
The beauty of Lucifer somehow turned him
and his heart was lifted up in pride.
Look it up and check it out in your Bible in your concordance.
Because your heart was lifted up with pride
I cast you out.
With no devil to tempt him.
His pride, pride somehow materialized.
It's a mystery.
And some people say
because when God sees pride in us, he goes, Ooh
I know that smell.
That's what ruined heaven.
Pride.
Fentanyl didn't ruin heaven.
Alcohol didn't ruin heaven.
Pride ruined heaven.
In conclusion, ladies and gentlemen of the jury.
The only measure of greatness is who's the best Christian in here?
I can tell you right now.
I happen to know who the best Christian is here.
Not on the platform.
Oh it's easy.
Matthew.
Come to me, no?
That's at the very end.
I need Matthew.
Matthew 18, 2 through 4.
There you go.
He called a little child to him
and he placed a child among them.
And he said, Truly I tell you
unless you change and become like little children
you will never enter the kingdom of heaven.
What are children?
Two-year-old, three-year-old.
They're humble.
They have no self-image to defend.
They're just teachable.
They're moldable.
They're children.
Unless you become like that
you want it to be the kingdom of heaven.
And therefore, whoever takes the lowly position of this child is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven.
I was telling you about
we have deacons who are so unlike what I gave.
These are really beautiful people in my judgment.
Can we thank God for all the deacons and deaconesses that serve here?
Deacon means servant.
Doesn't mean cafe in Spanish.
Boss.
It means servant.
So Jesus is saying here
you know who the greatest is in the whole church?
The one who's most humble.
That could be you.
Why don't you try to make that your goal?
God, work in me as a keyboard player comes.
Work in me so that I can be great in your sight, which is humble.
Let me serve others.
When Jesus the night he was betrayed
what did he tell the disciples to do?
To wash his feet?
Oh no.
You mean he washed their feet?
No, come on.
They're stinking feet that have been out of those dusty roads.
He washed them.
And he said, Now I gave you an example.
I've taken this humble position.
You do the same.
No, no, but listen, Pastor
I've almost memorized the entire book of Ephesians.
That's great.
Memorize it, but make sure the memorization doesn't make you proud.
Because the Bible can make you proud.
Anything can make you proud.
We constantly have to ask God, push it down, Lord, push it down.
What does Spurgeon say, the great preacher
that God keeps his best wines in the lowest part of the basement?
Way down.
So the best Christian here
you don't even know his name or her name.
Nobody will notice them when they walk out.
They'll never have reverend next to their name.
They might never write a book
but in God's sight
they're the best Christian in the whole place.
Beside that, it's the secret of unity in the church.
God hates division and strife.
God hates fighting.
God hates racial fighting, personality fighting
any kind of fighting based on anything.
And look what Romans says.
Live in harmony with one another.
Do not be proud.
But be willing to associate with people of low position.
Don't be conceited.
You ain't all that.
That's another translation of that at the end.
It's a Brooklyn, the New Brooklyn translation.
Have you ever read that?
You ain't all that.
Don't be conceited.
Why?
Because then division.
You know, the Bible says wherever there's fighting
pride is on the bottom.
Check it out.
Wherever there's fighting
if the fighting's going on
any stuff you got going on with your family or friends or former friends
and there's fighting and tension
there's always pride.
Political fighting, pride, pride, pride, pride, pride.
Pride, pride, pride, pride.
Nobody can be corrected.
That's another thing the Bible says.
Think to the humble person
correction is like ointment on their head because they want to learn
they want to be better.
But to the proud
what'd you just say?
Hey, look at me when I'm talking to you.
What did you just say about me?
I thought you loved me.
Why you be correcting me?
That's a proud person.
Can't take correction.
It's like a knife.
Like a knife.
But a humble person?
No, tell me more.
How did I mess up?
Because I want to learn.
I want to learn.
Because humble people realize they're not all that.
So they want to get better.
Amen?
But a proud person
don't you correct them?
Don't you correct them.
They'll jump down your throat.
That's what pride does.
Finally.
It's a secret of worship that I told you about.
Well, let's read that.
I love that.
A lot of verses
but they'll help us today.
To some who are confident of their own righteousness
and look down on everyone else.
Does that not tell it all?
Thank you, Luke, for giving me a summary.
To some who are confident of their own righteousness
I'm basically a good person.
Why are you talking to me like that?
That I need Jesus and all of that.
I'm a good person.
To some who were like that
and look down on everyone else
Jesus told this parable.
So two men went up to the temple to pray,
one a Pharisee, self-legalistic, proud person
and the other a tax collector, looked down on by other people.
And the Pharisee stood by himself and he prayed, God, I thank you
then I'm not like other people.
I'm not a robber, an evildoer, an adulterer.
I'm not even like this guy.
This is a low life next to me.
I'm not, thank God I'm not like him.
I fast twice a week
and give a tenth of all I get.
He's boasting.
Imagine in God's presence
he's telling God that God should be impressed by him.
Is proud, is pride not madness?
He's trying to convince God about his self-worth.
But the tax collector stood at a distance.
He wouldn't even look up to heaven
but just beat his breath.
And he said, God have mercy on me, a sinner.
I tell you, Jesus said
that this man rather than the other went home justified before God.
For all those who exalt themselves will be humble.
End of story.
And those who humble themselves will be exalted.
That's theology 101.
It's never mentioned
it's not written about
there's not many sermons about it.
Whoever goes up, God says
I will bring you down.
Did I just read that?
How come you're not responding?
Did Jesus not say that?
And everyone who exalts themselves, oh God
help me not to exalt myself.
Put me among the lowest of the low
so that when you see fit
you can exalt me.
But don't let me get exalted
because then you're going to bring me down.
Oh yes, you will.
So you can't even you can't even worship God properly.
That's why there are some that worship.
You ever notice this?
The best worshipers are humble people.
Why?
Because God is everything to them.
And others are kind of like
when does this emotional stuff get over?
How many owe him everything today?
Just lift your hand.
I wave your hand just up to God.
Oh God.
We just worship him right now.
Can you open your mouth
and just praise him for his goodness?
Come on, up in the balcony.
Let me hear it.
Downstairs, just give God praise and glory and honor.
Everything comes from you, Lord.
Gracias, Senor, por todo, Senor.
Okay, look up here
just this one last thing here I want to say.
Here's the kicker of it all.
The person who's humble is a roommate of God.
For this is what the high and exalted one says
he who lives forever
whose name is holy.
I live in a high and holy place.
But also with the one who is contrite and lowly in spirit.
My job is to revive the spirit of the lowly
and to revive the heart of the contrite
those who are broken over their sin and who are lowly.
God says, that's where I live.
Oh, I want to go to heaven.
Oh, if I could just be there
the streets are gold.
I've got a mansion just over the hilltop.
Praise God.
I can't wait to walk on Jerusalem Avenue.
That's great, but you can have God living in your own heart
because He lives with those of us
us who want to be lowly, humble
esteeming others better than ourselves.
So here's what the preacher always has to watch out for.
You preach something like this
and people can easily get psyched and say, you know what?
Praise God.
I'm gonna start being humble today.
Yep, no more pride with me.
Pastor Simba, that was a gem.
All those verses, there was a whole lot of them
but there was a lot of good stuff in there.
And as of today
I'm gonna walk in humility.
You don't have a chance.
We're not made for that.
So listen, here's the promise.
Remember, every time God gives a command
there has to be a promise that we can believe so that He can perform
give us the obedience to obey the command.
You get it?
When God says, love one another
even as I've loved you
he doesn't mean we have that love.
He means I'll give you that love so you can obey me.
So listen to this.
You know this first.
Come on.
Come to me, all you who are weary and burdened.
Come on out, choir
and I'll give you rest.
Take my yoke upon you and learn from me.
What can we learn, Jesus?
For I am gentle and humble in heart
and you will find rest for your souls.
Humility brings a rest.
For my yoke is easy and my burden is light.
You know the only one in the whole world that can make us humble is Jesus
because he was the most humble person that ever walked on the earth.
Imagine that.
We should be humble by our sins.
Am I correct?
That's one of the reasons we should be humble
because we failed the Lord.
Jesus never failed God.
He was sinless, perfect
and yet he was the most humble person.
He was the Lamb of God.
You know, sometimes it's hard for me to take God
don't let it happen to me.
But when you see preachers
or or music people entertain
and show off and parade themselves
and I've held this microphone long enough you can know
when someone's talking from their heart
and when someone's doing showtime, you know that.
How can we represent Jesus being proud
when he was the lowly Lamb of God?
You know why we're saved today?
Because he went down.
Oh, he went down
he went really down, down to the cross.
How many say amen?
Down to death, down to the tomb.
And then God, because he humbled himself
gave him a name above every other name.
And at the name of Jesus.
Every knee should bow, every tongue confess.
You know what I want to sing, brother?
You know that song we the one that Sue ended with.
Jesus, that one.
So if you can get in that key.
How many want to look to the Lord today for the blessing of humility?
Come on.
We've never, hardly ever heard that said.
Lift them up both hands, right?
By the way, you know why it's good to lift up hands?
That's humbling.
Come on, lift them up.
Come on.
Oh, don't be so proud.
Lift up your hands.
In the culture, people are lifting up their hands to what?
Athletes, rock stars, people in clubs
they worship their idols
and we can't lift our hands to God.
All the men in the downstairs here, get up here and come up here and form a choir.
Come on.
I need some men.
The women are fine
but I need some men up here, okay?
Come on, men.
Every man, let's sing.
Sing.
Come on, men.
Come on, man.
Sing with me.
Come on, can you open your mouth and give him praise?
We give you praise.
We give you honor.
We give you glory.
You are everything, Lord.
I have nothing except what you give me, Lord.
From you are all things
to you are all things, Lord.
Gracias, Senor, por todo, Senor.
Gracias, Senhor.
Thank you, Lord.
Keep praising him.
Come on, everyone, praise him.
Use your mouth, use your hands
praise him from your heart.
We praise you.
We exalt you alone, Lord.
Not unto us, but unto you be the glory and honor, Lord.
Oh Jesus, we love you.
Sing my everything, sing my everything.
I asked you in the name of Christ.
One last time, sing his name.
Jesus, we're overwhelmed today.
I'm just thinking, Lord, of that verse.
But being in the form of God, equal with God, you humbled yourself.
You left heaven.
You took on the form of a man.
You got hungry.
You knew pain.
You got thirsty.
They beat you.
But by humbling yourself
God has given you a name above every other name.
That at the name of Jesus every knee shall bow, every tongue confess.
Why?
Because you humbled yourself.
Lord, would you please work in us?
Would you engraft your humility into our hearts?
That'll put away all fighting, all competition, all arguing, all dissension.
It'll bring blessings untold into our lives
for you resist the proud
but you give grace to the humble.
Anyone who goes down in humility, you've promised
you will exalt that person.
You will exalt that person.
We don't want your hand on us to bring us down.
We want your hand picking us up, lifting us, blessing us.
Some of us of us as even grown up in church
and in church you can be proud.
There are proud churches, proud ministers, proud whatever.
Pride lives everywhere.
It was in heaven before there was a devil.
Well, we ask you to banish that from our hearts.
Help us to live only for your glory
to serve one another is better than ourselves, and lastly
to think of ourselves.
And when the devil comes and says, Oh
you'll never be happy you live that way
he's a liar.
The best life in the world is to live only for you, Jesus.
We give you all the glory.
We give you all the honor.
God, how do we do this today?
That we want you to know you deserve all the glory and honor from our lives.
Thanksgiving that we don't even care about last Thursday.
Every day is Thanksgiving for us, Lord
because you've done so much.
Everything we have comes from you.
Lord, bless the offering when we take it as we leave
and help the people to give.
In humility, honoring you.
The welcome center, just our fellowship together.
Just make it all sweet.
But before we dismiss, Lord
we're going to give you the loudest possible standing ovation we've ever given you in this place.
One, two, three.
Come on, let's praise him.
Shout to the Lord!
Shout to the Lord.