welcome everyone let's stand to our feet
praise the lord god so met us at the nine o'clock service
and he is going to be faithful to come
and meet us today
but let's welcome his presence into this place amen
let's open our hearts today
forget about whatever you brought in this building
jesus is more than capable of taking care of all of it
Let's focus our eyes on him today and open our hearts.
Give him all the praise that he deserves.
Amen?
Come on, let's clap.
We're made of others' presence.
The Spirit is with us.
We are here together to lift our hearts as one.
We're made of others' presence.
The Spirit is with us.
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
it is right to give Him thanks and praise.
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain.
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
it is right to give Him thanks and praise.
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain.
Each and every morning
we'll tell of His great love, of all His faithful mercy.
And all that he has done Each
and every morning
We will tell of his great love Of all his faithful mercies
And all that he has done
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give him thanks
and praise For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never take.
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God.
It is right to give Him thanks and praise.
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never take.
Come on, lift your voice and sing!
Glory, honor, wisdom, power, and strength
to our Savior, Jesus, worthy of all praise.
to our Savior, Jesus
worthy be our praise.
It is good to live in the name of the Lord our God.
It is right to give Him thanks and praise.
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never take.
It is good to let the name of the Lord our God
in his life to give him thanks and praise.
For his heart is overflowing with love for us
and his mercy we can never take.
Of glory, honor, wisdom, power, and strength.
To our Savior, Jesus, body of all things,
glory, honor, wisdom, power, and strength.
To our Savior, Jesus.
Worthy of all praise.
It is good to let the name of the Lord our God.
It is right to give Him thanks and praise.
For His heart is overflowing with love for us.
And His mercy we can never contain.
It is good to let the name of the Lord our God.
It is right to give Him thanks and praise.
For his heart is full of glory with love for us
and his mercy we can never take.
Glory, Father, with the power and strength to our Savior,
Jesus, worthy of all praise.
Glory, Father, With the power and strength
To our Savior Jesus Worthy of all praise
Glory, honor With the power and strength
To our Savior Jesus, worthy of all praise.
It is good to live in the name of the Lord our God.
It is right to give thanks and praise.
For his heart is overflowing with love for us.
And his mercy we can never take.
It is good to live to the name of the Lord our God.
It is right to give him thanks and praise.
For his heart is overflowing with love for us.
And his mercy we can never contain.
Come on, get your voice to the Lord.
Just give him praise this afternoon.
We bow to thy name.
We bless your name, Jesus.
You are worthy of your word.
We praise you, Jesus.
We hear your glory and honor.
Hallelujah, we bless your name.
Receive our praise today, Lord.
Come on, let's sing it.
Glory, honor, wisdom, power, and strength
to our Savior, Jesus, worthy of all praise.
Glory, honor, wisdom power and strength to our savior jesus
jesus Oh, praise, glory, honor, wisdom, power, and strength
to our Savior
Jesus, worthy of all praise.
It is good to live the name of the Lord our God.
It is right to give Him thanks and praise.
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain.
It is good to live the name of the Lord our God.
It is right to give Him thanks and praise.
For His heart Hallelujah!
Hallelujah!
As we prepare Just to sing the next chorus
I was sharing with the 9 o'clock service
the women were going to be starting a small group series
from the book,
The Exciting New Life by Andrew Murray.
Highly recommended by the leadership of this church.
It's like going to Bible school
if you just read through that book.
And I've been going through it.
And I stopped on a chapter
and I was sharing it
up at the Sanctus Young Adults Retreat this weekend.
My husband and I were there.
And it's this idea of
we're just singing, right?
For his heart, God's heart
is overflowing with love for us.
His heart is overflowing.
We're not coming into God's presence saying
please pay attention to me.
Please be interested in my life.
Please care about what I'm going through.
We're worshiping today because we're able to sing.
His heart is overflowing with love for us.
And his mercy we can never contain.
Think about that.
His mercy.
How many of us need mercy today?
This is the truth of God's word and who Jesus is.
We could never contain the mercy
that is offered to us through Jesus Christ.
And so there's this particular chapter in the book
that talks about the surrender of Christ to the believer.
And what I love about the book is
it doesn't start
with all the things that we need to do as Christians.
And really none of the book is about that.
It's more about everything that Jesus has done for us.
and will do in and through us as we look to him
as we depend on him.
And so the chapter is called The Surrender of Christ
and it just talks about
and it just blew me away, you know, for whatever reason
that's the chapter I just kept pondering and meditating on
that Christ has surrendered himself to us.
He's given himself.
Jesus Christ, King of Kings, Lord of Lords,
the Alpha and the Omega
the beginning and the end, has surrendered himself.
And that's why
verses throughout the New Testament talk about
for he so loved the church that Christ gave himself.
There are countless verses throughout the New Testament
that use that phrase over and over again
that Jesus has given himself.
He surrendered himself on a cross
because of his incredible, passionate love.
For us, he surrendered himself.
He came from heaven and surrendered his own life so
that we could be restored into relationship with him.
And now that the barrier of sin has been removed
and there's nothing standing in between us.
and intimacy with the Father
who is the source of everything that we need today.
I don't care what your need is today.
I don't care what you brought in here today.
Jesus is the answer.
You were made for him, by him, to glorify him
to be fulfilled by him alone.
That's what heaven will be.
Finally, to be in his presence
and nothing to be in the way, no sin, no physical body,
just in the presence of Jesus
and fully fulfilled and satisfied by him alone.
He wants us to experience that here on earth
and the Bible says it would be from glory to glory
to glory to come
and experience and know what this means
that Christ has given himself to you.
What have we done to deserve that?
Nothing.
But he has given himself, and he says
everything that I am now.
is yours everything that i am i have surrendered
what an incredible word i have surrendered myself to you so
that you would lack nothing today you are not alone
today you have jesus
and everything that he is you are his heir today
and he is yours everything that he has in yours so
whatever your need is today
don't be downcast Jesus is the answer
and he is yours completely if you put your faith in him.
He is yours completely.
He gives himself to you today.
And he just wants you to learn how to receive all that he
is.
The fullness of life that he gives us
because of what he did on the cross.
And it's through that
that then we come into worship.
Not this obligatory thing of now I've got to worship.
It's the right thing to do.
But we love him because he first loved us.
And now in response to a God who would give himself for us.
who held nothing back but surrenders himself to us.
Now, it's out of love
it's out of gratitude
that we give our lives back to him and say
now take all of me.
You've given me all of you
so now here is all of me, God.
Here's my heart.
Here's my life.
Here's my worship.
I put no idols before me, Jesus.
You are my God.
You are my King.
You are my Savior.
You are my everything.
And I give you the highest praise today.
Amen?
So let's sing that now with all of our hearts,
hearts of gratitude and worship
to a Savior who has given himself
everything that he is to you today.
Celebrate that today and glorify his name.
Amen?
Hallelujah.
Let's sing it together.
I lift my voice to sing of your goodness.
I lift my voice to sing of your love.
I lift my voice to sing hallelujah.
Jesus, our Savior, the worthy of it all.
I lift my voice to sing of your goodness.
I lift my voice to sing of your love.
I lift my voice to sing hallelujah.
Jesus our Savior, you're worthy of it all.
We give you the highest praise.
We give you the I lift my head because I'm forgiven.
I lift my head because I'm set free.
I lift my hands, a sign of surrender.
Jesus, our Savior, you're worthy of it all.
We lift our voice.
We give you the highest praise.
we we we
This is the promise, amen?
I lift my eyes to look to your coming I lift my eyes
I know you'll return.
You will reign in glory forever.
You will reign.
We give you the highest praise.
Jesus our Savior, your worthy of all.
We give you the we give you the highest We praise you, Lord.
We praise you, Jesus.
Highest praise.
Hallelujah.
With all our hearts, O God.
We bless your name.
Thank you for giving yourself to us, Lord.
For surrendering your life to us, O God.
That everything that you are is ours today, Lord.
Hallelujah.
We praise you, Jesus.
We worship you, Lord.
We bless your name.
We love you, Jesus.
We love you, Lord.
We love you.
We adore you, Jesus.
Oh, what a mighty God you are.
Hallelujah, hallelujah.
Hallelujah.
Just continue to worship him.
He inhabits the praise of his people.
Hallelujah.
Receive our praise today, Lord.
Oh, let it bless your heart today, God.
We worship and adore you, Jesus.
Hallelujah, hallelujah.
We worship you, Lord.
We praise you, Jesus.
We glorify your name, Lord.
We glorify your name, Jesus.
hallelujah you are worthy jesus you are worthy
you are worthy you are worthy
jesus we give you the highest praise
oh lord all of our hearts all of our lives
oh god we surrender to you
even as you've surrendered yourself to us
oh god hallelujah jesus Hallelujah, Lord
we bless you in Jesus.
Hallelujah, you are worthy, Jesus.
Precious Lord, You are so beautiful today, O God.
Lord, we thank you for your presence, O God.
You truly inhabit the praise of your people, God.
Be enthroned in our worship today, O Lord.
King of kings and Lord of lords, we bless you.
We worship you, Lord.
We exalt your name.
Oh, God, we praise Jesus.
Your people praise your name.
Hallelujah, hallelujah, hallelujah, Jesus.
We worship you, Lord.
Let's sing that verse together.
All the saints and angels bow before you.
The elders cast their crowning o'er the land of God and sea.
You are worthy of it all.
For from you are all things
and to you are all things.
You deserve the glory.
Let's sing that verse again.
All the saints and angels bow All the elders have
they've found you're the Lamb of God and see
you are worthy of the Lord.
You are worthy of the Lord.
Both of you are all things
and to you are all things.
You deserve the glory.
Come on with all our hearts.
You are worthy of it.
Lord God, You are all things
and to You are all things.
You deserve the glory.
You are worthy of Him all.
For from you are all things
and to you are all things.
You deserve the glory.
Let's lift our hands and sing, everyone.
You are worthy of your love.
For from you are all things
and to you are all things.
You deserve the glory.
One more time, let the church sing to the Lord.
You are worthy of it all.
Amen.
I'd like to share something with you.
Give God glory.
About three days ago
I was busy ministering in different places this past week.
Around Thursday, I started to get
some severe pains in my head.
And even to the touch
my wife got alarmed because...
It was very weird.
I couldn't lay in the pillow the right way.
And my left eye just was not functioning right.
And there was pain.
I didn't know what it was.
And I'm the type that, ah
it'll get better tomorrow.
But it didn't get better tomorrow.
So it was really bad.
And so I was alone last night praying with my Bible open
and wanting to get something to feed you with today.
And it was bothering me.
So I went to bed.
And when I laid on the pillow
I was having pain.
I don't think I'm a complainer
but I was experiencing pain.
So I tried to sleep through it.
About three in the morning
I got up again.
And I said, no
the Lord's woken me up for something.
So I went out of the bedroom to talk with the Lord.
And I said to the Lord, Lord
I can't do what you want me to do tomorrow.
Unless you heal me because I can't function this way.
I can't do this.
And there was no one to pray for me.
But when there's no one around to pray for you
you just pray for yourself.
Amen.
So my head in most places was sensitive to the touch.
And I just prayed, called on the Lord, prayed for a while,
went back to bed, drifted off to sleep,
got up this morning and.
I was a little bit sideways, I think, even this morning.
But I came to the church
and I was sitting in my office alone.
And suddenly, as I was worshiping the Lord
I felt like God just touched me.
And I touched my head.
There was no pain.
I felt my eye.
So I have no pain.
And we thank God for no pain.
Jesus is alive and he can still heal.
I am the Lord that healeth thee.
I am the Lord your healer.
I send my word
and if you need healing come on up to the front right now
everyone who needs a touch from the lord balcony included
come down here to the front
sing everyone I send my word and heal your disease.
I am the Lord your healer.
Come on, sing out loud.
Everyone sing.
I am the Lord that healeth thee.
I am the Lord I am the Lord your healer I send my word
and heal your disease I am the Lord your healer
Lift up your hands here in the front.
Lift them to the Lord.
I am the Lord that healeth thee
I sent my word and healed your disease.
I am the Lord your healer.
I am the Lord that healeth thee.
I send my word in courtesy.
I am the Lord.
Keep moving, choir members, and pray.
Sing congregation.
I am the Lord.
Call on the Lord.
Master Brian, quick.
Trust him.
Jesus, we thank you today for how you've reminded us.
You've given us everything.
You've held no good thing from us.
And as you walked among us
one of the ways
that you expressed all that you had longed to give
is a healing touch.
In so many ways and so many examples through the Gospels,
Lord
we have these accounts of how as you walked among us
you opened blind eyes
you brought healing to the infirm God.
And we thank you that you haven't changed
that you're the same today as you've always been.
And we thank you that on the cross you paid a price
that allowed whatever the obstructions would be
to stand in the way of your grace
and your love being made alive in us.
God, we thank you that by stripes, your stripes
we find healing today.
Amen.
That there is a Savior who still cares
and is able to meet the needs of people
as they look to Him and trust Him for it.
God, give them hope today as you touch them.
We have hope in you, God.
We trust you.
But God, confirm, Lord
in our hearts today just how alive you are
and how you see and how you want to move and touch.
Make your grace alive.
Make it real.
Even now we pray.
That Jesus would be glorified.
That we would know blessing, God, to become a blessing.
That through that, Jesus would be lifted up and glorified.
Touch the people here.
Touch the people online.
For your glory, we pray.
It's in Jesus' name we all ask and sing.
Amen.
Stay where you are.
Choir, come back quick.
Let's solidify Pastor Brian's prayer.
Everybody lift up one hand.
We're going to sing that word of God one more time, okay?
I am the Lord, that healeth thee.
I am the Lord, your healer.
I accept my word and heal your disease.
And Lord, we pray that
surgeries will be canceled
in the mighty name of Jesus Christ
for his honor and glory.
And everyone said, Yeah.
Hallelujah, glory to be praised!
Hallelujah, glory to be praised.
I lift my hands.
I lift my hands
I praise you Lord.
I bow my head
I honor you Lord.
Hallelujah, glory to the brave
Hallelujah, glory to the brave Hallelujah
glory to the brave I lift my head I praise you, Lord.
I bow my head.
I honor you, Lord.
I lift my hands.
I praise you, Lord.
I bow my head.
I honor you, Lord.
Hallelujah.
Go over to me, praise.
Hallelujah, God wants you to be praised.
Hallelujah, you're worthy.
Hallelujah, we praise and hate.
Hallelujah, so worthy.
Hallelujah, Lord, we lift you up.
Hallelujah, you're worthy.
Alleluia, we praise your name.
Alleluia, it's over.
Alleluia.
Hallelujah, we praise your name.
Hallelujah, so worthy.
Hallelujah, Lord we lift you up.
Hallelujah, you're worthy.
Hallelujah, we praise your name.
Hallelujah, you're so worthy.
Hallelujah, Lord we lift you up.
Hallelujah, you're worthy.
Hallelujah, we praise your name.
Hallelujah, you're so worthy.
Hallelujah, Lord we lift you up Hallelujah
you're worthy Hallelujah
we praise your name Hallelujah, so worthy Hallelujah
Lord we lift you up Lord we lift you up
I lift my hands in total adoration unto you.
You reign on the throne.
For you are God and God alone.
Because of you my cloudy days are gone.
I can sing to you this song.
I just wanna say that I love you more than anything
I lift my hands in total adoration unto you
You reign on the throne For you are God
and God alone Because of you my cloudy days are gone.
I can sing to you this song.
I just want to say
that I love you more than anything.
Hold me in your arms.
You were my shelter from the storm
When all my friends were gone You were right there all along
I've never known a love like this before I just want to say
that I love you more than anything.
I love you, Jesus.
I worship and adore you.
Just want to tell you Lord
I love you more than anything.
I love you, Jesus.
I worship and adore you.
Just want to tell you.
Lord, I love you more than anything.
I love you, Jesus.
I worship and adore.
Just want to tell you.
Lord, I love you more than any.
I love you, Jesus.
I worship and adore you.
Just want to tell you.
I love you, Jesus.
I worship and adore you.
Just want to tell you, Lord
I love you more than anything.
I love you, Jesus.
I worship and adore you.
Just want to tell you.
Oh, I love you more than anything.
Thank you.
I was lost in my sin
when he found me Broken
and in despair Desperately searching for something
For someone who
Then I met Christ the Savior Who gave His life for me
Overwhelmed by His mercy
And all He's done for me Forgive me.
My life has changed since Jesus came and loved me.
Forgive me.
I know I'm new.
Now I see.
Now I believe.
Now I know His love for me.
When I think of how far I have wandered Wounded
and filled with shame I stand amazed
that He loved me Before I called on His name
I had heard of the love of Jesus.
Oh, but I never thought it could be
that He would show so much mercy and save someone like me.
He loved me, forgave me.
My life has changed since Jesus came.
And He loved me, forgave me.
I know I'll never be I see, now I believe.
Now, I know His love for me.
I know His love for me.
he loved me forgave me my life has changed he loved me
and loved me and he forgave me my life
Stay for a second, choir.
We want to do as we did earlier today, have a prayer.
I'm going to ask Didi if, step forward, Brother Didi
and he's going to pray.
We have two things going on that I want you to know about.
Number one is tomorrow, about 284 children ages 9 through 13
leave the church on buses
and they go up to the largest BT Kids retreat we've ever had
and it's the longest.
It's from Monday through the Sunday, I think.
Yeah, they get back on Saturday, Sunday.
So there's 284 of these little ones, young people
and a good number of them are not part of the church.
They're not regular attendees at the BT Kids.
So they're unchurched.
We don't know what they know about the Lord.
But that's perfect.
Amen.
They're going to learn about Jesus up at that camp.
And that's a great age to get them, 9 through 13.
So also, they understand
there'll be some behavioral problems
or special needs situations.
So we need the counselors.
And Miss Amy, who's up there.
And all the workers up there.
They need a special anointing of the Holy Spirit on them.
Do you agree with me?
Because we've got to see a breakthrough for these children.
Got to see it.
So we're going to pray for that.
Didi's going to lead us.
The second thing is...
On Wednesday of this week
you join with me on Tuesday for our prayer meeting, please.
I invite you to come.
I'll be here and we'll seek the Lord together, worship.
But on Wednesday, a representative group of the choir
is going to be getting on an airplane
and traveling through Atlanta to Baton Rouge, Louisiana.
And from there, about a half hour, 40 minutes.
to the prison at Louisiana State Penitentiary.
It's called Angola.
For those of you visiting, the average sentence
this is the most serious prison.
It was the most infamous prison in America decades ago.
God's done something there, but 5,200 inmates.
It's as big as the island of Manhattan
and the average sentence is 91 years.
You have sex offenders in there with 300-year sentences
and death row where guys are appealing.
And they're going there for two concerts
and I'm going to preach the gospel after each one.
God's made it all possible through donation.
Listen, I had lunch with the person who wanted to go,
who told me
I heard you want to go to Angola.
We got an invitation from a more receptive...
How can I say it?
Warden, the first warden that we worked with,
our dear, dear friend.
But he moved on to Mississippi.
And then the other warden
didn't want so much of this Jesus stuff happening there.
And now there's a new warden who God has healed.
He came close to death.
And he talked to me on the phone.
I can't wait to see him, my friend.
And he told me, listen, pastor
when you see me
I'm a living miracle.
God brought me back from the dead.
That'll get Jesus in your life real quick, right?
And in the prison.
So he's very hospitable.
He's looking forward to it.
I shared that with the man.
What a blessing God is.
He said, what's it going to cost to move all those people?
Airfares, hotels, food, the whole thing.
I gave him a round number
which I had checked into
and he just took out a checkbook, and he wrote
and he paid for the whole thing.
Can we thank God?
Come on, can we thank God for the open door
and then the money that's been supplied?
So, Dini's going to pray also that the choir is anointed
that God gives me the right words to say.
We're going to visit also
not everyone can come to these two concerts.
Some guys are locked up because of behavioral trouble.
They're in Camp J.
They don't get out of their cell but one hour a day.
And then there's dozens and dozens of guys.
who are on death row
and we're going to go visit them.
And, you know, I was telling someone today
you just go from cell to cell.
It's beautiful ministry.
You go from cell to cell.
Here's a cell.
And I look in
and the guy's in his shorts sitting on the cot
and he looks at me
and he gets up.
That means he wants to talk.
And he walks and he goes, who are you?
I tell him, we start to talk, pray with him.
I go to the next cell after a while.
If that guy just goes like that
that means he doesn't want to talk.
I go to the next cell.
I just keep telling people about Jesus.
They're going to sing about Jesus.
I'm going to talk about Jesus.
But without the power of the Holy Spirit helping us
it's just words, palabras.
We need poder, power.
Amen?
Would you bow your head and pray?
Didi, pray.
So, Father God, we come to you this afternoon
humble before you, God.
We humble ourselves before you.
We stand here accepted, forgiven, loved by you, God
with a love that surpasses all understanding.
So, God, as we stand before you
we ask for your help.
With the kids, God
that are going to retreat, Father
we pray As Moses said
if you don't go with us
we will not go.
So Lord, I pray that you will equip the leaders.
We are empty vessels.
We want you to fill us with your spirit.
That the words of our mouth
the meditations of our heart will be acceptable to you, God.
May you fill us with your spirit, God.
I pray that these keys that will encounter your love
even as Paul said
that it will know you
and the power of your resurrection.
And the power of your love, God.
And I thank you, God
even as I stand here
my testimony of knowing you at a very, very young age.
I pray that these kids will also have a testimony, God.
That they will know you, God.
That you will keep them from harm, God.
That you will protect them
and that you will put your hands on each one of them, God.
We thank you, Father.
Lord, we also pray for the choir
that's calling to the prison,
God,
and even for Pastor God.
We pray, God, that you will give them the ability
to articulate,
even with the songs
and the preaching,
God, the many troubles that this man and this woman
go through,
God.
I pray that your power will go with them.
I pray that your spirit will go with them.
Even I pray that you will go before them, God.
Even before they get there
you will be there, God.
You will be there preparing the heart of God,
breaking ground for the gospel to penetrate the heart.
For you have come, God
to give us life and life abundantly.
May this be the gift from them as well, God.
We thank you and we love you.
In Jesus' mighty name we pray.
Amen.
Thank you.
Thank you, my brother.
Bye-bye choir.
Thank you.
Great work.
Let's hear for the choir so they know we appreciate them.
God is good, isn't he?
He keeps, you know
my wife's over here.
She wrote that last song.
That's one of my favorite songs.
He loved me.
Do you like that song?
He loved me, forgave me.
My life has changed since Jesus came and loved me.
So I was thinking
You see this front row here
and then the row behind it.
Those two rows of people.
That was the entire congregation on a good day
when we first came.
That row and the row behind.
And the auditorium was not as big as the lobby
over here on Smith Street.
And boy, I was thinking about it,
talking with pastors in another state this week.
Boy, it was...
We didn't know what to expect.
It was hard at times, fighting discouragement.
But look how good the Lord has done.
And I want you to know from my wife and I and the pastors
I know you're going to think, oh
you're being melodramatic.
As God is listening, we love you.
We love you.
Hold steady, please.
And we thank God for you.
And I tell, Elaine happens to be helping me today.
I'll turn to her and say
this is the sweetest group of people in the entire world.
And it is.
We have our, you know
irregulars like any church has.
But the way you worship God
the way you pray
I just sometimes sit over here and weep.
Because I think of all the days when there was no music
while my wife was always Excellent on the keyboard
but God has done a good thing.
How about in your life?
You ever look back?
How many, wait, how many look back on your life?
God has brought you a very long way.
Wave your hand at me.
It took you a long, long way.
Over mountains you didn't think you'd get over
through valleys that seem so long.
Would you please remember to share in your giving online?
Those of you online, please help us.
And then there's a physical offering taken as you leave.
But please, don't be a non-giver.
And I say this, you know, if you
how can I say this?
You should give and tithe to the church that you go to
and you're a member.
Pay your bill at the restaurant where you ate.
If you eat a Chick-fil-A and they say, okay
give me your credit card.
Oh, no, I'm going to pay a junior store
in downtown Brooklyn.
Try that out and see how it works, okay?
And I say that to our own detriment.
If you're a member of another church
you should be giving there.
But if you come here
you feel led to give to another church somewhere
where you used to live,
praise God
do as you feel led.
But that's not the way the church is sustained.
We should be faithful in the place where God put us.
Did I say that with sensitivity?
I want you to know that.
That's important.
And it helps us pay the bills.
And we got some big, big bills coming up soon.
We have to change our whole computer system.
I can't even explain it.
And since we've been here 20-some years now,
our whole HVAC system heating, air conditioning
the brain that works it
everything has to be fixed.
You know what that means?
Mucho dinero.
Comprende?
No comprende?
Mucho dinero.
And where is that?
God's going to supply everything.
God's going to supply.
Let's clap that God supplies everything we need.
Your phone?
So if you gave
I want to introduce my message.
If you gave this smartphone
, this cell phone to someone from Siberia in northern Russia
who had never used a cell phone
or some remote tribe in the South Pacific
or just someplace where there's no phones.
Thank you, Jeffrey.
Jeffrey, he is some keyboard player.
Do you hear what that guy is doing over there?
Thank you, Jeffrey.
so if you gave this phone to someone
and said here's how you make a call
it's your phone now it's yours so they make a call
so now you come back three days later
and you see in their room there's papers everywhere
there's cds there's all this stuff
and you go how'd you enjoy the phone
well
yeah
good i call the family member
and all of that what's all the paper with the numbers on it
Oh, I had to do some adding, subtracting.
I had to check on banking stuff.
What is 10% of this and that?
And then Elaine would say, no
you didn't need to write that out.
The phone does it.
You go to utilities or whatever and you hit it
and now you have adding, subtraction,
division and multiplication.
No.
Yeah, you wasted hours figuring out all that math stuff.
You didn't have to do that.
And what's the camera with all that film
that you bought at the drugstore?
Oh, I need it.
I want to take pictures.
No, you can take pictures with this.
No, it's a phone.
No, no, it's a new kind of phone.
And she got a picture of her children
or grandchildren or somebody.
Someone, you know, you don't buy music.
You download it on your phone.
What?
I can hear music on this thing?
Yeah, you can do a lot of things.
And all those trips that you went to the store to buy
there's something called Amazon Prime.
Oh, that rang a bell.
How many know about Amazon Prime?
Oh, yeah.
Those boxes are flying around.
Are you kidding?
I had all of that
and I didn't know how to use it.
And I wasted hours, hours, money, all kinds of things.
I took my car.
I went shopping.
I got a ticket.
That's going to cost me extra.
You mean I could have just got this
and when would they send it?
Like in a week or two?
No, next day.
Am I right?
Someone told me you get it same day.
True?
So, you know, being a Christian many times is like this.
We have everything that God promised we would need,
and then some
beyond what we could ask or think.
But if we don't know we have it, we're adding, subtracting
we're doing all these primitive things.
Thank you.
We do all these things
and we don't know.
No, when you're a Christian
you have everything you need.
You know, we sang that chorus a few weeks ago.
He is all I need.
Sing it.
Keep going.
Jesus is all I need.
He is all I need.
Now, when Jesus was here on earth
when it got time for him to give his life on the cross
he started telling the disciples
I'm going to send someone to help you.
I'm leaving, but I'm sending another helper.
I'll be gone.
I'll be seated in heaven.
I'm not coming back until I come back.
But you'll have someone working in you.
I've only been able to be with you.
He was in a physical body.
So if I was here
Jesus could be there.
Peter could be here, Jesus there.
But he said when the Holy Spirit comes
he'll be in you.
Many people learn to appreciate
as Christians the ministry of Jesus
and what he did on the cross.
But they're not so clear and a little fuzzy.
on why the Holy Spirit is so important.
Especially when you realize this
the only thing God can do on earth
everything he does on earth,
has to be accomplished through the Holy Spirit.
To the degree that you
and I and this church experience the Holy Spirit
that's what we'll be able to know of God and do for God.
Because there's no option B. It's Holy Spirit or bust.
So my wife and I have been talking a lot lately.
In some churches, they grow up.
Some of you possibly visiting have grown up.
No emphasis on the Holy Spirit.
No mention,
even though it's all throughout the New Testament.
And the Holy Spirit is identified with wildfire
and crazy stuff going on in certain kinds of churches.
So you write it off and you say, oh, that's wildfire.
Then on the other side, there is wildfire.
So it's a morgue.
or it's an insane asylum.
It's a cemetery
or they're bouncing off the walls
doing things that are not even mentioned in the Bible.
So today I want to give you
because last week we talked about
how the Holy Spirit helps you get through
when the going gets tough
.
I want to tell you right now
about some other things
the wonderful Holy Spirit has promised to do for us.
But like the phone
if you don't know it
you won't avail yourself of it.
So Jesus talked about it
and now Paul writes about it in Romans chapter 8,
and he says, you, Christians in Rome,
however, are not in the realm of the flesh.
You used to live just obeying the impulses of the flesh.
Drink, drugs, sex, money,
lying, hate, kill, racial prejudice,
whatever, whatever.
It ignited you.
That's how you lived.
But now you are in the realm of the Spirit, the Holy Spirit.
If indeed the Spirit of God lives in you, in you.
And if anyone does not have the Spirit of Christ
they do not belong to Christ.
So everybody here listen now
because I want to clear conscience when I sleep tonight.
You have to know this.
In the early church
And until this day
the way you can tell a Christian
and the only way you know a Christian
is they have the Holy Spirit living inside of them.
They've been born again.
They have a new life.
Not go to church.
Not a member of a church.
Not own a Bible.
Not believe in the man upstairs.
Not try to live a good life.
That does not make you a Christian.
You must, Jesus said, be born again.
How many are with me so far?
Say amen.
And that Spirit of Christ that comes and lives inside of us,
Paul says
if anyone doesn't have that
they're not a Christian.
I know, but they try to live a good life.
I know, but they're not a Christian.
A Christian is supernatural.
You've either had that supernatural experience
or you haven't.
And it's our job here to encourage you
if you have not been born again
it doesn't just confess your sins
and throw yourself on the mercy of god
and receive christ and what he did on the cross
okay so the holy spirit is given
and we're the temples of the holy spirit
each one of us individually
that'd be refreshing
tomorrow wake up the holy spirit lives within me
inside everything i say
he's going to hear Anything I watch
he's going to have to look at it with me.
Every place I go
I drag him into that place.
Probably be a life changer.
How many say amen?
But if you're not conscious of that
you have you here and God over there.
And once in a while
he might visit you in a meeting.
But that's not so.
He lives inside of all of us.
Why?
Well, one of the great reasons
why we learn later on in that chapter
,
it says
for those who are led by the Spirit of God
are the children of God.
The Spirit you receive, the Holy Spirit
does not make you slaves
like you were to sin, driven, compulsive.
You had to do it so
that you live in fear again.
Rather, The Spirit you receive
brought about your adoption to sonship,
and by him, by the Spirit, we cry, Abba, Father, Father.
The Spirit, Holy Spirit himself
testifies with our inner human spirit
that we are God's children.
So here's number one reason
one of the reasons God gave us the Holy Spirit
is the Holy Spirit lives within me and testifies
assures my human spirit
you are not what you used to be.
You are a new creation.
And that spirit bears witness with our human spirit.
We're not what we want to be.
We're not what we should be.
But how many know without a shadow of a doubt
you are not what you used to be?
Lift your hand.
Why do we know that?
The spirit bears witness with our spirit.
We are children of God.
When we pray, we're not praying to some foreign God.
We're praying, Father, Father, Abba, Father
which is another way of saying Father, Father, Father.
Satan will attack and say
you're not a believer of this.
He'll condemn you.
But the Holy Spirit bears witness with our spirit.
You are a child of God.
You're in the family of God.
I am in the family of God.
The Holy Spirit lives inside of me
and tells me no matter what failings I have
and where I mess up
I am a child of God.
How many know without a shadow of a doubt
you are a child of God?
Wave your hand at me, come on.
Not churchgoer, not just churchgoer, but a child of God.
The Spirit bears witness.
The scripture goes on further
that he that is joined to the Lord
is one spirit with the Lord.
Paul talks about that in 2 Corinthians.
So the merging is the spirit of God
merges with my human spirit.
And now I'm that new creation.
I'm not the old Jim Cimbala.
You're not the old you.
You're a new you.
Because Christ is in you.
How is Christ in you?
Through the presence of the Holy Spirit.
Comprende?
No comprende.
So now, notice why it's so important
the Holy Spirit lives within us.
Well, it's like this.
In the Old Testament
we had the law.
We had Moses and we had commands given by God
etched on stone.
And that revealed God's holiness.
Don't kill.
Don't commit adultery.
Don't lie.
Don't steal.
Don't bear false witness.
Honor your mother and father
and so on and so forth.
So that was those commands.
The only trouble was they were written on stone
and my problem is not stone.
My problem is my heart, my mind.
How many are like me, right?
To agree with my head.
Oh, yeah, that's true.
That's the way I should live.
But how are you going to do it?
How are you going to do it?
So that was the old covenant.
Now the promises started to come in the Old Testament
that one day Messiah would come.
And Messiah would be the deliverer.
He would be that ideal son of God, son of man.
He would be the answer to Israel's problems.
So everyone was waiting for Messiah, serious Jews.
When will Messiah come?
Rachel had a baby.
I wonder if that's Messiah.
There's a preacher out there.
Is he Messiah?
Oh, there's a guy called John the Baptist.
Maybe he's the Messiah. was waiting for Messiah.
And the Bible tells us in detail
that Messiah would be born in Bethlehem
in the book of Micah.
It tells us he would be ripped
and torn apart on a cross.
It tells us they would pluck out his beard.
They would beat him so bad he wouldn't be recognizable
and so on and so forth.
But along with those promises about Messiah
there were other promises
about something else coming from God.
And that was the Spirit of God giving us a whole new inside
a whole new person
like I've been saying.
So Ezekiel was one who prophesied the new covenant.
And here's what God said he would do,
not in Ezekiel's day, but one day in the future.
I will sprinkle clean water on you and you will be clean.
I will cleanse you from all your impurities
and from all your idols.
Notice who will do that.
I will.
God says I will.
Not you.
I will.
I will give you a new heart.
Oh, I'll give you a new heart.
Why?
What's wrong with the old one?
It's hopeless.
Did you know that you're hopeless without God's new heart?
That's what born again means.
You have a new mind, a new heart, a new spirit.
And I'll put a new spirit in you.
I'll remove from you your heart of stone,
that hardness and and arrogance and pride and stubbornness.
And I'll give you a heart of flesh, tender.
I'll make you compassionate.
But here's the key.
And I will put my spirit in you
and move you to follow my decrees
and be careful to keep my laws.
Who will make me live different?
The spirit that God will put in us
will move us to be more like Christ.
Give us new desires.
How many, since you're a Christian
you have new desires like you never had before?
You have a desire to pick up the Bible and read it.
You never had one of those
when you were clubbing every weekend, right?
So there's new desires
there's new longings.
Notice how this is the only way to defeat that old man.
Because those voices from the past are still calling.
Come on, come on, come on.
Don't get carried away with this religious stuff.
Come on, remember how it used to be and all of that.
And now the battle is sometimes the flesh and the spirit.
But notice what the spirit will do.
He will cause you.
He will move you.
He will inspire you.
He will draw you to be more like Jesus.
How many want to be more like Jesus?
Say amen.
More pure, more holy.
Look, he's causing it.
He's causing it, not me.
He's pushing me.
Well, the best way to overcome that is to be moving here.
You can't stay in the middle.
You got to be letting the spirit guide you.
I want to clean up your speech.
You know what?
You have a bad temper.
You shouldn't have spoke so inappropriately.
And he's putting all of these teachings in us
and causing us to go that other way.
So the Holy Spirit is in us
to bear witness that we are the children of God.
Praise God.
And then also to cause
I will cause you.
The problem with the Old Testament was us.
The law was fine.
It's me, the problem.
So God says, I'm going to get rid of Jim Simba.
I'm going to let him die spiritually.
And I'm going to cause...
My son, Jesus, to live in him through the Holy Spirit.
And now I'm going to renovate him.
Now I'm going to change him.
You got to see these inmates at Angola.
There's one guy up for a double murder charge.
And he's going to die there unless God intervenes.
And if you met him
he's the most gentle person
that I can't describe how gentle he is.
I have a picture I keep on my phone.
It was a meaningful moment.
I was there preaching in a chapel
filled with, let's say, 500 inmates,
no guards, no weapons, just me and a keyboard player
and these inmates.
And most of them were Christians.
Some of them weren't.
And at the end, I ministered
and then one of them yelled up at me, Pastor Jim
how can we pray for you?
They're looking at double life sentences
but they want to know how to pray for me.
I said, yeah, well
I got a number of things you can pray about.
Suddenly he stands and he goes, come on, guys
let's get him and pray for him.
When he said get him
I didn't know what that meant.
You know, like, let's be careful with the language here,
okay?
And, yeah, and they just came up and surrounded me.
I have a picture of it.
There's like 40 of them laying hands on me
crying out to god for me
they're in there for murder
who would ever want what would change them to want
to pray for some minister that's that new heart
how many thank god let's put our hands together
thank god for a new heart new life
so I saw some of you
I see it every Sunday
some of you visiting
you watch the choir sing
and you're watching people stand up
and I see you notice
why are they standing up?
Why are they lifting their hands?
Why are they emotional?
Why is that lady with the blonde hair always standing up
and worshiping God and praising God?
Don't you get it?
You don't know what we've experienced.
We were lost, but now we're found.
We were blind, but now we see.
Congregation, let them know.
Praise God.
So lastly, here's some gems of what God planned
for us through the Holy Spirit.
Please remember these.
Jesus said this in John.
He said, all this I have spoken while still with you.
But the advocate, or the word can be helper, the Holy Spirit
whom the Father will send in my name
will teach you all things.
And we will remind you of everything I have said to you.
So now listen as Jeffrey comes.
When you read this Bible
if you could have a minister
or a commentary next to you, that's helpful.
But the best teacher is the Holy Spirit.
So when you read it, look at me.
When you read it
just stop before you read it.
Holy Spirit, teach me what this means.
You wrote it.
Apply it to my heart.
Thank you, Lord.
I know you're going to help me.
And the Holy Spirit teaches.
Now, when the Holy Spirit teaches us
it's called revelation.
Not the book of Revelation, but revelation.
The Spirit imparting to our minds
and our hearts the meaning of these verses.
And applying it.
And there's no bottom to it.
You can read.
How many have read a verse like 20 times?
And you read it for the 21st time.
And the thing opens up and you go,
oh no, I didn't know it meant that.
How many have ever had that happen, right?
You're reading and you're reading and you're reading
and then you go, what?
That's the Holy Spirit teaching you.
Teaching me.
He's the best teacher.
All other teachers can go sideways, but
never the Holy Spirit.
He gives us the meaning of this.
And he edifies us.
He applies it to our heart.
Don't read the Bible with con su cabeza solo
but con su corazn.
Ask the Holy Spirit to teach you.
Read it with your heart.
These words are spirit and life, Jesus said.
So they have to be understood
through the Holy Spirit teaching us what it means.
By the way, that's why Jesus chose 12 fishermen
and tax collectors to be his followers
because they'd have to depend on the Holy Spirit.
If they had gone to the rabbinical schools
and they were famous rabbis
they would have fallen back on
what they had learned in religious schooling.
But now they had nothing.
They used to catch fish in the net.
How would they know how to minister?
So they would have to look to the Holy Spirit all the time.
Holy Spirit, help me.
Help.
I said it last week.
I think I want to say it again.
If I've ever helped you
if any song Carol ever wrote
or anything she ever said
or did has ever helped you, trust me
it's not us.
It's the Holy Spirit blessing you through us.
We can't impart blessing.
Only God can do that.
So now we know he's our teacher.
Everybody say teacher.
That's my teacher.
Don't read the Bible without saying that prayer.
You don't have to give a long prayer.
Just Holy Spirit, give me light, illumine me, my heart
so that I can see new things in your word.
Those prayers are found especially in Psalm 119.
Open my eyes, Lord
that I might see new
and marvelous things in your law.
But then there's more.
There's fake teachers.
There's fake preachers.
There's fake doctrine.
Paul said
in the last days there will be doctrines of demons.
Read it.
First and second Timothy.
Timothy, be careful.
Ministers are going to come.
And just like Satan imitates an angel of light
these ministers are going to come with cunning.
Oh, they'll be so convincing.
But they'll bring in false teaching, false doctrine.
They'll get you away from Jesus.
They'll get you away from holy living.
They'll get your mind taken up with money
and the pleasures of life.
They're con artists
but they're very cunning, very cunning.
Some are legalistic.
They want to add to Jesus.
They'll say, no
you're not saved by faith in Jesus alone.
You have to do this.
You have to worship on this day,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Others on the other side.
Don't get hung up.
There's no such thing as sin.
If it feels good, you do it.
Because God wants you happy.
You get it?
Are you following what I'm saying?
So now listen what John says.
Same cure.
Same answer.
In 1 John he says
I'm writing these things to you
about those who are trying to lead you astray.
Brothers and sisters,
there are people trying to lead all of us astray.
Okay, would you read that verse with me out loud?
Come on.
I am writing these things to you
about those who are trying to lead you astray.
I don't want to get started on that.
I lose my peace.
Con artists using all kinds of trickery to get money.
As for you, the anointing, what anointing?
The help of the Holy Spirit
that you received from him remains in you.
See, inside.
And you do not need anyone to teach you.
But as his anointing teaches you about all things
and as that anointing is real,
not counterfeit like the teachers
just as it has taught you, remain in him.
Remain in union with Christ.
And that anointing will help you to discern
the tricks of the trade
of these false teachers.
Notice, you have an anointing that teaches you all things.
You don't have a need for anyone to teach you.
Now look, look at me
and I'll close.
If a human teacher would be the determining factor
on how mature a person is
,
oh
she's a great Christian
because she sat under this teacher or that teacher.
Would God be fair?
What if someone got saved
like I know people in northern Argentina,
up in the province of Encorrientes
or Formosa?
And there's mucho pobrecitos, very poor
and they meet in a little church
and the pastor's just been saved a couple of years himself
but that's what it is there.
Well, then that person can't grow.
That person can't be mature.
Why?
They don't have a great Bible teacher to help them.
No!
They can become a better Christian than you
and me
because they have an anointing
that teaches them all things.
It's the Holy Spirit that keeps us straight.
And keeps us in line with his word.
So discernment is so needed today.
Because I'm just telling you
there's a lot of junk out there.
There's a lot of great churches
and good men and women of God.
But there's a lot of weird, weird, weird, weird stuff.
Right?
Always remember this, though,
as a little tip just from your pastor.
Whenever it's showy
and they're drawing attention to themselves, walk away.
No one who ever met Jesus had the encounter with Jesus,
strutted around, acting proud.
Impossibly.
When you meet Jesus, you go down.
How many say amen?
So that he can lift you up.
When you don't know Jesus, you go up
but not knowing that he will one day bring you down.
Just thought of that song
but it doesn't fit this.
You got to know when to hold them
and when to fold them and when to walk away.
That has nothing to do with what I just said, does it?
But you got to know when to walk away.
Walk away.
You see someone drawing attention to themselves?
Bye.
I'm not interested in you.
I'm not interested in you, Jim Cimbala.
I want to hear the word of the Lord.
I want to know Jesus better.
Okay, lastly, and this is so beautiful.
Many times people want to live for God
but they get thrown in a situation.
I'm thinking of something that my wife went through.
When we rented Radio City Music Hall,
6,000 seats for the first time
and they told her and us
When the choir comes up on that elevator,
biggest elevator in the world
biggest stage in the world
when they come up
like the Rockettes do during the Christmas show
when they come up singing with their gowns on
and praising God
after that first song, Carol
you have to walk and talk to the whole audience.
And at that time, she was very, very, very, very shy.
She told me ten times
I can't do that.
You go.
I said, no, I'm not doing it.
You're in charge of the choir.
I'm not.
Husbands, where does it say husband obey your wives?
Is that in the Bible?
Does someone find that in there?
William, don't let her do that to you.
Don't let her boss you around.
I'm only kidding.
So anyway, here's the promise.
When you are brought before synagogues
and Radio City Music Hall,
Rulers and authorities
do not worry about how you will defend yourselves
or what you will say.
For the Holy Spirit will teach you at that time
what you should say.
Can we clap our hands together?
My wife walked out there that night.
God came on her to help her.
The Holy Spirit did.
And she was getting sick from nerves.
She took that microphone.
Praise God.
She started walking around the stage.
No, she didn't.
But she was moving for a thing.
Why?
Because the Holy Spirit helps us.
So look at me.
Look at me.
Never feel like I don't know enough verses.
What if they ask me this question?
I want to give my testimony.
I want to do this.
I want to do that.
But I can't.
I'm not ready.
You'll never be ready.
The Holy Spirit is ready.
And in any situation God puts you in, Jesus said
don't worry about what you will say.
I'll give you what you will say through the Holy Spirit.
No, some of you don't believe it.
So I'm going to stay on it one more time.
Never say, I don't know what to do.
I'm not used to that.
That's not my gifting.
Listen, when you end up in a situation
where you have to talk or react, don't worry beforehand.
Take out your notes.
If I only had notes.
No, you just open your heart.
Show me, Holy Spirit, what to say.
How many believe he'll do it every single time?
Will he do it?
That's the problem.
Come on out, choir.
What a wonderful God we have.
Now you appreciate the Holy Spirit more?
Treasure him.
The sweetest moments in my life, my wife's life,
and in the history of this church
are
when we've had visitations of the Holy Spirit.
Oh, did you know this?
One time Peter went to Cornelius' house.
Cornelius was a Roman soldier.
There were no Christians who were Gentiles yet.
And the Bible says Peter went,
led by God, to preach to this whole household of people.
And while he was still speaking, Peter
read Acts 10 when you go home
the Holy Spirit fell on everyone who was listening
to the word.
Not an individual, the whole group.
And they were all filled with the Holy Spirit.
And the believers that were with Peter knew they were
because they were all speaking in tongues
just like Peter and the other believers did
on the day of Pentecost.
They spoke in languages they didn't know
because the Spirit can cause you to do whatever he wants
you to do.
And they said,
we can't stop these guys from getting baptized.
They're filled with the same Holy Spirit that filled us.
So the Spirit, we should always be sensitive in the meeting.
The Spirit can fall on a congregation.
And do things we can't imagine.
All right?
Some of you are battling with that, fighting with that.
No, I'm going to tell you the truth as it is in Christ.
While we're worshiping God
it could happen now
it could happen Tuesday night
the Spirit can fall on us
and lead us into worship
or ecstasy or a new filling of the Holy Spirit.
And the Holy Spirit does that.
And we should recognize that and honor his presence.
Amen or no amen?
Amen.
Carol recorded a song years ago with the choir, Psalm 34.
And when the song ended
it was a live recording.
Did you know this, Jeffrey?
When the song ended
one of the duet guys that was walking off just said,
praise God.
And suddenly I was on the edge of that right there.
The next thing was
I was supposed to walk out and do something.
Oh, did God freeze me.
And suddenly the spirit came down.
And for the next
I don't know, five minutes, seven minutes, ten minutes
there was nothing but an ocean of prey.
People got lost.
People fell on their knees.
People stood.
People were weeping.
And the Holy Spirit was conducting.
No one said a word.
My wife never said a word.
I never said a word.
Nobody said a word in the choir.
And we were all lost in God.
Why?
Because where the wind blows
you follow the wind.
Are you open to that or are you all dead?
I don't want to be a deadhead.
I want to be alive to God.
I don't want emotionalism.
I don't want fake anything.
I'm not doing that.
I don't want to work up some frenzy.
But oh, am I hungry for the Holy Spirit right now?
When you talk about him
you get more hungry for him.
So we want to teach you a song.
If you know it
you can sing along.
But otherwise, just listen.
If you could lift the instruments.
Wonderful Counselor Mighty God our father prince
we You got it?
Sing loud.
Sing.
Come on.
We go.
If you need a word from the Lord
if you have to make a decision
you need his teaching
come up out of your seat.
Come on.
Maybe God brought you here just for that.
Sing.
Wonderful.
I need a word from the Lord, Pastor.
I need the Holy Spirit.
Wonderful.
Mighty God.
Come on, everyone.
Praise the King.
Great I Am.
Come on up to the front.
God's going to speak to you.
The Holy Spirit is going to guide you and lead you.
Lift your hands in the building.
Sing.
Wonderful Counselor
Mighty God Thank you.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
Sing.
Praise the King.
The great I Am.
We glorify.
Everybody stand up.
Stand up and sing, everyone.
Wonderful.
Let the church sing.
Let the church sing to Jesus Christ.
We honor you, Jesus.
We praise you, Jesus.
Wonderful.
Hallelujah.
Praise the Lord.
The great I Am.
We glorify.
Come on, congregation.
Lift your voice and your hands.
Sing.
Wonderful.
Lift your hands to Almighty God and praise Him.
For Jesus is worthy of all praise.
He has been given a name above every other name.
That if the name of Jesus every knee shall bow
every tongue shall confess that Jesus Christ is Lord of all.
there's a glory upon the father
prince we fall without Last time
for all of us, sing.
Wonderful.
Master.
Mighty God.
We love you, Jesus.
Holy Spirit fill our church
with the fullness of all of your power
and grace and the gifts of the Holy Spirit
let no one hold back
but let everyone be open to everything you want to do in us
Bear witness all the time
with our spirit that we are the children of God.
Satan, you're a liar.
We belong to God.
He is our father.
Cause us to walk in your ways by your power,
not by our good intentions.
Not by self-effort.
We can't do it.
We've tried, Lord.
We've tried.
God, I have tried with good intentions to change.
I can't do it.
You have to do it.
So Spirit, come like a mighty rushing wind.
Come like a river and flow through us
showing the sweetness of Jesus to everyone around us.
Open your word to us.
Be our teacher.
Every day,
give us the prompting to get alone with our Bibles.
Every one of us in this room, Lord
we need your word every day
but we need it taught by the Holy Spirit.
Help us to have the faith to trust you to do that.
Keep us from false doctrine, false teachers,
tricksters, con artists
doctrines that seem good
but they're not.
Give us discernment.
Let the anointing that's in all of us, Lord, keep us away.
from the wolves in sheep's clothing.
Finally, give us the faith that no matter what we face
no matter what situation we're in today or tomorrow
if we will look to you
you will give us the word we need.
We don't have to worry.
We don't have to prepare.
We don't have to scribble down notes.
In the hour that we need to talk
you will give us the words, Holy Spirit.
And you'll give us the decision that we need to make.
And you'll lead us and guide us.
Te amo mucho, Seor.
We love you and we praise you.
Bless the offering as the people leave.
Remember the kids this week, Lord,
and our trip to the prison later on in the week.
Bless the prayer meeting coming up.
Help me to have a word for the people, Lord.
Give me a word to edify them.
We just thank you for this service, your presence here.
First-time visitors, just let everything be done
decently and in order,
Lord.
Blessed by you.
For we pray in the name that's above every other name.
In Jesus' name we pray.
You can go where you want to go
if you want to sing for a little while.
Our little group up here is going to sing to the Lord.
Greet one another.
Wonderful Counselor Mighty God Our Father