Good morning everyone
Let's all stand Welcome Praise the Lord
It's so good to see all of you
Amen
Oh it's a little quiet in here this morning
Are you happy to be here this morning
Are you ready to worship the Lord
Praise the Lord God is good
He's worthy to be praised Hallelujah Lord
We welcome you into this place right now
God Be lifted up God Be enthroned on our worship Jesus
We love you Lord We open our hearts to you God Come
and visit us God as we lift up your name Jesus
Come on let's sing this together
We are here together to lift our hearts as one
We're in our Father's presence His Spirit is with us
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give Him thanks
and praise
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain
Come on sing it again
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give Him thanks
and praise
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain Each
and every morning we'll tell of His great love
of all His faithful mercy
and all that He has done
And each and every morning
we'll tell of His great love of all His faithful mercy
and all that He has done
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give Him thanks
and praise
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give Him thanks
and praise Come on with all your heart
sing it out Glory honor wisdom power
and strength to our Savior Jesus
worthy of all praise Glory honor wisdom power
worthy of all praise
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give Him thanks
and praise
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give Him thanks
and praise
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain
Come on let's sing it again Glory honor wisdom power
and strength to our Savior Jesus
worthy of all praise Glory honor wisdom power
and strength to our Savior Jesus worthy of all praise
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give Him thanks
and praise
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God Come on
and sing it one more time Glory honor wisdom power
and strength to our Savior Jesus
worthy of all praise Glory honor wisdom power
and strength to our Savior Jesus worthy of all praise
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give Him thanks
and praise
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give Him thanks
and praise
For His heart is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain
And His mercy we can never contain
Come on pump your hands We worship you this morning
Lord It is good to give you thanks
and praise Jesus You are worthy of our praise today
Lord We give you all of our worship God
We give you all of our praise
Jesus We bless your wonderful name Lord
Oh how we love you today Jesus Come on sing it with me
Glory honor wisdom power
and strength to our Savior Jesus
worthy of all praise Glory honor wisdom power
and strength to our Savior Jesus worthy of all praise
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give Him thanks
And praise for His heart
is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain
It is good to lift the name of the Lord our God
It is right to give thanks
and praise for His heart
is overflowing with love for us
and His mercy we can never contain
And His mercy we can never contain
Amen Come to the Lord this morning He is worthy He is worthy
Amen Amen
You know as I thought about the songs I wanted to sing
with all of you this morning
I thought of that song Holy
Forever I love to sing that with you all
and it meant so much
more to me last night as I was laying in bed
and of course I'm going through the news
and we're all seeing just the turmoil in our world
and you read all the the articles
and everybody's opinions and just all the chaos of it
all right
The volatility of our world
and you feel yourself getting anxious
And then I had to stop
as I have been reminding myself so much of lately
Stop Take your eyes off of this Lift your eyes
Lift your eyes to the only one who never changes
who is the same yesterday today
and forever Kingdoms rise and kingdoms fall
Nations come and they go
and they're all broken right
It's dark
It's broken It's all laden with sin
but there is one who is holy without sin
perfect in His love perfect in His righteousness
perfect in His mercy
and His justice and His kingdom knows no end
That is our King
Amen
Amen That is our King
and our eyes have to stay on Him
Fix your eyes on Jesus today
Take your eyes off the things of this world
Fix them on the one who never changes
He is secure He is steadfast
He is immovable and He is with us
Amen So let's worship Him with all of our heart as we sing this song
Declare it
and encourage your heart today
With eyes of faith lift your eyes today
Look at the one who sits on a throne
with all victory all power in His right hand
He is with us
Thou must endure generation Falling down in worship
and sing the song of ages to the Lamb
And all who come before us
and all who will believe
sing the song of ages to the Lamb
Come on declare it Your name is the highest
Your name is the greatest
Your name stands above them all All souls
and dominions all powers and positions
Your name stands above them all
And the angels cry holy all creation cries holy
You are lifted high holy holy
forever If you've been forgiven
and if you've been redeemed we'll sing the song forever to the Lamb
If you walk in freedom
and if you bear His name we'll sing the song forever to the Lamb
Come on sing it out
We'll sing the song forever and amen
And the angels cry holy all creation cries
holy You are lifted high holy holy
forever If you'll be holy holy
to the end of the age holy
You will always be holy
holy forever Come on let 's declare it
Your name is the highest Your name is the greatest
Your name stands above them all
All glory all power all majesty
Your name stands above them
all Your name is the highest
Your name is the greatest Your name stands above them all
All glory all power all majesty
Your name stands above them all
Holy all creation cries Holy you are
living light Holy holy
forever You do n't even see Holy to the King of Kings Holy
you will always be Holy holy forever
Come on sing it out with me
All your name is the highest
Your name is the greatest Your name stands above
every other name All glory all power all majesty
Your name stands above them all
All glory all power all majesty
All glory all power all majesty Your name stands above them all
Holy all creation cries
Holy you are living light Holy holy holy forever
We sing praise to the Lord Holy holy holy
you will always be Holy holy holy
forever Hallelujah Jesus Hallelujah
We worship you Jesus
Come on fix your eyes on the Lord right now
We bless your name Jesus
We glorify your name You are worthy to be praised
Hallelujah Jesus Name above every other name
We worship you Lord King of kings
and Lord of lords
We bless your wonderful name Holy holy holy are you Lord Hallelujah Jesus
Hallelujah Jesus We bless you worship Jesus
Hallelujah Hallelujah Jesus
We glorify Your name Jesus We glorify Your name Jesus
Just continue to worship Him Come on lift your voice
Just continue
to worship Him We give You praise
we give You glory we give You honor God
We gather in Your name this morning
Lord We come to meet with You
Lord We invite You into this place
O God Come and dwell in the midst of Your people
Lord We worship
and adore You God We declare that You are King of kings
and Lord of lords
There is no one like You There is no one beside You
O God Hallelujah Jesus
Oh how we love Your name Jesus
Come on let's join together
and sing it Jesus Jesus Jesus Jesus Jesus
Can you see Oh how we love Him
Jesus Jesus Jesus Jesus Can you see I love Him
so Oh how we love Him so All of our hearts we love Him
I love Him
So Jesus Jesus I need You so Can you sing I need You
so I need You
so Oh how much we need You Lord We need You
so We need You so Jesus Jesus I need You so
Come on sing again I need
You
so I need You
so We confess our need for You Lord
We are helpless without You Jesus I need You so
Jesus Jesus
I need You so Come on pour your heart
Oh praise His name
Oh we praise You Your people praise You Lord
Receive our praise today
I praise You You are worthy to be praised
Jesus Jesus I praise You
Come on sing it again
And I praise You Oh we praise You Sing Jesus Jesus
I praise You Sing I love Him so Come on declare your love for the Lord
Tell Him
that you love Him for all that He's done I love Him
so Jesus Jesus I love Him
so Lord we love You today
We join our hearts together Lord
We join our voices together to tell You
that we love You today Jesus We love You God
We love You Lord
We bless Your name today God We give You glory
and honor in this place
Lord We declare that You are our only hope God
And we are so thankful
that we know You today
that we have You today God Thank You Lord for revealing Yourself to us
Thank You for loving us
Thank You for saving us
Thank You for giving us Lord a hope and a future Lord Jesus
In You God alone In You alone not in this world God
In You alone do we have those things So we bless You
We thank You and we give You the remainder of this meeting
Bless everything that takes place
and be glorified through it all We pray in Jesus' name
Amen Praise God
Praise God Praise the Lord church God is good
Amen Scripture says to sing a new song
and make a joyful noise as one voice
So will you join with us as we sing in the sanctuary
and praise Him
Amen Let's sing Praise Him in the sanctuary
Praise Him with the timbrel
and dance Praise Him with the sound of the trumpet
Praise Him for His mighty acts
Praise Him in the mighty heavens
Praise Him for His greatness to us Praise Him with the clash of
the cymbal We know He 's working
Praise the Lord Let everything that happens praise Him
Let everything that happens praise the Lord
Let everything that happens praise Him Praise the Lord
We sing praise Him Praise Him in the sanctuary
Praise Him with the temple
and dance with the sound of the trumpet
Praise Him for His mighty acts
Praise Him by blindness Praise Him for His mighty words
Praise Him with the clash of the cymbals
He alone is worthy
Praise the Lord Let everything that happens praise Him
Let everything that happens praise the Lord Let everything that happens praise Him
Praise the Lord Let everything that happens
praise Him Praise the Lord
Praise the Lord
From the rising of the sun to the setting of the same
we will praise the name of the Lord for He is worthy to be praised
Hallelujah
Praise Him Praise all my heart
We praise all my soul
Praise Him in our hearts Our souls
We praise Him in our hearts
We praise Him with our voices Praise Him
Praise the Lord praise the Lord Praise the Lord praise the Lord Praise the Lord praise the Lord Praise the
Lord praise the Lord Praise the Lord praise the Lord
Praise the Lord praise the Lord
I lift my hands in total adoration unto You
You reign on the throne for You are God
and God alone
Because of You my cloudy days are gone
I can sing to You this song I just want to say
that I love You more than anything
I lift my hands in total adoration unto You
You reign on the throne for You are God
and God alone
Because of You my cloudy days are gone I can sing to You this song
I just want to say
that I love You more than anything
Hold me in Your arms You are my shelter from the storm
When all my friends were gone
You are right there all alone I've never known a love like this
before I just want to say
that I love you more than anything
I love you Jesus I worship
and adore you
Just want to tell you Lord I love you more than anything
I love you Jesus I worship
and adore you
Just want to tell you Lord I love you more than anything
I love you Jesus I worship
and adore you
Just want to tell you Lord I love you more than anything
I love you Jesus I worship
and adore you
Just want to tell you Lord I love you more than anything
I love you Jesus I worship
and adore you
Just want to tell you Lord I love you more than anything Good morning
everyone
Praise the Lord God is good Today's Good News Sunday
and we try to on this first Sunday of every month
take a little extra time
to just thank God for salvation
for what the gospel can do in someone's life
And I want you to welcome
here in a second a young man 18 years old in our church
He's been here since 2024
His name is Gavin He's never spoken publicly here before
Come on up Gavin Put your hands together
Gavin is in the house
Good morning congregation
I'm here to talk about how Jesus changed my life
So like Pastor Simula said in 2024
before I gave my life to Jesus
I wasn't a believer I knew about God
but I didn't have a personal relationship with Him
So I felt like I had a more compass
that I could just stand by
and you know
I felt like I knew what was right and wrong
and that's what I lived by
So when times got rough I depended on myself
So but that was part of the problem
I thought it was good enough
but in Psalms 143 the Bible tells us
All have turned away
all have become corrupt
There is no one who does good not even a single one
But it also says in Romans 323
For all have sinned
and all fall short of the glory of God
One of the hardest things
for me was watching a very close friend fall into substances
and drugs I saw how it affected that person
and the people around us
and the friend group we stayed in
I asked them to quit many times
but nothing really changed So in 2024
when I went to BTYM the youth retreat my cousin
Aileen was part of the worship team
and my dad told me I had to go
So I went not really expecting much to be honest
But on Friday night the first night we got there
Pastor James told us
that this weekend would be lifechanging
as long as we just let go
and let God work
So for the first time I stopped resisting
and opened my heart
So throughout the whole weekend
Saturday that Friday night especially
I got to meet one of the best people in my life
Adia who changed my life
But that moment the moment that changed everything for me was
Sunday
After the service
we were told to find like a quiet place around the campus
and pray So I did what I thought
and prayed for specifically for that friend
Later on in the day after I got back
home I called another friend
and they told me to call them
and you know tell them that I prayed for them
So I did and before I even got to say anything they told me
that I should stop right there
because they stopped substances and all of that
So in their mind
they completely thought it was just up to their own
but I knew it was Jesus that changed them I knew
that God stepped into their life
and changed it because I called to do so So praise God
praise God
He proved himself to me that weekend
and ever since then I've opened my heart
I've been in this ministry
and I want to say thank you to this ministry
the BTYM St
This this place has changed me for the good
And yeah
God used this church to bless me specifically
I I shared Jesus to my friends
You know a couple of them went to the youth retreat
this year this past year
So I've been trying to spread to whoever I can
because I know what Jesus did to me
He could do to others as well
So yeah
So I was one way before Jesus Christ unsure and distant
But then after I encountered Jesus
now I live in faith peace
and confidence and knows that He hears His children
when they call on His name So if there's anything that I'd ask
that you take from you know my testimony is that just let God let go
and let God Thank you Jesus is all I need
Jesus is all I need I need no other friend I need no other one Jesus is all I need
Oh when I'm tired
and I'm weary when I'm on my journey home
and when the road is rough and long
and I feel so all alone oh
when my strength is all gone
and I can't carry on that's
when my Jesus is all that I need Jesus is all I need
Jesus is all I need
I need no other friend I need no other one Jesus is all I need
Yes
Oh and when life has let me down
and peace cannot Be found
when all my hopes and all my dreams lie scattered on the ground
Oh and my joy turns to sorrow
and there's no hope for tomorrow That's
when Jesus He's all that I need
Oh Jesus
He's all I need It's Jesus He's all I need
I need Your love the friend I need the one the only one
Oh Jesus
He's all I need Everyone stand everyone stand let's sing together
He's all I need He's all I need Jesus is all I need
He's the only one Jesus is all I need He's all I need
Yes my Jesus
He is all that I need
Keep standing Bible says in James if anyone's in trouble let him pray
If anyone's happy let him sing
songs of praise We've been singing songs of praise
but in every meeting there's people in trouble They're being attacked emotionally mentally spiritually
They're being attacked financially They have a wayward child Something's going on
You walked in the building today with a burden a load
I'm going to ask the choir to do me a real big favor
and sing the whole song again Do you love that song I love that song
because it says Jesus is all I need Five words
and it changes everything
If you're here today
We have deacons here in the front who will stand with you Come out of your seat right now
out of the balcony
My house shall be called a house of prayer Jesus said
because I want to help my people I just want them to look to me
and call out to me
and I will bless them and help them
So anyone and everyone who needs something from the Lord
because you're in trouble in some area of your life
I have been in all kinds of trouble in my life
and a million times God has met me He'll meet you here
You just come forward right now Do it
Oh He's all I need He's all I need Jesus is all I need
Jesus is all I need I need no other friend I need no other one Jesus is all I need
Oh when I'm tired
and I'm weary when I'm on my journey home
when the road is rough
and long I feel so all alone
When my strength is all gone that can't carry on That's
when my Jesus is all that I need Jesus is all I need
Jesus is all I need I need no other friend I need no other one
Jesus He is all I need
Oh and when life has let me down
and peace cannot be found
when all my hopes and all my dreams they lie scattered on the ground
and when my joy turns to sorrow
and there's no hope for tomorrow that's
when Jesus He is all that I need Oh tell yourself today sing Jesus is all I need
Jesus is all I need I need no other friend I need
no other one Oh Jesus is all I need
Oh would you lift your hands with me Let's sing together
Oh He's all I need
Oh He's all I need Jesus is all I need
Oh He satisfies He satisfies my needs of life Jesus is all I need
Jesus is all I need We praise you Lord
We praise you Lord We praise you Lord
Just open your mouth right now everyone
Praise Him out loud Come on if He's all that you need tell Him
that Praise Him Gloria tu nombre Señor Thank you Lord
We praise you Jesus Lord we thank you that
when there's no one else around you're always there for us
Lord No when no one else can help you are my helper Lord
When we don't know how we're going to go on
you are Jehovah Jireh You will provide for us
I thank you for every honest heart that came forward here Lord
Would you meet their needs now Come on God
these are your people
These are your people We're calling on you Don't you hear all these hearts going up to you
God So do according to your promise
When you call I will answer You said answer
and help and bless each one in Jesus' name
But getting back to the offering we we got plastered again
and with snow and then lower offerings
So those watching online would you just pray about what you might want to do
Most give online There are baskets
when you leave You can give an offering in the mezzanin
and the lobby as you leave
But the greater percentage give online Would you help us Would you help us
Because this comes at a time
where it's like a challenge to my faith We want to step out and do more My wife
and I are committed
and with the pastors that we want to see a church built
over in Slovakia among the Roma people the poorest people there discriminated against
Pastor Brian's been over there He's heading up this whole project He'll give us reports on it
In fact we'll show some pictures next Sunday
and we want to help them do that
and then just other needs that we see
that we want to help people
Because my wife and I have found over the years if you bless other people God will bless you
I said if you bless other people God will bless you How many believe that
And it's found in the Scripture give
and it shall be given How will God do that
When will He do that I don't know
But God it will it will not fail in His promises He will bless you He will help you
How many people are going through financial problems
because they're they're cheap with the Lord They they they they hold back on giving to the Lord
And let's not do that
But that 's not I do n't want to put you in condemnation I want to encourage you
Give Go out That 's the secret of life
Go out from yourself Money whatever love encouragement Go
out Do n't try to always get in what I want what I like what I want Just go
out For it 's more blessed to give than to receive Lord would you help us this week
and send monies in to meet all our needs
Help us to catch up You're the God of catching up
You're the God of everything You help us in so many ways I stand here
and God we have a track record with you
You have never failed You have done things beyond what we could ask
or think And individually you've done that too
So help us to be givers not takers to have faith and be liberal
We thank you for that in Jesus' name
Amen
Well we have a guest speaker today who he'll come out in a second
But he made a very wise decision years ago
when he married my daughter
Which and Pastor Brian made a very wise decision
when he married my other daughter
So it's rare that I have my son James who sings in the choir
and then my two daughters here
So I'm very very happy I'm overflowing with thanksgiving to God
And before Pastor Al comes toledo they pastor he
and his wife founded and pastor a church called Chicago Tabernacle in Chicago Illinois
And Chrissy's written a book
and she travels now herself and speaks quite a bit
And we're just so happy I want you to meet her before her husband comes
In fact both of you come out Let's hear it for come on Pastor Al and Chrissy Toledo
Let's hear it Clap louder
It's my daughter
Wow
What a service I was sitting there in the one two three four fifth row with my mom
and just overwhelmed by the presence of God by my sisters' beautiful leading us into the presence of God
and by the choir And what makes this place so special to me besides the fact
that I grew up in this church not at this location It was
when I was about 19 years old
and I don't know if many of you know this My dad wrote about it in his book
but
I was
I turned my back on the Lord even though I came from the real deal
Like my parents I don't need to tell you they love Jesus with all their hearts
But you know you can be deceived even
when you're surrounded This is to any of you young people maybe even here today You can be deceived
because Satan comes to kill to steal
and to destroy And it happened to me He almost destroyed me Satan
But the church you guys at the 290 Flatbush location
a note was slipped up Someone had the courage to hear from the Holy Spirit
but to act on it
and to give the note to my dad
And the note said Tonight is Chrissy's night Can you imagine
that The Lord would love me so much
that He would put it on someone's heart to pray for me that night
And that night I was very suicidal and nobody knew that
but me and God
And it was on that nightI won't get into the detailsbut was what was happening in the prayer meeting
I got to see with my own eyes in the spiritual realm the battle
That's why you never want to miss the prayer meeting Don't miss the prayer meeting
because you might miss when the Lord moves Don't miss the prayer meeting
because I am here today because of a prayer meeting
And on that night I had tried My parents know I had tried I had said I'll
I'll I'll do right
I'll do right
I couldn't do right
But when Jesus touched me
because you guys prayed He absolutely delivered me He set me free And this story Amen
This story is as fresh to me at 56 years old as it was all those years ago
You know why
Because I wouldn't be here if God's people didn't pray
And I want to just encourage you keep being a praying church We are a praying church in Chicago
and I just thank God for all of you
It's so good to be here My husband
and I are just thrilled to be here
We have three married children We have eight grandchildren God has been good to us
Amen
Amen Amen Let's put our hands together for
Pastor Al Toledo Hallelujah
It's um I'm so happy to be here
and so so honored I grew up
I was always maybe four to seven blocks away from Chrissy Ten
I grew up right over here I had a supernatural experience with the Lord
and the first church that I walk into was the Brooklyn Tabernacle
And I mean I was I was you know I was from Fort Greene
I was fight to school fight to get back from school
and
but I had this supernatural experience with God
And I just we just came back from Italy We were speaking to pastors I came here
when I was 18 years old
Now I'm 59 years old I feel old
But man this place has so marked my life blessed my life gave me my wife
Oh that rhymes I'm kind of rapping here
right
And you know I
I thank God all the time
because like I was just speaking to pastors
and I'll get to the message real quickly
But I was just speaking to pastors in Italy I don't know how this has happened
but I have the privilege of like encouraging leaders even around the world now
And I'm always mindful that it was
because this church had such a there was such a special grace on this place
I I speak to pastors and they're struggling
and I feel like Lord I had such an incredible example Pastor Hammond
I didn't see him Pastor Ware Pastor Lincoln I was a teenager He used to talk to me
and pray with me and like the example
Nancy Martinez
Like I
just I I have to say I'm so grateful to God for this place
and for all of the leaders who have led this place so faithfully raised up so many people
Could we praise God
Come on for all of the leaders
Hallelujah Jesus
We bless you We praise you We glorify your name
O God You get all the credit You get all the glory O God
But man has he been good and so faithful
and I just
I forgot how special it's been a while how special this is so I want to
I want to share word with you
from Hebrews chapter four very kind of famous a couple of very famous verses
but I'm going to read a little bit longer
and and this passage is sort of a an exhortation
and now verse 11 is the exhortation
but then there's all of these promises that are built into it that are very very powerful
and think about the very day that we live in we need this word for today right now
we're praying I have my phone with me in church
which I usually don't do that
but I'm waiting for a text
because one of our staff members
and her husband are actually in Israel
and they've been kind of they they were in uh in bunkers for for like the last day
and I heard that they're trying to get them out of Israel
her name is Doris her husband is Nate please pray for them
that they get out of Israel safely
but you know after following the Lord so
it's been over 40 years now I believe one of the most important things for my life in God
and for anyone's life in God is
that we have to continually learn remember practice stepping into God 's rest
that 's what I want to talk to you about today
stepping into God 's rest there 's a rest that God wants to give His people
there 's
a special rest that is available to any person
whether you 're watching online you 're a first time visitor here I ' m telling you
I ' m not talking about man 's rest man 's rest is you go on vacation
and you rest for a couple of weeks
I'm talking about something deeper greater richer more powerful something that surpasses all circumstances something that can meet you
when you're in a bunker in Israel
or whether you're walking down the streets on Fulton Street doesn't matter
where you are how many know there is a rest that comes from God that is special and supernatural
but the Bible tells us as Christians
that we can move in
and out of rest Psalm 116 verse 7 puts it this way
it says return to your rest my soul for the Lord has been good to you
like look at what this says return to your rest my soul for the Lord has been good to you
because sometimes even when we know the Lord we can slip out of rest You know
but but but David had a moment a revelation
where he said Wait a second God has been so good
Has He been good to you Has He been faithful
Hallelujah
We can return to rest We we move in and out of it
And I I have to tell you
I I think at the heart of knowing Jesus other than salvation itself
the greatest gift of salvation is to actually be able to live and walk in His rest
Like imagine inheriting You know I used to walk down the streets in Brooklyn Heights when I was a kid
and I used to say
when I become I almost played professional baseball a hundred years ago
when I make it to the big leagues I'm going to live in a brownstone in Brooklyn Heights
and I would walk by
and I was like on the outside looking in and it never happened
anyway
But um but it's interesting
because you know when you
when you we all have our idea of what it means to arrive
and I'm telling you right now it has nothing to do with material
or circumstantial things Come on that's a that's a that's a good time to say Amen
I bear witness with that
And so but imagine inheriting like like a brownstone
and and and somebody hands you the keys
but you never go in That's what it's like for the Christian who continues to worry
That's what it's like for the Christian who who continues to to churn
or or feel bitter towards someone
when God says you can enter into my rest
And so there's this exhortation in the Bible
No matter what people do to you no matter what happens no matter what's going on you
and I no matter how great the battle
or the responsibility or the burden God is he exhorts us to step into His rest
So let me read this to you Hebrews chapter four starting with verse eight
It says For if Joshua had given them rest God would not have spoken later about another day
When now when the Bible says this here about Joshua Joshua led them into the Promised Land
You know they they were slaves in Egypt They they the Lord delivered them by His mighty power
but He didn't deliver them from Egypt so
that they could stay in the wilderness He delivered them so
that they could step into the Promised Land
and the Promised Land was a form of rest
But there was an even greater rest
because as I mentioned a moment ago rest is more than circumstantial That was promised land rest
It says There remains then a Sabbath rest for the people of God
For anyone who enters God 's rest also rests from their work just as God did from His
Let us therefore make come
on say these two words Ready Every effort every effort to do what
To enter that rest That 's the exhortation
No matter what 's happening in your life no matter what 's happening in my life
and I've learned over the years pressures struggles responsibilities God says make every effort to enter into that rest
In other words go for rest first
You need solutions You need you need help You need strength Go for rest first
The Bible tells us The Bible says instead of trying to fix it go for rest first
So it says make every effort to enter that rest so
that no one will perish by following their example of disobedience You see
when we don't get God's rest we naturally are inclined to do something disobedient
Why do people fall into sin so much
We fall into sin
when we don't feel rest
And so you either get God's rest
or you go someplace else
which is a false rest but doesn't work
And then we grieve God
and we disappoint God Let me keep going here
Now now this is this is like the promise
because there's an exhortation
but there's a promise It says For the word of God is alive
and active sharper than any doubleedged sword It penetrates even to dividing Listen to this soul
and spirit joints and marrow It judges the thoughts
and attitudes of the heart
Keep going a little bit more Nothing in all creation is hidden from God's sight Everything is uncovered
and laid bare before the eyes of Him to whom we must give account
Therefore since we have a great High Priest who has ascended into heaven
Jesus the Son of God let us hold firmly to the faith we profess
for we do not have a High Priest who is unable to empathize with our weaknesses
but we have one who has been tempted in every way just as we are
Yet he did not sin This is very very important to us today
It says Let us then approach God's throne of grace with confidence so
that we might receive So
that we might receive mercy
and find grace to help us in our time of need
and the implication is is
that when you get the mercy
when you get the grace guess what you get You get rest Be at rest once more O my soul
And so I want to pray I want to unpack this for the next few moments
but I want to pray
because I would say God is always whispering into my spirit
Because anybody here have a couple problems Can I see your hands
I would say God is consistently saying Don't forget to rest
Before you try to figure that out don't forget to rest
It's amazing to me how God is able to place something in your spirit
that is so distant from the present inputs
So so Doris I reached out to her in Israel
and she sent me back two Bible verses I'm like I should be sending her Bible verses
She's sending me Bible verses You know why
Because it doesn't matter
where you are How many know God is able to give us rest Hallelujah
So let me pray Father we thank you
and we Lord what a beautiful service
God
I ask that you would bless the next few moments
that you would minister deeply to every heart I pray in the mighty name of Jesus
Amen
and amen Hallelujah
Okay so let me unpack this By the way I had a doubt whether I should preach this today
because I was like this has to be the happiest church in America
I've never seen people clap at the daylight savings change
and you actually lose an hour
I was like what are these people drinking Like what's going on here They lose an hour of sleep
and they clap
But maybe we still need rest
Amen
Okay so very quickly let's unpack this
So what is rest What is rest Rest is a state of blessing It's a state Okay
Rest is not an action Rest is an actual state of being
Like you're resting in your being on the inside
It's a state of blessing
and calm that makes you trust in your salvation and then live in expectation
Okay so rest is a state
where you are just blessed
because you know the Lord How many know the Lord How many are happy to know the Lord
And when you know the Lord He brings you into this state of blessing
You you are you've been delivered from sin We were we were slaves to sin How many are grateful
We're going to heaven on that day
If He comes back tonight we're going to heaven Hallelujah Praise be
If anyone is in Christ He's a new creation It's a state of blessing
right
And and calm
But here's what it does
Okay it makes you trust in your salvation so
that you don't have to work Like you didn't I hope you didn't come to church today
and worship today and give today
because you were somehow thinking if I do that
then I earn something How many know we didn't worship today We didn't give today
because we want to earn something No we don't work so
that we'll be loved We work
because we are loved Anybody here grateful Hallelujah
And and when you rest in God everything that you're doing is
because you already know that you're loved by God
and
and and there's there's a calm inside of you
because you know I'm good
I'm a child of the King
But here's the thing
But you also live in expectation
So my my wife is really my wife is a really like happy person and she wakes up
and she's always like what's God gonna do today
You know what's God gonna do God's gonna do something God's gonna speak
When when you're resting in God no matter what's going on you're like
oh I'm waiting I'm looking
because I know God is up to something
Somebody believe God is up to something I know that He's up to something When I play baseball
And people used to ask me about how do you concentrate
You know what concentration is It's relaxed intensity Athletically speaking
I was like that's a great way to be a Christian
Christians should be totally relaxed God is good I belong to Him
But also very intense God wants to speak to someone today
God wants me to witness to someone today God wants to use me today
And when we rest in God it's
when we discern His voice the best
When we rest in God it's
when when we understand what He's doing in a moment the best
When we rest in God we're steady
When we when when someone's at rest in God they're strong
They're solid Most importantly not most importantly
but you know I have found
that when you rest in God
and you see this in the Bible some of the greatest doors open
when God's people rest So for example I think about Moses
and the nation of Israel They've got Pharaoh behind them behind them the army behind them
They've got the Red Sea in front of them
And what does God say to Moses He says stand still
and see the salvation of the Lord What was He saying to Moses He was saying Moses just rest
and watch what I'm going to do
And I'm telling you the word of the Lord to someone today is just step into my rest
and see what I'm going to do Enter into my rest
But notice it says enter into rest
So there's a there's a move of faith that God wants from you today
It's a move of faith that says God I I want to step into your rest
And here's what I would say You're your best
when you rest Come on somebody say I'm my best when I rest
And today could be the very day that God is about to do something exceedingly
and abundantly beyond what we could ever ask
or think or imagine How many would say
Amen Hallelujah
Now what is this passage The exhortation is stepping to rest
If you're angry today the exhortation is stepping to rest If you're wounded today
the exhortation is stepping to God's rest If you're in trouble we just prayed
What was that moment just now
when when people came down What was the whole point of it First
and foremost is to step into rest You step into rest first
and then you walk out of here
and God starts to work
and do all kinds of things
But it all begins with rest Enter into that rest Now
when you read this passage it says a couple things to you that are very very important
How does God help you find rest What says for the word of God is living
and active sharper than any doubleedged sword
Right I I for years
I I've thought about this for years
Right
And it's able It pierces It's able to penetrate soul
and spirit joint and marrow attitudes and thoughts
So what God uses to bring rest is His word God has a word of rest to you
But notice
and this is why we're going to get into our hearts for another ten minutes at the most Right
So the Bible says that God uses His word
and it goes beneath the surface
Soul and spirit joint and marrow attitudes
and the hearts Nobody can see
that Nobody can see your joint
and marrow Nobody can see your soul and spirit
But you know what God can
Nobody knows It says nothing is hidden from God Nobody
Each heart knows its own bitterness No one can share its joy
Nobody knows your pain Nobody knows what you've been through
Nobody knows about your trauma Nobody knows about that thing that some some leader did to you
that they shouldn't have done No one knows any of those things except God
And what God says is I will give you rest
But when God gives you rest you know what He does He works beneath the surface
Because brothers and sisters there are there medicine can help
and doctors can help but there are some places that the Holy Spirit can reach
and only the Holy Spirit can reach He is the God who goes in deep
God wants to touch us in a deep place He wants to minister to us in a very deep
and profound way He says I go as deep as it goes
And when I go there if you let Him go there
if you let Him go there He will give you rest
This is really so special how God wants to go
and touch you in a way that no one can
And when He does it it's like on any given day
when God touches you like that you're in the balcony
It's like you're just
you're just different because He reached that place
that no one else can reach A little bit more unpacking here
So So now when we think about the working of God right
He he goes deep into deep places He covers a whole spectrum of of struggle
and weakness So remember it says for Jesus he he empathizes with our weakness
When God thinks what does God think about What does Jesus think about
when he sees you One of the things he thinks about is I understand what their struggle is
Did you know
that the Lord understands what your struggle is Okay
And when God goes to minister to you he wants to minister to you in the context of your struggle
Now I've got a little chart here I call this the spectrum of weakness
Now I I just want to explain this to you
and then two quick application points
But so let's go back to the the the garden
where it all happened You know man did she really have to take that bite Like man
So when when they fell it activated a whole spectrum of weakness
and struggle which Jesus says I empathize with So so the the the spectrum goes from independence to rejection
Every struggle on the planet lies somewhere between independence
and rejection Independence was when they said
you know what I don't care what God said I'm going to go ahead
and eat that fruit I want
it
I'm smarter I don't need him They ate the fruit Nobody here struggles with independence
but some you know some places
right
So from independence all the way the minute
that they fell the minute
that they sinned what does the Bible tell us The Bible tells us
that they ran and they hid from God
Why Because the presumption of sin is
that God will reject me If you sin you feel like God's going to reject me
And when the Bible says that Jesus ministers to our weakness right
And he empathizes with our weakness
If you struggle with independence he still he has mercy on you
If you struggle with rejection he has mercy on you
No matter what we struggle with God he empathizes
and he wants to speak deep into our soul in a way that nobody else can
No one else can touch us like Jesus
He wants to minister to both sides of who we are Wherever wherever that battle is
and He wants to give us everyone rest
Okay if they could play the keyboard it won't be much longer So let's talk about this
and all this teaching is for this application So let's talk about rejection for a minute You know
when you're a pastor you're supposed to know the know the Bible
and then you're also supposed to kind of know what the devil is doing You know
and I could talk about this from so many different vantage points
but let's just take this whole social media culture On our way here we were we stopped in London
We were in Italy Italy
but we stopped in London
And on the news they have outlawed social media now in London for children under 14
or 15 I don't know
because statistically speaking social media is destroying children
And you know why It's
because social media the social media culture was masterminded by Satan so
that he could activate on a massive scale the spirit of rejection
After we've I don't know 30 we've been at this 30
something years more than the bottle
more than more than cocaine more than any kind of ugly thing I'm telling you right now
nothing plagues people more Nothing plagues men more than guess what The spirit of rejection
Kids look on social media they look at someone else's life
and they say God life favors someone else instead of me They get into comparison mode
and they just feel terrible about themselves
We've been there Every one of us has You know it's funny because hurt people hurt people
So because of the fallen nature we fall
and even when we're kids we reject kids on the playground Some people walk around wounded
because they were rejected when they were eight years old The spirit of rejection is so profound
and so powerful and and it affects so many people
I I knew a guy who was in the ministry who was traumatized
because he was sweeping the floor and his dad was there
and he broke the broom
and his dad went off on him
and and and put him down
and he happened to be adopted
and it it traumatized his life Why
Because of a moment of rejection
And you know why Jesus came
Jesus came to overpower the injury the wounding that comes from the spirit of rejection
So many people all they can think about all they can
think about is what other people think about them All they can
all they can process is is how do people feel about me
Do they love me Do they accept me Brothers
and sisters there is one who claims you There is one who loves you
There's one who embraces you every day every day Hallelujah You can find rest
even you even if you've been rejected He's the God of rest
So many stories over the years
but I I have to tell you I was in I woke up at two thirty
because of jet lag and all that My clock is off
So I opened Starbucks today
and I was reading the Bible and praying about this
and then I thought to myself you know who the perfect example for this is
Hope he doesn't mind me saying it
If I don't preach next service then you know why Pastor Simba
He's told this story here a hundred times
But you look around His dad my dad never missed My my dad wasn't perfect
but my dad never missed a baseball game His dad never went to a basketball game
Like I don't even I can't even fathom what Pastor Simba went through as a kid
But you know what happened
We're all the benefactors of it
He found the rest of God Come on Hallelujah He found God's rest
See you know him as as Pastor Jim Simba
but one day he was just a kid in Brooklyn that no one knew
but God knew You know
and and and I I don't even know what the moment was
It doesn't matter what the moment was
but the fact of the matter is is
that despite hurt and pain
or rejection or whatever it might be he found it
And think so let's go back to Moses Stand still
and see the salvation of the Lord
Right a whole nation was delivered What could God do with your life
and with my life if despite the wounds despite the trauma despite the hurt despite the pain
what could God do if we could just really deeply step into His rest
Come on come on let 's praise God He wants to do a work of great rest
A rest that delivers us It delivers us from trauma and hurt and pain
He's the God of rest
One more thing very quickly Then there's the other side of it is we rest not from rejection
but we rest from independence Independence is something that the minute we have we have eight grandkids right
It's a miraculous thing You tell one of your grandchildren you see this
It's hot Don't touch it
What's the first thing that they do It's
because of the spirit of independence
There's a lot of different reasons why we might bend towards independence
It's just part of the fallen nature
But sometimes we're our own worst enemy
And I need to say this to someone today Maybe the best thing that could happen today is
that you would be delivered from a spirit of independence How many would say Amen You keep hurting yourself
because has to be your way You want to do your thing
When God says Look let me reach deep into your soul
because I want to give you rest
I'll close with this This happened This has happened in the last three months Young lady in our church
She she grew up in Chicago not too far from our church
and she had an abusive dad
And she started to hate men I don't know what it's like here
but in Chicago she went to a high school In Chicago the teachers were teaching her
and applauding her and saying Come on you know men are horrible You should be gay Literally the teachers
This is her testimony So she said Okay that's the thing to do Let's be gay
And then
but she was 16 or
and and did all kinds of horrible things
And then finally she gets married And to a woman
And she was came to the point
where she was suicidal because you see you can chase things
and chase things and say I don't care I don't have to answer to anyone
I don't have to obey anyone I'm going to do my own thing
And sure enough she came to the end of herself
And then she somebody got a Bible to her She opened the Bible
and she started to read
And guess what happened She met Jesus
And the minute she met him there's a peace that came over her soul A year
and a half ago She was married to a woman
She went to the girl She said I can't be married to you
She got a divorce She's serving God
She's been telling her story all over the place
How many know God is able Let's close our eyes for a second
Maybe you're here today
and you've maybe this is your first time here Maybe you've been coming for a short while right
We're gonna pray for all of us
but you know you really can't have rest until you rest in Christ Jesus
And if that's you here today
and you're like I've tried everything in my life I've tried it all
but I still don't have rest The Lord brought you here
because there is one who can give you rest in His name of Jesus
And if you walked in the room and you're like
Man
I just I am so at the end of myself I need something new
and I want to put I want to try Jesus I feel Him knocking on the door of my heart
I want to open up my heart and receive Jesus
It's as simple as a prayer And if
and He knocks on the door of our hearts
He says Anyone who will open the door I will come in
and I 'll sup with them I will give them rest
If that 's you you want to accept Jesus right now
Could you raise your hand Anybody here in the room You want to accept Jesus
Thank you Anyone else Thank you I ' m gon na just wait Just just lift your hands
Anyone want to accept Jesus right now Hallelujah
Several hands have gone up We 're gon na pray for them
But what about someone else You came into the building
and you're like I need rest You need rest from your weary soul
Come on lift your hand if you need rest
We're gonna close right now If you're here you came
and you're like I need the rest of God
Hands are going up all over the building
Come on let's stand to our feet We're singing it Need you
so I need you so Jesus Jesus I need you so
Come on one more time before we pray everyone I need you
so I need you so Jesus Jesus I need you
so Father I lift up every person who raised their hand to receive you
and I lift up every person who needs rest right now
People who've experienced trauma People who walked in with wounds God people who are watching online
and they're at the end of themselves Father in the name of Jesus release your rest God we pray for
the peace that surpasses
all understanding
God we pray for healing in the name of Jesus
We pray for hope in the name of Jesus
We pray O God that you would sweep over this place O God
and that you would open doors O God as we trust you as we rest in you God
We declare we will rest in you
O God God I pray for rest for those who've never accepted the Lord
Just repeat after me Let's all do this together
Say Lord Jesus thank you for this day You brought me here
because you wanted to meet me
And Lord I really needed to meet you
So I'd open up my heart
and I invite you in to be my Lord
and my Savior and my Master
and my friend You died on the cross for my sin
and I receive what you've done for me
And Lord now be the King of my heart
and the King of my life Thank you for receiving me even as I receive you In Jesus' name
Amen Amen Come on let's praise God for everyone who has lifted their hands Come on
before we go stretch out your hand to the left
and to the right Father in the name of Jesus we pray for rest to the left
Come on pray Let's just pray You don't know what someone brought in the room
Rest to the left Rest to the right
O God Meet needs Lord God Meet hearts today in the name of Jesus Lord
Hallelujah Let's lift up one hand
and sing I praise Your name Same melody Let's sing it
I praise His name I praise His name Jesus Jesus Jesus I praise His name Father we thank you
We really thank you for Your Word today By Your grace we enter into Your rest today
No discombobulation struggling fighting turmoil
We enter into the beautiful rest that only Jesus can give Would you bless the offering online
and giving now as we leave Would you bless the 60s fellowship That's going to be starting now
Would you bless the welcome center so
that we can hug people
and give them a gift
and pray for their needs
We just thank you for a day in your house Get us home safely Watch over us
Keep us close to you We ask all of this in Jesus' name
And everyone said