Welcome everyone that's on stand.
So good to see all of you.
Those of you watching online enter in with us today.
Amen?
Let's worship the Lord.
Has he been good to you this week?
Has he been faithful?
Is he worthy of the praise today?
Hallelujah, Lord.
We come into your presence with thanksgiving, God.
We enter your hearts with praise, Lord.
We lift it up in this place, Jesus.
Come on, sing with me.
We stand and lift the blood.
For the joy of the Lord is not saying.
Holy is the Lord, God of my TV.
The earth is filled with story.
Holy is the Lord.
God of my TV.
How awesome is me.
Holy is the Lord.
God of my sea.
God of my city.
Come on, give your voice.
Oh holy standard with the head.
For the joy of the Lord is used.
We are down and worshiped with God.
Our praise our pity.
Holy is the Lord.
He dead is filled with his glory.
God of viety.
We stick his standard with our pride.
Holy in the Lord.
Holy is the Lord.
The earth is filled with this glory.
God of my seed.
Holy is the Lord.
Holy Suns.
God of my seat.
Holy is the Lord's God of my seat.
The earth is still with his glory.
Is still with his glory.
Hallelujah.
Come on, lift your voice to the Lord this afternoon.
We worship you, Jesus.
Hallelujah.
We bless your name today, Lord.
We bless your name.
Hallelujah, Jesus.
We worship you, God.
We worship you, Lord.
We thank you today, Jesus.
Thank you for your love today, God.
Thank you for all of your provision, Lord.
Thank you for every blessing, God.
Thank you for your faithfulness, Lord.
Your mercies that are new every morning, God.
We say thank you, Lord Jesus.
Oh, God, that our hearts overflow with praise today, Lord,
for all of your goodness, God.
That we would count every benefit, Lord Jesus.
You are our strength.
You are our portion forever, Lord.
We bless your name today.
Free us to worship you, God.
Free us, God.
Open our mouths, Lord God.
Open our mouths, Lord Jesus.
Oh God, give us the freedom to praise you today, Lord.
Because you are worthy, Lord.
You are worthy, Jesus.
You are worthy, oh God.
Thank you, oh Lord.
We bless your name today, God.
Receive our praise.
Oh God, let it be a sweet alone to you today, Lord.
Let it bless your heart, Lord Jesus.
Hallelujah, God.
Come on, with all of our hearts less singles today.
Come on, open your mouth and worship the Lord.
He is worthy, he is worthy
he is worthy of all of our praise.
He is worthy of all of our hearts today.
Hallelujah, Jesus.
We worship you, Lord.
We give you praise, oh God.
We love the fire name of this praise, oh Lord.
We have the name of Jesus.
Come on, let's see it together.
He's in the way.
Come here, come with me, Sunday.
We scared it all to God!
He said awesome!
Come to me!
So I think it's awesome!
He's in awesome!
Is it too bad?
Hallelujah!
Blessed be your name, God!
Blessed be your name, Jesus.
Blessed be your name.
Hallelujah, Jesus.
We worship you, God.
We worship you.
We worship you, Lord.
We bow our hearts before you, Lord.
Oh, we bow our hearts before you.
You are God.
You are high and lifted up.
There is none like you.
At your name, every knee will bow.
Every tongue will confess.
At your name the demons tremble.
We thank you, Jesus, for your name today.
Thank you, there is power in your name.
What an awesome God you are.
Hallelujah.
The things of this earth grow dim, God.
Our problems become small in light of who you are today.
Thank you, Jesus.
Continue to give us revelation, Lord.
Give us eyes to see who you are.
Who you truly are, God.
Not who we've made you to be
but who you are.
You tell us who you are, God.
We are your people, Lord.
We love you, God.
We honor you, Lord.
Not just with our mouths, but with our lives today.
We honor you, God.
We yield to you.
We just surrender to you.
We submit to you, God.
We bless your name in this place, God.
We give you this meeting.
Have your way, Lord.
Glorify yourself, Lord, in this place, Jesus.
Let your name be lifted high, God.
We open our hearts to you, Lord
and we pray that you would move in us, God.
Do what you desire to do, Lord.
We yield to you, God.
You take control, Lord.
We love you and we bless you.
We give you the rest of this meeting in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Praise the Lord.
Oh Lord, you have turned my body into density.
Over and over and over again.
Oh God, you have turned my sorrow into joy.
Oh God, you have turned my body being into dancing.
Over and over and over again.
You have been much peam.
The middle of my head.
You are my joy.
I will always worship you.
I will always worship you for you.
You are my joy.
I will always worship you.
I will always worship you for you.
You are my joy.
You are my job.
Oh God, you have turned my body into density.
Over again.
Oh God, you have turned my sorrow into joy.
Water over again.
You have been achieved the neighborhood by God.
You are my joy.
I will always push you.
I will always push you for you.
You are my joy.
I will always worship you.
I will always worship you for you.
You are my joy into dancing.
You some party.
It's too dancing.
Over and over and over and over again.
It's in case he holds.
Great world on his eyes.
No greater sacrifice.
I'll just come back on.
What is the sun?
What is the stones?
Of the glory and the honor to the sun.
To the stars is opportunity.
I praise God for words of the star.
Now on the throne of majesty the fathers will complete.
He raised in victory.
I do get to the tea.
He is way too glory
and be honest to the sun.
But it's not for me.
We sang it this morning.
We say it.
Let's sing it again.
We sing it in a different context.
The Lord is a hiding place.
And the name of this hymn is He Hideth My Soul.
Let me say what I said this morning.
Sometimes the devil attacks your mind.
Your emotions.
Your nerves.
Have you ever been attacked?
Anyone here ever been attacked?
Just like the Lord has special moments for us.
He draws near to us.
The Bible talks about a day of evil when Satan attacks.
And I want you to know today
my wife and I have experienced many times in the ministry attacks of the enemy.
Give up, quit, be discouraged, whatever.
And you have to run to the Lord.
The hiding place, the shield is the presence of the Lord in the name of Jesus.
So my mother's favorite hymn was this song,
He Hideth My Soul in the Cleft of the Rock.
You know, you can get into a place in God where nothing can touch you.
How many understand what I'm talking about?
You can get there
it doesn't matter.
You cast off depression
you cast off attacks in your mind.
You have to do it.
And uh maybe you're under attack right now.
You could be in the choir and under attack.
You could be a minister and under attack.
Everybody gets attacked.
If you're a Christian, you get attacked.
Am I correct here?
So we're in no rush to do anything here.
We're gonna sing this hymn.
Let's stand up, everybody.
And if you're under attack right now, this week, this month, this day,
just like look, look at me.
Just attack, attack, attack, attack.
Just get out of your seat and come to the front
whether you're in the balcony or downstairs.
We're gonna sing this song over you.
You're not gonna quit.
You're not gonna give up.
You are gonna keep marching on with Jesus.
Amen.
Come on, let's sing it.
Come on.
Okay, okay.
Everybody says, Second, second.
Everybody, lift your hands up to the Lord and say wow, sick.
Let's dance up.
Cover us.
Protect my brothers and sisters.
Give them the joy of the Lord
which is their strength.
Peace that passes all understanding.
Satan, we resist you in the mighty name of Jesus.
We know who you are
but we point you to the cross
where Jesus died for us
and to the empty grave
where he rose from the dead.
He conquered you then
he conquers you now.
In the strong and mighty name of our Savior.
We will rejoice in the Lord always
and again we will rejoice.
For we pray it in Jesus' name.
And everyone said Amen.
I just came down from the mezzanine lobby just as uh you were singing
uh how whatever that third song you were singing.
Uh because from the end of the nine o'clock service I've been signing the book.
My book Jesus Every Day.
It's really, I know I'm gonna it sounds weird.
I hate to even say this
but it's really a good book.
I can't I can't believe I wrote it.
It's really it's a hundred-day devotional.
And today, uh no
in the last three days
I got a text from two ministers who told me I can't put your devotional down.
One said I'm reading two at a time
even though you're supposed to read just one for the day.
I get no money from this.
All pro proceeds go to the church.
Uh so I'm not hawking my book for personal reasons.
But you live ever you live your life one day at a time.
Look at me.
Stop thinking about yesterday and who said, she said, he said
and what happened yesterday.
You can't change it.
Why be anxious about tomorrow?
That's called worry
and God forbids it.
Don't worry about a single thing.
But give it to the Lord.
But today is the day, and many people
some of you here
you're messing up your every your life
because you're you're living in the past with regret, bitterness, resentment, unforgiveness.
Oh, yeah.
You can spend the rest of your life doing that.
Or you're worried about the future
and you let the only day you have today
today is the only day you live today.
Can I get an amen for that, please?
Today, Sunday.
You don't have Saturday, it's gone.
Don't talk about Monday.
No, no, monna is Possible, impossible.
Maso menu.
So uh Today is the day.
So I wrote this book, Hundred Devotions, short
that you get a little nugget of encouragement for every day.
Somebody could use a little spiritual vitamin for every day.
Amen?
That's all this is.
And um coming in uh I was here two weeks ago.
You know what?
I gotta get another job or something.
I gotta get another way of no matter what you do
sometimes you set people off.
So two weeks ago here I said
you know what Tyndale, the publisher
said by the way
uh Target picked up your book.
And from December to March
they're gonna have it in the Target stores around the country.
That never happened to me before.
I don't know how it happened, why it happened.
I take it as a blessing from God.
More people can buy the book, right?
All in favor, say aye.
No, there's someone out there
I know you're watching.
Uh you're uh you're not happy
because before I got to the airport
where I had to go to for a commitment
I uh I got uh an email saying
I've been watching
and I used to live in New York
and and I heard you announce
that your book's gonna be in Target.
You should be ashamed your book is in Target.
Don't you know there are leaders in the LGBTQW XYZ movement and all of that?
And you should be ashamed of that.
How would I know that?
And maybe someone who goes in there could buy it
and find Jesus as their savior.
Am I correct here or not?
If the Muslims want to sell it, I say amen.
Right?
Buddhists, I don't care if you want to sell it
because I know what it says in it.
Oh, this person lit into me.
And then ended like this.
And that, and you don't know that
and that you should be ashamed.
And by the way, blessings, bye.
You can't make these things up.
You can ask my wife.
We weren't even at the airport.
I was there, whack, whack, whack.
But praise God.
Praise God.
So I'm gonna be up there signing and the book.
You know what people did?
Some people were buying five or six books.
And I would I said, Why?
No, this is a Christmas present gonna be sending it to some people in Trinidad
, this, that, the other.
So however you want to do it, get one, get whatever.
If you don't want me to sign it
I sign it and I give one of my favorite verses.
Doesn't mean anything, uh nothing special.
I'm the one special
but if that means something to you
I'd love to meet you out there.
Did you know while we're on this subject?
I met some amazing people.
We have amazing people in this church like you.
The choir is gone
but something remarkable happened this morning.
You know that second song that I got up what he's done what he's done.
She said she started to sing the song.
And when she came to the words that he died for me or something
she broke she couldn't sing it
she put her hand up like that.
We were all listening, you know.
The choir, the the congregation sensed it.
You're so perceptive
you're so kind.
They they sensed what was happening
and some started to cheer for her
and she couldn't sing
so they picked it up
and they started singing her verse.
I never saw anything like that in my life.
And the choir was ooh and doing their ooze
and the church was singing
and she was like, No
I can't do this.
It was so beautiful, it affected people.
So I met someone up there who I signed a book for, and I asked
Where are you from and all of that?
And uh, this person was an usher or works with the children
I'm not sure.
I said, Where do you live?
She said, Upstate New York.
I said, What?
I said, Yeah, I live in upstate New York.
Probably an hour and a half from here.
And you usher here, and you do,
oh yeah.
I used to live in Pennsylvania.
And you came here every Sunday.
Oh yeah,
it's my ministry.
It's where God sent me.
And we have problems, what?
30 minutes away, 20 minutes away.
I have to walk 250 steps from where I live
and sometimes I'm going
I don't know about this.
I can't do that.
What a what a shame.
We got some wonderful people.
Let's thank God for the body of Christ.
Everyone, just clap your hand.
Remember that.
So just to give this report, Angola, prison, Louisiana State Penitentiary
for those of you visiting, 4,200 inmates.
Average sentence is 91 years.
Only murderers, double offenders, murder first degree, murder second degree.
There's people on death row who have been in death row for 10 years.
They're appealing and appealing.
Some other serious felons, but 91 years.
So we've been going there for years.
And I made a visit recently with the singers
a traveling group that Carol selected.
Carol and I were there.
We met people we knew from other visits
and um They had a beautiful meeting as you'll see, and I spoke.
So I got it in my heart.
Forty two hundred let's send forty two hundred boxes to the inmates for Christmas.
Soap, toothbrush, toothpaste, deodorant, a pair of socks, and maybe a New Testament.
So Pastor Eric Prez is working on it
putting it all together.
How many think that's a good idea?
Say amen.
Because the Christians there will be blessed.
They say there's almost a thousand now Christians there in the prison
because of what God's doing.
And um and uh the ones who are not believers
they'll receive this.
They'll say, why?
What am I getting this for?
And then the guys who are in there
who are like inmate chaplains, inmate pastors
they can really minister.
So we guessed it's like $80,000, $90,000.
He's still getting the numbers.
We're getting we gotta figure it out.
So I didn't I had it in my heart.
I told the Lord, Lord
I don't want to steal from the church and they're giving
because we have other things that are going on.
So God somehow provide.
And just this past week
or in the last 10 days
someone who was at our conference a few weeks ago from Sarasota, Florida
just called and said, Whatever it costs, shipping, everything, the bags
they can't have a box.
We found out we can't give them a box
because the prison has to see what's what you're giving them in each box.
So it has to be a plastic bag that you can see through.
And uh we're gonna get that.
And the person said, Whatever it costs, 80,000, 90,000, whatever
we'll pay for the whole thing.
And we thank God for that.
Come on, can we thank God for that?
That's the Lord.
That is the Lord.
And those watching, and in case you're watching, thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you, really thank you.
So this was quite a visit that we had here.
So uh just watch us
make it loud so they can hear that music, brother.
That beautiful.
And when you remember people like that and give
whether they're Christians or not
when you give to them
God is gonna bless us as a church.
How many believe that?
Lift your hand if you believe that.
If we bless people in prison
it doesn't matter what crimes they committed.
There, but for the grace of God
we all could be in prison.
So we bless them
God will help us and bless us.
And I want to remind you
we need your giving.
Those we we missed online
the online went down for the nine o'clock service.
I'm saying to all of you and to you there, um
please help us by giving online
or as you leave the building, they have baskets.
And sometimes it takes special gifts that God puts on your heart to get things accomplished.
And um we got one that God put in our hearts
especially my wife's heart
and that's for the Roma people who are over in Slovakia.
Among people who they don't want to hire them
they won't let their kids go to school
it's just the worst prejudice you could imagine.
Um to build that God is doing something
but they have no money.
And uh to build a church over there
where in all of Europe it would be the largest Roma gypsy
but that's not a good word.
Uh biggest Roma church in all of Europe it could be.
And uh when you bless people who don't have
you get such a joy, amen?
For wait a minute
I read that somewhere for it is more blessed
to the culture says, gimme, gimme, gimme, more, more, more.
And God says, give, give, give.
And your blessings will increase.
How?
I don't know
but he'll do it.
He can't lie.
Amen?
Some while ago I talked to someone I can't remember the the exact relationship
, the mother or the mother-in-law.
But it almost happened, I believe, to my sister-in-law,
but in this case, the mother, the mother-in-law elderly,
not you know, real um quick thinking at that age
was contacted by somebody who started to say
I uh I handle your investment portfolio
or a banking or financial advisor.
And uh I calling because I want to help you.
If you just strategically move your accounts around
uh you could get a much better rate than you're getting now.
And within 20 minutes
when they told her, okay
it's all set
now just press send, she lost everything.
How many scams are there out there?
Are we not getting warned every day?
How many of you are called
and if you don't know the number that you see, don't pick up the phone.
Lift your hand.
I called a minister the other day
he asked me to call him
and now when I called him
he didn't pick up twice
and then I knew he didn't recognize my number.
I had to text him and say it's me.
Remember, you asked me to call you?
And because everyone's on guard.
Why?
There's so much deception.
The culture is built on deception.
Everything is deception, not hardly anything is as it seems.
I'm thinking back to
when I we rented Radio City Music Hall for three years to do outreaches.
And I got to know the manager, uh the stage manager, biggest stage in the world.
You can't go out on that stage unless you pass by him
he tells you you can go.
When the spotlight is on the stage
where you're supposed to go
you can hardly see it.
I once walked out there and I was groping, praying, Oh God, please
I don't want to spend the rest of my life walking on this stage.
I gotta find where I'm supposed to go.
And I saw a little glimmer on the ground on the floor
and I went to it.
But he said to me, You know
I've been watching your wife in the choir.
And the stage hands too
and I know they curse like sailors.
And but they're toning it down during the rehearsals because you know what
uh you people seem to be real.
I said, Well, thank you
that's a compliment.
He said, No, listen
I've been working here for 10, 15 years.
You don't know what I deal with with these entertainers.
They use language that make our stage hands blush.
And they're cursing
they curse the crowd, big entertainers.
I can name somebody mentioned to me
you would all know the name.
He said, and then when their announcement is made
and ladies and gentlemen
let's welcome they totally transform into another human thing.
And they seduce the whole audience.
And when their act is over and they're walking off
whether they sing or they're comedians or whatever
they're cursing before they even clear the curtain
they're cursing the audience.
The foulest language.
And everyone's paying and buying their stuff and thinking they know them
they don't know them at all.
They're vile people, a lot of them.
He told me a couple that were more genuine.
But he says, I have to deal with that every night.
I hear they're cursing
they're lay at me
they're mad at everyone.
And then they he said
I'm telling you
it's like a transformation.
Deception.
It's very hard to find sincerity anywhere.
In other words, uh all that glitters is not even in church
how people act to you and act or preachers.
That's not who they are.
They could be a totally other person.
But they've learned the act of deception.
Now it's a big scam now
but it actually relates back to the original scammer, the original deceiver, who is Satan.
Satan is a liar from the beginning, the Bible says.
Jesus said that.
And he he's the master of deception.
When Satan attacks, there's two ways he attacks.
He does on a frontal assault
which is just what we were praying against.
Frontal assault, discouragement, depression
uh uh just attacking your mind
where you you think you can't take it anymore
and you just know this is not of God
this is the devil.
He has another way though.
He doesn't want to do frontal assaults all the time.
He sneaks around and he deceives.
He comes like a friend.
He sends people into your life who are not what they seem.
Just like God sends people into my life
my wife's life
who have been a great blessing
Satan sends people too.
What do you think?
He doesn't have control of people.
And they're not what they seem
and they're a trap.
They're sent by Satan to trap us, to hurt us.
The classic example of this, of course, goes back to the Garden of Eden
where the serpent came and pretended to,
you know, be fighting for the rights of Adam and Eve.
No, you should eat of that tree
because God knows if you eat of that
you'll know you'll be just like a god.
So I'm here to help you.
He wasn't here to help them
he's here to destroy them.
And there could be people situations right now going on that uh Satan is it's a setup.
So let's say this is the map of Israel, north-south
it's longer than it is wide.
Here's the north
there's the south.
Further south is the desert
where the Israelites spent 40 years after they came out of Egypt as slaves.
Forty years they wandered because of their unbelief
and now they came up, look, along this side
and this running the whole length almost of Israel is the Jordan River.
So they came up on the east side of the Jordan River
and Moses now died and turned the reins over, leadership over to Joshua.
Joshua's one of the great names in the Old Testament.
And now cross over the river and possess the land.
I've promised this land to your forefathers, Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob.
But there's people there that you have to drive out, destroy.
I've watched and waited
they will not repent.
Their religion is an abomination.
What they do to their children is an abomination.
I'm bringing judgment on them.
I'm using you.
So go and possess the land.
Do not spare anyone and don't make treaties with them.
And don't intermarry with them.
Because you will not convert them
they will convert you.
So have nothing to do with them.
You're a separate people.
That's the word meaning of the word holy or sanctified, separated to God.
So they crossed the river
and the first battle they fought was the Battle of Jericho
and the walls came.
There you go.
So after the Battle of Jericho
which they were victorious
they fought a battle against a smaller place called Ai, the letter A, the letter I,
and after a little problem there
they they won that battle.
And now they were going to go out and possess the land.
But all if you could just take that child out or hold the child
it'll not distract me and the people.
Thank you.
So what happened was the tribes around them that were in the land, Hivites, Jebusites, Amorites
they they heard what had happened.
And now they got together, some of them, and said, Look
let's form an alliance.
We don't like each other
but let's for this get together
because we gotta stand against these Hebrews, these Israelites.
So that was force against force.
Joshua 9 says it like this.
Now when all the kings west of the Jordan heard about these things,
the kings in the hill country, in the western foothills,
and along the entire coast of the Mediterranean Sea as far as Lebanon
that's up in the north,
the kings of the Hittites, Amorites, Canaanites, Perizzites, Hivites, and Jebusites.
They came together to wage war against Joshua and Israel.
So here's your classic picture.
We have Israel with God leading them
walking into where God sends them
and now people are gonna say
we're gonna fight you
we're gonna stand against you, force against force, and more numbers
numbers make for strength
so they're going to say
we're gonna align ourselves with each other so we can defeat them.
But not all the tribes who lived in that land wanted to just go head to head.
Satan has plan B. So let's read about it.
So, however, when the people of Gibeon heard what Joshua had done to Jericho and Ai
those first two battles
they resorted to a ruse, to deception.
The word there means a lie, a deception, a scam.
They ran something against them.
Now Gibeon was only like ten miles north of what would become Jerusalem
so they were right in that territory.
They were those people that were to be driven out
and have nothing to do with them.
God had told Joshua that.
But listen to what they did.
They went as a delegation whose donkeys were loaded with worn-out sacks
and old wineskins, cracked and mended.
They put worn and patched sandals on their feet.
They wore old clothes.
All the bread of their food supply was dry and moldy.
Then they went to Joshua in the camp at Gilgal and said to him, and the Israelites
We have come from a distant country.
Make a treaty with us.
The Israelites said to the Hives, by the way, those the word for Hivite
there in the Hebrew, Hebrew
the root means interestingly, snake.
Serpent.
Notice in the Bible
the Bible says Satan pictures two things.
The lion, Satan goes about like a roaring lion
and then he's a snake
he's a serpent.
Right?
So notice, lion head on
I'm gonna crush your skull.
Serpent, no, I'm gonna come a little sideways on you.
So those were the Hivites.
But perhaps you live near us, the Israelites said.
How can we make a treaty with you?
We are your servants.
What are you talking about?
Don't get excited.
We've come a long way.
They've been traveling for 45 minutes.
No, we've come a long way.
Don't you see the sandals?
Don't you see everything?
And look, we're your servant.
We want to help you.
Everybody needs a helping hand in life.
We're your servant.
They said to Joshua, but Joshua asked
Who are you and where do you come from?
And they were good at this.
They answered, Your servants have come from a very distant country.
Because of the fame of the Lord your God
for we have heard reports of him
all that he did in Egypt
and all that he did to the two kings of the Amorites east of the Jordan,
Sihon, king of Heshbon,
and Ag, king of Bashan
who reigned in Ashtaroth.
We heard about all that.
And our elders and all those living in our country said to us
Take provisions for your journey.
Go and meet them and say to them
We are your servants.
Notice, make a treaty with us.
Come on, just let's let's let's let's get along.
Come on.
We come a long way.
We don't want trouble.
This bread of ours was warm
when we packed it at home.
On the day that we left to come to you.
But now, look, see how dry and moldy it is.
And those wineskins that we filled were new.
But see how cracked they are.
And our clothes and sandals are worn out by the very hold that long journey, hold that.
So the way they traveled back then is they took animal hair
and they made what we would call like suitcases or packing crates
but it wasn't wood.
It was this these big sacks
and they would put their stuff in it
and both sides would be on either side of the donkey.
And they made that really old and all of that.
And they took another kind of animal skin
and put uh back in that day
they put wine there in that.
It saved the wine better than other possibilities.
So when they showed it to is it look
look at look how old this stuff is.
And look at our sandals.
Look at these shoes.
This is not Amazon Prime.
This is just this is some old stuff that we have.
Right?
So you know why it looks old?
Because we've been traveling so far.
Check it out.
Look at the bread.
The bread just came out of the oven when we left.
Just came out of the oven.
And now look at it.
It's hard like a rock.
I just gotta say this quick.
How many remember the day
when supermarkets would have a section of day-old food?
Raise your hand if you remember that.
No, most most of you don't.
But there was so A and P
which was back there
my when I was 10, 11, 12
my mother would send me Eastern European
wanting to save as much as she can.
Jim, Jimmy, go and buy this and buy that
and buy this on Floppish Avenue, right?
Parkside Avenue.
That's where I was.
And go to the day old section to get some day old bread because it's 30% cheaper.
So I didn't know
I didn't think of this.
But one day I went
and I took the day old bread
and I felt it.
And I hit the counter with it.
And it like almost cracked the counter.
And I had no cell phones
but I was thinking
this is just year old bread, not just day old bread.
But I had to be an obedient son
so I brought it back.
That's how their bread was.
Moldy hard.
Just as proof.
We've been traveling so long.
This this thing was right out of the oven.
Look at it now.
So now we read.
Ah, that's the killer verse.
The Israelites sampled their provisions
but did not inquire of the Lord.
They checked out the sandals
they checked out the bread
and they used their head, their brain.
They checked out everything they talked about, the clothes
everything looked dusty and all.
The one thing they forgot to do was ask the Lord what was going on.
Did you know you're not as smart as the devil?
Look at me, young man.
Look at me, sir.
Look at me, ma'am.
The devil's trying to run a game on all of us
and you cannot outthink him.
You're only how old?
He's been forever just about.
He has experience.
He knows you.
He knows me.
He knows how to run deception.
And what looks good is not good.
That road that looks so good
it could lead to destruction.
But he doesn't have a big sign.
Follow this to hell.
Follow this to destruction.
Of course he doesn't.
He says, follow this
and you'll be happier than you've ever been.
So they tested everything
but they didn't ask the Lord.
And finally, then Joshua made a treaty of peace.
There's hardly anything in the Bible wrong about Joshua.
But here's one.
He made a treaty of peace with them to let them live
and the leaders of the assembly ratified it with a seal.
So you know what that means?
A few days later
some people came to Joshua and said, Yo
you know the people we made a treaty with?
They're not from a far country
they're from down the street.
And the people heard about that
and realized that they had been deceived
and the people got in a big huff and went and said
Let's attack and kill them, those Gibeonites.
And Joshua and the leader said, We can't.
We swore to God before we'd said
that we wouldn't attack them.
We signed a treaty.
And now for the rest of the time in the Old Testament
they are going to be a thorn in their flesh
and be a problem that they didn't have to be
but it's because they acted
and got deceived without asking the Lord what was really going on.
You know, that guy that seems so nice, ma'am
he might not be that nice.
And guys, I know she's fine, I know that
but let's go a little deeper than that, okay?
Then she's fine.
Did you ask God about that relationship?
Well, you think he doesn't care?
Of course he does.
He might save you from a lot of trouble.
I've been duped.
Have you not ever been duped?
What someone you look at me
you've never been fooled by things?
Of course.
We're so limited in our intelligence unless you're proud
and think you're that smart and hip.
No, Satan's I've been at this game way longer than you and me.
They tested everything by using their brains
and they forgot there's something better than brains.
There's God.
And he knows everything.
He knows the beginning and the end.
He knows what's real and not real.
So the Gibeonites did not say we're gonna fight 'em.
And notice what they asked for.
They just asked for, look.
Let's just get along.
Let's just live together.
But God had said there's certain things you can't live together with.
Can I tell you something, sir, up in the balcony?
Bad company corrupts morals.
Have you asked God about those friends you're getting so close to
or worse going into business with?
What fellowship does light have with darkness?
I'm not talking about living on a hill in a monastery.
I'm talking about being a normal human being here.
But you gotta be very careful of what associations you make.
And who you date and who you marry and who you hang with.
We're to love everyone
and to share Christ with everyone
but we can't be with everyone
or they're gonna have an effect on us.
Look, just like God sends people into our lives
Satan sends people into our lives.
He has control over people
like God has control over people.
I look back on my life, so just recounting to Carol how certain people
, I missed them, my father-in-law
how God sent him into my life
and what he meant has meant to me
and then other friends I had in the ministry who took an interest in me.
They were life changers
but Satan has people too.
Not everything that glitters is gold.
And you can't tell a book by its cover.
But my book has a nice cover.
When you go up there, no
what did I just say?
I ruined this whole thing.
And my book has a nice cover
but it's really good.
Read it, it's good.
That's a bad example.
So, but let's be real.
Let's be real
let's do real talk.
So, you and I know we live in Brooklyn, a lot of us.
And well, if you live and grow up in Brooklyn
if someone walks up to you like they would do in other states and says
How y'all doing?
Good morning.
If you do that in Brooklyn
you reach for your wallet
and just put your hand on it and go, wait a minute
that wallet is there.
Am I right or wrong?
Well, I you I don't know you.
Why are you saying good morning to me?
It's a different mentality here.
But there's a lot of scam artists.
So let's just establish this as we close.
There's such a thing as deception
and Satan is the master of it
and part of spiritual warfare is not just fighting back
and praying back against forces against you
it's being wise and discerning enough to spot a scam.
So?
Look at what Paul says to a church in Corinth
where he had started this church.
Anyone you forgive, this guy had been sleeping in 1 Corinthians, he mentions it.
This man had to be put out of the church.
He was unrepentant about sleeping with his own stepmother.
And Paul said, No
you've got to put him out of the church.
He's unrepentant.
He could contaminate the other people.
But now the guy had repented
and when someone repents and is meet and means it
you forgive him and you try to restore people.
God is not interested in burying people
he's interested in saving people.
So now Paul says, Look
if I also forgive that person
and what I forgive in
if there's anything to forgive
I forgive in the sight of Christ for your sake.
In order that Satan might not out with us
for we are not aware
for we are not unaware of his what?
Scheme.
Not his power, his scheme.
He's a schemer.
He works stuff.
He'll send friends into your into your children's life that are messengers of Satan.
All friends are not equal for your children.
Am I correct or not?
Some might be wanting them to try drugs.
What are you going to do about that?
So we have to be careful.
He goes on, though, and says
not only does Satan have schemes, Satan
in his scheming and deception, goes right into the ministry and into spiritual things.
So there's fake pastors
there's real pastors
there's fake pastors.
There's real men of God, women of God, there's fake.
2 Corinthians 11.
For such people are false apostles.
You mean someone could call themselves an apostle
and wear a robe and a turnaround collar and be totally false?
Absolutely.
Or they could be a true man of God.
It's just not that simple.
Also, there are deceitful workers.
Oh, they're working
but they're liars.
They're working for their own good.
They want your money.
They don't care about your soul.
They want your adulation.
They want to be able to claim you as their following.
They're not interested in you
and Christ and your walk with him.
They masquerade as apostles of Christ.
So Halloween's coming up.
The world's going to celebrate that, right?
So what do people do?
They wear a mask.
So the whole point of the mask is
you don't know who I am.
All you see is the mask.
And he said, the preachers are like that.
These people taking advantage of you
they're wearing a mask.
They're not real.
Why are you looking at me that way?
That's not in the Bible
or is it in the Bible?
I'm asking you
is it in the Bible?
Masquerading as apostles of Christ.
And no wonder.
Aha.
For Satan himself masquerades as an angel of light.
Satan isn't walking around with a dark thing on and horns.
Are you thinking he's stupid?
When he comes after us
he can masquerade as a preacher, as an angel of light, as a dream in the night
as a light shining in your room
and now you know you're gonna follow that light wherever it leads you.
Don't follow it until you make sure it's of God or not of God.
Oh, I know, but the merchant preacher said Jesus.
I listened.
Demons say Jesus.
Jesus, get away from us.
We know who you are, they said.
So ministers don't fake ministers
these kinds that Paul's talking about.
They don't wear signs saying I am fake.
They come real, they look real.
They're like the Gibeonites, the bread
the whole thing looks good
but it's not.
Two ways, by the way
you can tell about them is number one
they're usually going to end up looking for your money
and talking about money all the time.
Watch, always look for that.
And number two, they're gonna lift themselves up in front of you as somebody special.
It won't be so much about Jesus.
Some of them won't even mention Jesus.
My wife just told me her sister was at a funeral
and at the funeral, a minister officiated.
How would you do a funeral for 40 minutes
and never mention the name of Jesus once?
No, how would you do that?
God, Lord, but that could mean anything.
That doesn't offend people.
You know what offends people?
Jesus.
Let me know what I'm talking about.
Just lift your hand.
That's where it sets hell off.
All hell breaks loose when you say Jesus.
Demons do not cower
and we don't have authority when we say, Creator of the universe, God of all truth.
Those are all true.
But the name that's above every name is the name of Jesus.
So they will play down Jesus
or they will produce
we learned that from 2 Corinthians
they'll produce another Jesus to you.
Not the one Paul told you about.
He says in that same context
I don't have the verse up, he says
you've received Jesus from these characters
but not the Jesus I told you about.
No, no, no, no.
No.
Not the Jesus I told you.
There's a white Jesus, conservative right-wing Jesus
there's a black Jesus
there's a Puerto Rican Jesus
eating baccalaito after the meeting or something.
There's uh the all-American Jesus, you know, blonde
and things any place for an NFL team or something.
There's the there's the prosperity Jesus.
All he's interested in is getting you more money.
Come on.
Am I kidding or am I telling the truth?
There's a hundred Jesuses out there.
So how do you know who's the real one?
How do you know who's the one who can save your soul from hell
and have your sins forgiven?
That's why he's talking about that.
And Jesus said, as the time goes on, I close.
As time goes on
it's not gonna get better
it's gonna get worse.
Pastor Simba, I didn't come to hear that.
Okay, I'll tell you a lie.
Uh it's gonna get great now.
Do you want a lie
or do you want the truth?
Okay.
Here's what Jesus said, not me.
Talking about the end times, Jesus said, Matthew 24.
Then you'll be handed over to be persecuted and put to death
and you'll be hated.
Hold that for a second there, Joy, by all nations because of me.
How would you recruit to have followers with that sentence?
Follow me, everyone, because you'll be persecuted
and you'll be put to death
and you'll be hated by everyone
so come and follow me.
Our American concept is no
don't say that.
If you want followers, tell them anything
but don't tell them that.
But Jesus said, No
I gotta tell you the truth.
But if you he that endures to the end
the same shall be saved.
And I'll take you home to be with me and forever.
So Jesus goes on and says
At that time many will turn away from the faith
and will betray and hate each other.
So the falling away will be people hating,
and a few, just a couple false prophets, will appear.
No, many.
And will deceive many people.
Why would the Lord let that happen?
It's the nature of life on earth.
At that time, if anyone says to you, look
here's the Messiah
or there he is
do not believe it.
For false messiahs, false prophets will appear and perform great signs and wonders to deceive impossible.
Even the elect.
What is that false?
Wait a minute, what does that mean?
They will perform great signs and wonders to deceive.
So there are people who, for a miracle, will run anywhere.
I've been around that since I was a kid.
Anywhere there's a supposed healing or a miracle
they're gonna run, give their money
follow the guy no matter what he preaches.
No matter how he abusive he is.
No, there was a miracle.
Well, we know God does miracles
but there's another kind of miracle that you have to be careful of.
It's not whether the guy was healed.
The question is, what's the sermon after the healing?
Because unless it's the gospel of the Lord Jesus Christ
we have to say away with you.
Come on, can we say amen to that?
Most people turn, a lot of people turn into miracle mongerers.
They just run after some sensational sign.
What's the guy saying?
What's his spirit like?
Oh, I don't care, but ooh, look what happened.
So we can't downplay God's power.
God is real.
How many believe God can do miracles?
Amen.
But it seems as if there's signs and wonders of another kind.
So they tested everything
but they didn't inquire of the Lord.
So what's the point?
The point is there's deception.
Satan is masterful at it.
Number two, what the goal of it was, just make a treaty.
Just put up with that stuff in your life, Jeffrey, if you come.
Just keep that friendship going.
You know you have no business talking to that person like you're talking to them.
That's inappropriate.
You know that.
But Satan's gonna say, listen, don't get carried away.
No one's perfect.
He's a master at that.
He's a master preacher.
Why did they get fooled?
Because they depended they depended
and relied on their brain
and their IQ rather than oh God.
These people claim to be from a far, far country
and it looks like they are.
But Lord, speak to us.
And the Lord would have told them get them out of town
and save them all that trouble.
You know the Lord loves you, you know that, right?
And he wants to save us from trouble and heartache.
And he wants your soul saved.
And you could be here judging what I'm saying
and checking me out and all of that
but you're not checking me out
you're checking yourself out.
How you react to this truth
you're you're determining how you look at truth.
Either these verses are true, or then throw this book away.
Then Jesus is a fake.
Because he's the one warning us.
False prophets, false teachers, false
oh my goodness, there's fake everything.
The main thing is we gotta ask God to keep us true.
Amen.
And I want him to protect our church.
I don't want fake things in our church.
Fake manifestations, fake preaching.
And if I should go off
and start preaching stuff that's not in this Bible, look at me.
Get up and walk out while I'm preaching.
And say, that boy
that fool lost his mind.
He lost his mind.
We've got to adhere to the word and to Jesus.
But here's, look
here's the last word.
The last word, 1 John 4, 1. Look at it.
Can you see it?
Dear friends, don't believe every spirit.
But test the spirits to see whether they are from God
because many false prophets have gone out into the world.
Test the spirits.
The Holy Spirit gives discernment.
The Holy Spirit can produce miracles, tongues, interpretation of tongues,
healings, word of wisdom, word of knowledge.
There's all kinds of things the Holy Spirit can do.
Read the book.
But one of the things he gives is discernment.
Discernment.
So that not judging everyone and being mean to people.
Because sometimes in our zeal
we treat people so mean
thinking we're being spiritual and we're not.
We're just being mean.
Satan hooked us by giving us a mean spirit.
So I'm trying, brother.
I'm trying as good as I can.
So what you have to do is ask the Holy Spirit give me discernment.
Don't enter into things quickly.
Look at me, please.
Look at me.
Don't make sudden decisions.
Pray.
Think.
Weigh it.
Talk to your spouse.
Talk to a pastor.
Get a prayer partner.
Don't jump into things and then you find out,
oh no, they're Gibeonites.
Come on, have we not all been fooled?
How many have been taken in at least once in your life?
Lift your hand, okay?
Someone lifted up both their hands.
I don't know what that problem was.
That's that's deep.
There's some deep stuff there.
Test the spirits.
Do I read about this in the Bible?
Is that Jesus there to oh, brothers, please?
I plead with you now.
If you want me to get on my knees
I'll get on my knees.
Please read your Bible every day.
Please.
Don't send me money every day.
Don't lift up the Brooklyn Tabernacle every day.
Read your Bible every day.
How do you know the true how do you will you know the false unless you know the true?
Do you know the people who work for the Treasury Department who are anti-uh counterfeiting?
Did you know what they do?
They don't study counterfeit.
They don't look at the counterfeit bills and say, oh
look what they did on that one.
They study every millimeter of a real dollar, of a real hundred.
And they know it, the color, the paper
they know everything about it so
that they know it so much
that if you bring a fake money,
they go, No, it's fake, get it out.
Get that money out of here because they know the real.
How many want to know the real Jesus, the real word of God, the real truth?
Come on, you have to know that.
I can't do that for you.
Women, come on Friday to hear Karen Jones.
Come on Tuesday to the prayer meeting.
I'll be leading it and exhorting you, hopefully.
But the point is
you can't live off of meetings.
You've got to walk with God.
Please walk with God.
Ask God for discernment.
If you're in some relationship now or getting close, come on out, choir singers.
If you're getting close to some, don't make a commitment.
If you're dating someone who's not a believer
would you please come up?
Just tell me up in the in the at the I'll be in the mezzanine.
I'll have someone pray for you
or I'll make an appointment.
Don't do that.
I know, but he looks so good
and he got a lot of money in his bank.
Pastor Simbal, the last guy I went out with
he was asking me to pay on the date.
I mean, uh, what's that about?
I got it.
He was broke, but he might have been a Christian.
There are broke Christians.
Why are you laughing?
Is that true or not?
Am I true or not?
There's broke there's Christians who are broke.
They have no money.
Oh, this guy got a lot of money
but what if he's a Gibeonite?
No, no, I'm not going to church now
but when I when we get married
uh I'll be there.
I mean, I know that like the back of my hand.
You know how many heartaches I've dealt with over these years?
You gotta talk to the Lord.
Jesus, what's going on here?
If you're at the crossroad making a decision
I plead with you and my friends behind me
we're pleading with you.
Go to God today and say, Lord, what's happening?
What's really what is this really all about?
I know how it looks.
I check the food
it's dry and moldy
I check the the saddlebags, but God
you know all things.
That's a close ride.
If you're right now making uh crossroad
or if something's happening that's like strange
and you can't really know, is this God?
Is it not God?
What you can't go by
that you make money from it.
God's not into it
whatever makes more money, that's him.
God is not like that.
You gotta find out his will
you gotta discern spirits.
Not everyone who loses looks so sweet has a sweet spirit.
They're like those characters that the Radio City musical guy told me about.
If you want to just come to God today and sing with us
He is all I need because you have a dilemma.
You're at a crossroads.
Just get out of your seat right now.
Just slide out from where you are, slide out and come here to the front.
Just come out of your seat and say, Pastor
I want to pray.
Your sermon was for me.
Come from the balcony, come from downstairs, whatever, wherever, just get up here.
Let's sing from the beginning.
Everyone sing.
He is all saying everyone.
Every eye closed, just before we all stand
if this is meant for somebody
please take it as a word from the Lord.
Be careful who you rent that apartment to or those rooms to.
Pray about that because once they're in
it's almost impossible to get them out.
And you might mean well
and you want to help someone, but know
know that it's God's will.
Pray, he'll show you.
Let the person do everything that's right, but then pray.
God is this of you.
He will lead you
he will guide you
he'll protect you.
All the people said, Everyone stand now.
Sing loud.
Come on.
Come on, sing loud.
He is all like this
everyone is saying that.
We have absolute confidence that you are able to keep us.
But part of that is looking to you for your direction
and your discernment for our lives about all these things, people, situations.
Seems like an open door.
It looks like a good job opportunity
but is it you, Lord?
Or they're gibbeanights behind the door.
We can't know that.
We're we're not intelligent enough, wise enough.
But you know everything.
And you're our father.
God, you're my father.
You're our father.
We love you, Father.
Just tell the Father that you love him.
Just praise him out loud
right where you are.
Don't be embarrassed.
Tell him out loud.
I love you, Father.
You're gonna protect me, Father.
So, Lord, for the people in front of me
whatever they're facing, give them direction.
Give them confirmation when it's of you
and give them an alarm when it's not you.
Because we want to do your will.
We want to make you happy.
And making you happy, we bless ourselves.
So we commit today to you.
Speak to us in a anyway, through the word by the Holy Spirit in a dream
and then uh confirm it so we know it's you, Lord, not our imagination.
You said test the spirits
teach us how to do that.
But not every spirit comes from God.
Protect us from fake preachers, fake apostles, fake miracles, fake everything.
We want the truth.
We want everything you have
but let it be true, Lord.
Let it be true.
New Testament, Holy Spirit moving in power.
We love you, Father
and we praise you, Father.
Bless the offering and the welcome center downstairs
but uh offering as people leave and give online.
Let my words, Lord, help somebody today.
You know, every time I've cried to you and said
give me something that will help the people.
You know that, God.
You know that.
I believe you gave me this word today to help the people.
Help us all through it.
Your word is truth.
We pray this in Jesus' name.
He is all in.