So I'm gonna make an announcement before my father dies.
I'm so happy I have this microphone first.
My son, Pastor Patrick
and his wife has her baby boy on Thursday.
So I have a lot to thank God for today.
We are so excited.
God is so good.
Hallelujah.
Come on, if you're thankful to the Lord for today
I want you to lift up your voice.
Sing with all of your heart today.
He has been good.
Let's sing together.
We are here together.
Sing with our hearts as one.
We're in our heart.
We are here together.
Switch our hearts as one.
We're in our spreads.
It is good to live the name of the Lord God.
He designed to give him thanks and praise.
He is right to give him thanks and praise.
And all that he has done.
It is good to live the bread of the Lord.
It is right to give him thanks and pray.
But his heart is up
and blowing with us and his mercy we can never say.
It is good to live the bread of the Lord.
It is right to give him thanks and pray.
In his collars with the name of the Lord our God
in his right to give it thanks and praise.
And his mercy we can never consider.
It is good to lose the pale.
It is right to give a face and ways.
But his heart is open going with the water.
At this mercy we can never say inspir.
At his mercy we can never save.
Not by beating ourselves out
because of our weaknesses and our failures.
Not in being afraid of punishment and condemnation.
If you feel weak today.
What a beautiful thought that is, isn't it?
In knowing that his perfect love casts out all fear.
Casts out all fear.
And as his love
that perfect love that paid the price for us
took the punishment so we don't have to fear it
so that we can come boldly to the throne of grace
and receive everything that we need.
Receive it.
Not earn it, not try.
Literally receive everything that you want today.
Everything that you want is received
because of free gift just lavished on you at the throne of grace.
A throne of grace.
Grace be what we don't deserve.
Just being given.
Because he loves us that much today.
And it's in that
that we become what he created us to be.
It's in that.
What a beautiful salvation.
What a beautiful gospel.
What an amazing God that we serve today.
Amen.
Allow his perfect love to cast out all fear in you today.
He loves you today.
He loves you.
And so, God, we worship you today.
You are worthy of praise.
What an awesome God.
What a beautiful Savior you are, Lord.
You are everything, God.
Everything that we need, Lord.
We stop trying.
We stop striving.
We stop trying to earn right now, God.
We rest in your perfect love, God
that you have bestowed on us freely, Lord.
We receive it.
We open our hearts to it right now, God.
And we receive it, Lord.
You are everything that we need, Lord.
We look to you alone right now, God.
Be our everything, Jesus.
Hallelujah, Lord.
Hallelujah, should we clap to the Lord for sword?
Hallelujah, you know, shout out praise today.
What a money.
Come on, sing it out.
She's the Lord.
With the dark hands in the same way.
With the dark hands to give you the glory.
With your dime to give you the praise.
And we will praise you for the rest of our days.
Yes.
We will praise you for the rest of our days.
We can dive hand and must have prayed.
We live our hands to give you the glory.
We lift our hands to give you the praise.
And we will praise you for the rest of our days.
Yes.
We will praise you for the rest of our days.
We clap our hands in the state you air.
We clap our hands to give you the gold.
We clap our hands to give you the praise.
And we will praise you for the rest of our days.
We will praise you for the rest of our days.
We save us all to give you the Lord.
We save us all to give you the praise.
And we will praise you for the rest of our day.
Yes.
We will praise you for the rest of our day.
Jesus, we give you the praise.
We pray you had.
We give them your day.
Melody father.
Nothing but stop.
And we will praise you for the rest of our day, Jesus.
We will praise you for the rest of our day.
Hallelujah, we have sent you.
But I know who he is.
He is my home and my defense love and everything.
That's just who he is.
It's my elder.
It's my birthday.
It's my aunt away.
It's my brother.
What's up?
That's a big.
It's my dog.
That's the beef.
What's up?
That's just cookies.
But I know just to be hope in my defense.
Love and never end.
That's just who he is.
It's my hope in my defense.
Love and never end.
That's just who he is.
Amen.
Let's put our hands together and praise the Lord.
Now Lanise is going to come
and she's going to ask God to bless the offering.
We're going to take it like this.
Not physically pass a basket
but as you leave, there's baskets.
And most people give online.
Those watching online, welcome, good morning, and thank you
all of you that send in gifts.
People send in $20, $200.
I opened one letter this week.
There was a check for $1,000 from someone who doesn't even come here.
And what can I say?
Thank you.
And thank you to you.
Because you're keeping everything paid
and on the up and up.
We have extra expenses at Christmas time.
We're trying to do all these things, outreaches and a Christmas show.
We'll tell you about that soon.
But uh unfortunately it all costs money.
But God made it so
that we can partner with him.
He has his blessing
and we can do our work, our singing, our preaching, our whatever.
But we can give toward the work of the Lord.
You know what Pastor Bryan will give a little report on Tuesday.
He just got back from Algeria.
Algeria is in northern uh Africa
and Muslim and kind of shut tight right now.
He told us before we came down here
that he found out a gospel preaching church in that entire country of tens of millions of people.
There's one church that preaches the gospel.
And now Christians can't even talk together like in a restaurant.
If they find Christians gathering together
you suspect and something could happen.
And they're against any kind of overt Christianity.
You can witness, you can't witness
you can't invite anyone
you can't celebrate Christmas.
And here we are.
Are we not blessed today that we can gather?
Come on, let's give God just a hand clap of praise
that we have freedom to gather.
And we take that for granted.
Just think about what we complain about
and compared to people who are suffering real persecution.
So let's do our best
let's give our best
let's sacrificially uh give
let's bow our heads.
Linese is gonna pray.
Thank you, Jesus.
Lord, we praise your name.
We thank you for this opportunity
that we can come in and worship you freely, Lord God.
With abandon, Lord.
Lord, better is one day in your courts
better is one day in your house and a thousands elsewhere.
And we just praise you, Lord
for the opportunity again
just to worship you freely.
Because we know that others are not able to do so, Lord God.
And and we thank you for the opportunity to give so
that we can partner in the ministry of reconciliation, Lord God
not just what we're doing here in our local church
but uh partnering with our missionaries who are functioning all over all across the world, Lord God.
So I pray that you will just impress upon the hearts of your people to give,
to give freely, to give cheerfully, Lord God
knowing that that they're giving to your work for the expansion of your kingdom so
that souls will come to know you as Lord and Savior
because that is why we're here, Lord God.
So I thank you and I praise you for the gifts that are gonna be coming in so
that your people will know you for who you are.
We praise you, we magnify your name.
In Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
Thank you, Lanise.
Let's hear it for the choir, too.
They were a blessing for thou, O Lord.
Everyone loves a story that has a great ending, uh, come from behind,
unlikely ending starts, you know, very small and then no hope
and then it grows bigger
and God blesses and it ends with a triumph.
Everyone likes that story.
That's Rocky.
All those Rocky movies were based on one thing, which is,
you know, the guy, yo, Adrian
I did it for you, and all of that.
Uh all the way to the championship and all of that.
And the Bible has tons of those.
Tons of those.
Uh Joseph, despised by his brothers
he rises to the top, saves the people.
Uh David, the little shepherd boy, kills Goliath and becomes a king.
And so on and so forth.
And then the changes of people's lives in the New Testament
where they start messed up like all of us have been
and then through Jesus Christ they change.
But there are stories in the Bible that are reverse.
And that's why I want to talk about one today.
Why would why would God put in reverse stories
where it starts high and ends low?
Why would he do that?
Both Old and New Testament
there's these stories as kind of warnings
or signposts or blinking lights to remind all of us
that uh sometimes things start better than they end.
And we want them to end better than they start.
Amen.
So of all the people, uh hard to understand the story
and uh uh hard to understand the book actually of Judges.
But let me just say who the judges were.
So after the people of Israel came out of the is uh Egypt
and went through the wilderness for forty years, and then came into the land under Joshua, Moses died
and they possessed the land more or less.
But there were tribes that didn't get out
and then there were surrounding tribes that were a thorn in their flesh.
And now comes the book of Judges.
Joshua dies, and now all hell literally breaks loose.
Because everyone ends up doing what was right in their own eyes
that's how the book ends.
There's no steady moral leadership.
Even the people who God uses are sideways in so many ways.
And it's just the
it's the most depressing book in the Bible for sure.
Because here's the cycle
which we'll see.
The cycle is the people are in the land and they're worshiping God
but all the idols are around them of the culture of the people,
the Canaanites or the Philistines or whoever.
And they have their women there and their beautiful daughters
and they seduce the Israelite men who marry them
and then start worshiping their gods.
And then they bring the whole people into worship uh Israel starts to worship all these foreign gods
that God said was were an abomination.
So uh, and then what happens is God uh tries to warn the people, talk to them
they're not listening.
Nah, I'm not listening.
I know, but look what I did.
I brought you out of Egypt.
I did such and such.
I know, I know, I know.
That was the old stuff.
It's a new day.
Whenever you hear people say it's a new day
just hold on to your wallet.
So um there's nothing new under the sun.
Just takes different forms.
So then what happens is God says, Oh
you don't want to serve me?
Okay.
The people of that day had geopolitical answers for what was happening
but that's not the answer.
It was God.
God would say, You don't want to serve me?
Good, go serve the Philistines for 10, 20 years.
See how you like that.
So now the Philistines or some tribe is grounding the Isra uh the Israelites under their feet
and making it hard for them.
They're starving, their children are uh are are uh uh prejudiced against
and then the people get desperate
and they cry out to God.
As they cry out to God
God's ear is always open, like with us
and then God raises up a judge.
So the judge was sometimes a military ruler, a military champion, sometimes a wise uh ruler
or someone to gather them together and decide issues.
One of them was uh a female, Deborah, was one of the great judges.
And they bring order and some religious turning back to God.
But just let some years pass by and they backslide again.
And now they're messing around with other gods and other tribes.
And then God says, What?
And I'm talking about not just a day or a month
I'm talking about years.
Years go by, and then God says, Fine.
Again, you don't want to serve me
I'll let you serve these people that you think are so great.
Their gods are.
And then for 10, 20, 30 years
some just think some little kid grew up at eight
and by the time they were 38
they never were free because of this um captivity they were in due to their spiritual wandering.
And then God would they would cry out to God, God's amazing.
No matter how many times you mess up
how many have found in your own life
when you call on him and you're sincere
he will come and help you.
Wave your hand if you have found that in your own life.
I don't care how you've messed up.
So that's the story of who the judges are.
And some of them we hardly know anything about, some like Gideon, Jephthah
we know a lot more about.
And now we come to the man, Samson.
So let's read.
This is an anatomy of a disaster.
Again, the Israelites, see, again
they did evil in the eyes of the Lord.
So the Lord delivered them into the hands of the Philistines for 40 years.
Look, look, they're sell they're suffering for 40 years because of their spiritual wandering.
So sometimes we go through stuff, brothers and sisters.
Don't blame your mother-in-law, don't blame the culture,
don't blame the man
don't blame anybody.
Look first at yourself.
Do I get a witness here?
Because what we sow
we also end up reaping.
So that's what happened here for 40 years.
And a certain man of Zorah named Manoah from the clan of the Danites
the tribe of Dan
had a wife who was childless, unable to give birth.
The angel of the Lord appeared to her and said
You are barren and childless
but you are going to become pregnant
and give birth to a son.
So through natural means, with her husband, Manoah
she's gonna have a baby
although there's no logical way she can have a baby.
And now see to it
that you drink no wine or other fermented drink
and that you do not eat anything unclean.
You will become pregnant and have a son whose head is never to be touched by a razor
because the boy is to be a Nazarite, dedicated to God from the womb.
He will lead in delivering um Israel from the hands of the Philistines.
So let's get this beginning.
Not too many guys in the Bible were predicted their birth before they were born.
Not a whole lot of people.
John the Baptist was one
obviously Jesus was one.
So this is a special little baby gonna be born.
And the Lord tells the parents
now make sure you live separate and consecrated
but now he's gonna be a Nazirite.
What was a Nazarite?
A Nazarite was not a tribe.
They had twelve tribes and they had the Levites
but a Nazarite were people who took on vows
or it was put on them, in this case by God,
to be specially consecrated to God,
specially dedicated to do God's will, specially living close to God.
And they drank no wine or beer
and they didn't cut their hair
and uh they were just separate.
He's a Nazirite.
It's not a New Testament term
it's an Old Testament term.
But like we would have in the Middle Ages people going into the monastery
or convent to be a nun or priest,
oh no, he's gonna take the cloth
he's gonna he's gonna go in there especially dedicated.
So um this child is gonna be special.
This child has to be guarded
the parents have to watch out for him
because this boy is gonna deliver when he grows older
he's gonna deliver the people from the Philistines.
God has chosen his instrument that he's gonna use.
So now the story goes on in chapter 16.
Well, let's let look up here at me before we read that.
Now, Samson, when he gets older
begins to judge Israel and deliver them.
How does he do it?
It's he does it through physical strength.
He's the mightiest warrior ever in the history of Israel.
But what's strange about it is he's not jacked up.
He's not buffed.
He's not at LA Fitness, you know, twice twice a day.
He's not pumping iron
he's not taking protein shakes
he doesn't look big.
He's not 6'6, 260.
That's the weird thing about it.
He looks just average
but when the spirit comes on him
this is Old Testament
when the Spirit comes on him
he he he becomes Rocky Balboa on steroids, right?
He takes everybody out.
He cannot be controlled.
Doesn't matter how many you put against him
he fights uh ferociously.
And that's the way he leads Israel uh to freedom.
So he rules for a while
and he's a strange person to read about
but judges is a strange book
and Samson is one of the stranger people in it.
But he rules and gives deliverance
and no matter what they throw against him, he beats them.
He beats the Philistines To death literally.
As time goes by, twenty years remember
something must happen to him.
His brain must go soft
his spirit gets hard, he gets proud
maybe he gets callous.
Like, I'm Samson.
Dude, dude, my name is Samson.
I'm not Benjamin Bo.
I am Samson.
And that can happen to us.
You know, the blessing of God becomes a curse.
God uses us, blesses us, helps us.
And we start out very humble and we need the Lord.
And now as time goes by, instead of becoming more in love with the Lord
we start to think
we feel our oats.
We get full of ourselves.
Always remember, when you're filled with someone's filled with the devil
it can be cast out.
But when you get full of yourself
it's a whole set of problems, different set of problems.
So as time goes on
he's just doing some very strange things
even though he's the judge that God raised up.
Remember, from birth he was named.
So one day, Samson
this is three chapters later, a lot of water under the bridge.
One day Samson went to Gaza where he saw a prostitute.
He went in to spend the night with her.
The people of Gaza were told, Samson's here.
So they surrounded the place
and lay in wait for him all night at the city gate.
They made no move during the night, saying
At dawn we'll kill him.
But Samson lay there only until the middle of the night.
Then he got up
God probably woke him up, and took hold of the doors of the city gate
together with the two posts
and tore them loose, bar and all.
He lifted them to his shoulders
and carried them to the top of the hill that faces Hebron.
Okay, so he still got the blessing of God on him, but yo, Samson
why would you be with a prostitute?
Is that God's plan for your life?
Is that a good example for the rest of the Israelite?
I know you have a track record
and you're all that
but is that appropriate?
What are you thinking?
What's going on?
No, I'm Samson.
Something's going on
wouldn't you say?
But listen, all disasters start with little things.
There had to be little things going on before that.
Where you just, instead of feeling your need of God
and humility and trust in God
you start to strut around
and think you're all that.
And Samson must have got all of that.
But he's not gonna stop at that.
Here comes, you know
God sends people in our life to bless us.
How many believe that?
Say amen.
How many have had people in your life, a friend, a pastor, a relative
somebody who blessed you and the Lord used them?
Just lift your hand if you have people like that.
Well, guess what?
The devil has folks too.
And you have to discern now in life is this someone the enemy is sending to pull us down?
Because oh, the enemy had someone for him
and her name was Delilah.
Just that name, right?
Sometime later he fell in love with a woman in the valley of Sorak
whose name was Delilah.
The rulers of the Philistines went to her and said
See if you can lure him into showing you the secret of his great strength
and how we can overpower him so
that we may tie him up and subdue him.
In other words, could you please find out the secret?
This guy six one, 180
and he tears us up.
How does he do it?
There's some secret
there's some connection with his God
that this power comes on him.
Could you please find out what it is?
Because when he's like that
we we have no hope.
So they tell Delilah that each one of us will give you 1100 shekels of silver.
So they make it attractive monetarily for her.
So Delilah said to Samson
tell me the secret of your great strength
and how you can be tied up and subdued.
Hello, Samson.
Calling Samson.
Check your emails.
Delilah is asking you the secret of your strength.
Why would she do that?
And you don't know her that well
and she's a Philistine.
What exactly is this about, Sam?
But guess what?
Samson's already sleeping.
I told you it's an anatomy of a disaster spiritually.
And one of the things Satan is working for all of us
starting with the speaker
is to put us to sleep.
Spiritual sleep.
You're moving around
you're doing all kinds of stuff.
You're agile, hostile, and mobile
but you're sleeping.
Your spirit's gone to sleep.
So he gives her three fake answers
which I'm not going to read, and says, No
if you do this
if there's bowstrings that have never been used before
if they tie me with that
and then I'll be like all the other men.
She tells the Philistines
they get the bowstring
she ties him up while he's sleeping
and then she yells, Yo, Samson, the Philistines are here.
And he just breaks them like that.
And they go running into the hills.
And she has the chutzpah to say to him, Samson
why do you lie to me?
I thought you cared.
I thought we had a meaningful relationship.
Why would you lie to me about your strength?
Don't you know I want to get you killed
because I've just had a lot of money put in my hands?
And guess what?
He does it again.
And he does it again.
Three times he gives her false answers.
Samson, what are you doing?
Why would you want to play with fire?
Delilah is fire.
The Philistines mean destruction.
But isn't that the way it is with even believers who drift away,
start strong, start dedicated, start consecrated.
And now what are you doing in that club?
You're dating who?
It's quiet now
but you know that's true.
Am I correct or not?
We can find our places in we can find ourselves in places
where the Holy Spirit is saying to us
what are you doing here?
Watching what?
With who?
But Samson, see that gradual thing.
I told you God puts this in the Bible for our learning.
And uh He's out to lunch now.
Imagine how stupid he became.
You know, when we backslide spiritually
we really become stupid.
Everybody says stupid.
Because that's how we get.
We get stupid.
We play with fire
we play and risking everything.
But for the moment it's like
I don't get it.
What's wrong?
Come on, brothers and sisters.
Let the word of the Lord go in all our hearts.
Satan will lead you to be stupid.
Even though you're bragging how smart you are
how much money you're making
and you're going to the Bahamas on a vacation and all of that, but really stupid.
So finally, there's this verse.
Then finally, after the third time
then she said to him
How can you say I love you?
She had little tissues that she would wipe through her eyes with.
How can you say that you love me
when you won't confide in me?
Don't you know I want to get you killed?
Why don't you share more?
Come on, open relationship.
We need meaningful talk and conversation.
Quality time.
Right now, Samson, come on
give me quality time.
Open your heart.
I'll open my heart to you.
So predictable.
He was in love with that.
The Bible says he was in love with her.
It goes to warn you
you gotta be careful who you fall in love with.
It doesn't say he thought he was in love
it says he fell in love with her.
Just because you're attracted to someone doesn't make it right.
No, God wouldn't let that happen if it wasn't right.
You're wrong.
This is the third time.
No, go back, I'm sorry.
This is the third time you've made a fool of me
and haven't told me the secret of your great strength.
And now, this verse is always makes me laugh.
This verse, which they just took off the screen.
Um we have another one here?
What happened?
By the way, we want to apologize.
The lights have been dimmed today.
There's something sideways with the lights.
Have we got the verse?
Just tell me what I should do.
There we go.
With such nagging, she prodded him day after day until he was sick to death of it.
I'm not asking any husbands to say amen about anything.
No, I am not going there.
I refuse to go there.
But come on, guys, under the cover.
How about a little amen over here?
You know.
Just like she drove him to distraction by nagging.
Better, oh, Proverbs, better to live on the top of a roof alone
than with a wife who just drips and drips and drips.
But let me turn it around.
Better to live on top of the roof than with a husband who drips and drips and drips.
Down, women, down, down, down, down, down, down.
Boy.
Everybody is really into this.
But is it not true?
Person who nags you
you just want to.
I watched in stores, toy stores
when kids just start nagging their mother.
No, I'm not getting you that.
It's too expensive.
But oh, they don't stop.
They go and go.
Well, she nagged him to death.
You know, if someone said
that woman's gonna be the death of me.
Well, guess what?
She was.
And she got through by nagging.
Nagging.
So he goes and tells her this.
He told her everything.
No razor ever has been used on my head.
He said, because I've been a Nazirite dedicated to God from my mother's womb.
If my head were shaved
my strength would leave me
and I would become as weak as any other man.
Isn't that interesting?
Listen, Jeffrey comes.
The whole thing's secret was his consecration to God.
If you break that
all bets are off.
No, but God can do anything.
Not when you're running around with prostitutes and talking to Delilah.
I mean, don't live in fantasy.
Please.
All of us, wake up.
But God can do anything.
I got that.
But God's character is such
that you can't turn your back on him
slap him in the face before you do that
and do what you want to do
and then not think there's going to be repercussions.
So he told her everything.
And that's something.
It was God's power, absolutely.
But notice what made the power operative.
It was his consecration.
He belonged to God.
He was separated.
By the way, did you know that's what this word saint means?
When Paul writes letters in the New Testament to the saints at Ephesus, to the saints at Corinth.
Saint means separated one.
We're not supposed to be like people in the world.
We don't talk like people in the world.
We don't have the values of people in the world.
Let the people in the world laugh us and go
ha ha ha ha, they're Christians.
They won't be laughing for long.
We're supposed to be separated.
That's what a Christian is.
Christ died on the cross so
that we would be separated to him.
The Bible says if anyone loves the world
they're an adulterer.
They got married, but now they're running with other women.
That's what James, the half-brother of our Lord, says.
So there's a lot
and today there's hardly any emphasis on that.
Just get the people in church
and teach them a praise and worship course.
How they live during the week, shh, don't be judgmental.
We don't need hate speech.
That's that's regular fair today in churches across America.
Don't ask too many questions.
Doesn't matter how they live.
Dude, they're coming on Sunday
and they put something in the offering.
Don't rock the boat.
I know, but how do they live?
Shouldn't that be asked for all of us?
How many want to live for Jesus and be more like him?
Raise your hand up.
Otherwise, what are we doing?
So he tells her the secret.
It's my consecration to God.
Once you cut my hair
I'm not a Nazirite anymore.
And when I'm not dedicated to God, Jeffrey, he told her, I'm nothing.
No, but God has all power.
I know God has all power.
I got that.
But wake up.
Don't use Christian triumphalism to get around your situation on the ground.
On the ground, it's how we trust him.
The just shall live by faith.
Walk in the Spirit
and you won't fulfill the lust of the flesh.
Resist the devil and he will flee from you.
Don't I get an amen from any of that?
Anyway, that does matter.
Amen.
No, but I go to the tab on Sundays.
That's great.
I hope we're a blessing to you.
But Jesus didn't die on the cross and raised again
so you would go to the tab.
That's nowhere found in the Bible.
We belong to Jesus.
We're saints of the Most High.
We're in the family of God.
Am I right, brothers and sisters?
We're supposed to be coming more and more like our Father.
Ah, Samson, you're going the wrong way.
And here's the saddest verse, maybe, in the whole story.
When Delilah saw that he had told her everything, oh
be careful who you share with, you know.
Someone says, No, you've got to let everything out.
You gotta talk.
We're doing Freudian psychology.
You've got to go into your compartments and let everything out.
My foot.
There are some things better left, never said.
Forgetting those things that are behind.
Don't talk about them.
They're not worth talking.
They're under the blood
don't talk about them.
And don't give your secrets to Delilah.
So she sent word to the rulers of Philistines.
Come back once more.
He's told me everything.
So the rulers of the Philistines return with the silver in their hands.
You greedy little Delilah.
Looking for her money up front.
You talk about somebody brazen.
After putting him to sleep on her lap.
See, he put her
she put him to sleep on her lap.
But the problem was he wasn't
he was way asleep way before that.
She put him to physical sleep
but he was sleeping
maybe like some of you are.
You're sleeping.
That's why the New Testament says to us, Wake up!
Be alert.
Your enemy goes around like a proud like a lion seeking whom he may devour.
Wake up!
Be alert!
Come on, be alert.
For someone to shave off
she called for someone to shave off the seven braids of his hair.
That's one of the first weaves.
He had a weave before they were even in.
But now they're gone.
And so began to subdue him.
And listen, and his strength left him.
Here's the verse.
Then she called, Samson
the Philistines are upon you.
And he awoke from his sleep, only the physical sleep.
The other one he was too deep.
And he thought, I'll go out as before and shake myself free.
But he didn't know the Lord had left him.
Is that not a tragedy?
He didn't even know it was over.
He didn't know the Lord had left him.
Gradually he got sucked in.
And he's running with prostitutes
and he's doing this and that, and now Delilah
he's playing with fire.
What's he thinking?
I want to go there.
I want to talk to him.
I want to grab him and shake him and say, Samson
please just think what you're doing.
But we can't shake him
but we can shake ourselves.
What are we doing today?
How are you living?
What's our closeness to the Lord?
Are we really consecrated and dedicated to the Lord?
Do we identify as Christians first
or as Americans or white people
or black people or West Indian?
Is that your identity?
Lots of luck.
I'm none of those.
I am a Christian.
I want to be a Christian, number one.
Can we put our hands together?
I want to belong to Christ.
Ah, he did not know that the Lord had left him.
Let's read the end.
It's sad.
Then the Philistines seized him
gouged out his eyes.
But he was blind before that.
You get the story here?
You get it?
She put him to sleep
but he was sleeping.
They gouged out his eyes.
He's never going to see again
but he already was blind.
He was blind to what he was doing.
And they took him down to Gaza
and binding him with bronze shackles
they set him to grinding grain in the prison.
Now, it's true.
At the very end
his hair starts to grow back
and God shows mercy
but it's still a sad ending.
No one's going to convince me otherwise.
And they're mocking him.
Bring out Samson so we can laugh at him.
All the Philistines, because he had done a lot of damage.
And they bring him out and he said
Lean me against two posts, he's blind.
And then the spirit comes on him one last time
and he pulls down the whole amphitheater
and he kills himself along with all the Philistines that were there.
And someone says, Well
that that's a happy ending.
It's not to me.
Not to me.
Don't try to tell me that's a happy ending.
That's a sad ending.
Yeah, thank God God gave him a blessing at the end.
But that's the way Samson should die.
Grinding grain in a prison.
Blind?
Eyes gouged out, people mocking him.
So why would God put that in the Bible?
Well, how about this?
Let's jump to the New Testament
and just look at this one verse here.
Look at this in Hebrews.
Let us draw near to God.
With a sincere heart and with the full assurance that faith brings.
He's writing that to Christians.
Let's draw near to God.
Not all Christians live near to God.
Well, of course not.
Some wander, some backslide.
Some everybody in this front row lives in a different proximity to the Lord, spiritually speaking.
Less consecration, more consecration, more serious about their faith, less serious about their faith.
Just churchgoers.
Come on.
He says, let's draw near and stay near.
With full assurance that faith brings having our hearts sprinkled to cleanse us from a guilty conscience
and having our bodies washed with pure water.
And then the book after that one, our half-brother of our Lord says,
Submit yourselves then to God
and resist the devil and he will flee from you.
Come near to God and He'll come near to you.
Wash your hands, you sinners
and purify your hearts, you double-minded.
Come near to God.
Not physically like God's there
but once you cot a son with your heart.
Draw near to God.
He loves you more than anyone.
He'll protect you from everything.
He's got a beautiful table spread.
He's waiting.
Come unto me, all you that labor heavy laden.
But he's not going to force you to come.
He invites you to come.
Lo, I stand at the door and knock.
That was to a church.
Not that he was on the outside of a church, which was Christian.
Lo, I stand at the door and knock.
If anyone hears and opens the door
come in and be with me
and I'll be with you
and you won't believe how I'll bless you.
But you've got to open the door and come in.
Let me come in.
Is this not true?
It's not true.
I know this is not a kind of contemporary 2025 sermon in a lot of circles
but it's in the Bible.
What can I do?
God lays things on my heart
and I try to preach the whole counsel of God.
And part of the counsel of God is this draw near to God.
He'll draw near to you.
Don't you think he loves you?
When you didn't know him
Christ died for you.
Through thick and thin
hasn't he been there for you?
But don't turn your back.
Don't drift away.
That's why God put Samson in the Bible
and stories in the New Testament about people who even traveled with Paul the Apostle
and then forsook him because they got fell in love with the world.
They started dating the world.
Anybody here dating the world?
Break it off.
And don't give notice.
Just say bye.
But that's not polite.
Don't be polite.
Just break it off.
You're dating the wrong people.
Come to Jesus and stay there.
So what do you think, brothers and sisters?
Don't you think we all need this?
Is not this not a good warning and encouragement for everybody?
Listen, it hasn't stopped.
Wait, it hasn't stopped in the New Testament for the last 2,000 years.
There's stories of preachers
and missionaries and all kinds of Christians who started out so good
and then they ended up worse than sideways.
So the Holy Spirit is saying
He that hath an ear, let him hear.
Be alert.
Humble yourself.
So the last few weeks I've gone up there and signed my book.
And thank you for all of you that bought it.
I'm not doing that today.
You know what I'm going to do today?
I'll pray with you until the next meeting begins.
God put that in my heart about three in the morning.
I'll stay, some deacons will stay.
Because this is more serious than anything.
And some of you need just now that not just listen
I'm an expert.
I have a PhD in backsliding.
You should have checked me out in high school and college.
I wasn't even a strong Christian in college, and now look
I'm in the ministry.
Isn't God full of mercy?
Isn't he?
How many look back on your life?
It's only God's mercy.
Can we say amen?
Only God's mercy.
Only mercy.
So let's bow our heads.
If the Holy Spirit
as you're re hearing this sermon and listen to those verses,
you say, Pastor Simbala, you know what?
I'm not going to tell you all the angles and details.
But I need the Lord today.
I draw I need to draw near to God.
Maybe Lord sent me here today.
Like as a as a a warning.
A loving warning.
See, when the Lord warns us it's full of love
it's not screaming at us.
Don't do that.
Don't go that way.
No, no, say goodbye to Delilah.
Samson, what are you doing?
Anybody here wants me to pray for them?
Just stand right where you're sitting.
Just stand up.
Anybody just stand up right where you are.
Up in the balcony.
Anybody here?
I don't care if you've drifted one foot from the Lord.
One foot's too much for any of us.
We're either drawing near to God
or we're drifting away from God.
There is no middle ground, no holding pattern, no parking spot.
You're either drawing nearer or you're drifting.
Pastor, I needed to hear that.
I love the Lord.
I want him to hold me close.
I'm coming home.
Oh, that's a good song, you know.
Coming home.
Nevermore to Rome.
Open wide your arms of Lord of love.
Lord, I'm coming home.
Anybody else in the balcony?
Just stand up.
That sermon obviously was for everyone
but I believe there's some people that God appointed to be here today because, oh
did you need to hear this?
Oh, if Samson have only been in this meeting here before everything started to crumble.
If you're standing
come out of your seat and just come up here.
You can stand, you can kneel
do what you want.
I give you my word
I and others will stay with you as long as you just want to quietly pray.
Come on, come out of your seat.
Then we'll pray.
But now we're going to sing.
We're coming home.
Forgive us.
Forgive us our trespasses, Lord.
As we forgive those who trespass against us, forgive us, Lord.
Wash away iniquity.
Have mercy on us, Lord.
There's mercy with you today, Lord.
You love us.
We're coming home.
What were we doing?
How long have we been?