How many are happy in Jesus today?
There's joy, unspeakable joy in this place
because God is here.
Come on, let's sing this together.
Let the glory of the Lord rise among us.
Let the glory of the Lord rise.
Oh, let the praises of our key.
Let it rise.
Let's not let the rocks cry out today.
Let's say, let the glory of the Lord rise upon us.
Let the glory of the Lord.
Let it rise.
Let the peace of my key.
Let's have the breeze in the key.
Oh, that's the boy.
Oh, let me praise them back here.
Oh, we sign, single.
Jesus is worth living.
To the King of Kings
and the Lord of Lords this morning.
Let our praises rock.
The Bible says if we don't praise him
then the rocks will cry out.
Oh, let's not let the rocks cry out this morning.
He is worthy of all of our praise.
Hallelujah.
Praise you, Jesus.
Oh, we love you, Lord.
Oh, we worship you, Lord.
Hallelujah.
Glorify your name, Lord.
Oh, can I just encourage you to speak your praises out loud this morning?
Let's sing this together.
I stand a mix.
I stand a mixed.
And wrong meetings.
Listen.
I said.
I said you lift your voices, sing how marvelous Jesus.
He took my sin.
He took my sin and my son is only to have seen my song singing singing.
Well, as the instruments play
if you have a testimony of your own today of how Jesus loved you
how he saved you
just lift your voice to him.
Just take him.
Oh, thank you, Jesus.
How marvelous, how wonderful is his love.
Praise you, Jesus.
Oh, we praise you.
Oh, we love you because you first love us.
Should go all the way.
She has cry.
Should the holding one in place because he's as crashing.
Let the wheat say I have small.
Let the boy say I ever knew
Because the What the Boy has done for Let the Weeks I have strong.
Let the poor say I have
because of what the poor has give.
Let's say give thanks.
Because of what the Lord has for me
say I am so let the poor say I am race
because of why the Lord has the course say I pray because of one the border.
Let the police say I am song.
Let the poor say I am rich
because of what the doing has done for us.
I was distracted thinking
weighed down by whatever and a little bit of a funk.
Do you ever go on a funk?
And a voice said to me, probably my conscience
why don't you give thanks?
You preach about it.
Why don't you do it?
I just preached a few weeks ago about in everything give
And I said, you know what?
I don't want to be a hypocrite.
That's true.
So I started to give thanks.
I felt nothing.
But as I started to give thanks
because it had been a few hours since I had given thanks to God for anything
everything began to change in my life.
My heart my mind a peace came.
I was reminded that God is faithful.
So can I tell you something today?
If you're going through pressures
and toils and snares and and you've been distracted
why don't you just give thanks to God today?
You know, some of you owe some of you owe not to the IRS
you owe to God a lot of back thanksgiving, right?
Back praises.
How many owe God all the praise, all the thanksgiving?
So we're gonna sing that.
I like that song.
That's from the scriptures.
Uh and we're gonna sing a little verse.
Uh and if you're here today and say, Pastor
I need to do what you did that day.
I need to just start giving thanks.
But I don't feel like giving thanks.
God doesn't say feel anything
He just says give thanks.
In everything, give thanks.
See if it won't turn everything around.
Come with your heart, come right to the front, from here, upstairs.
If you're watching online
why don't you stand up
and start to give thanks online?
Let's start with the verse, okay?
Come on, with your grateful heart.
Come on.
To the holy one.
Give thanks.
Because he's given.
Jesus Christ.
Give thanks with the grateful heart.
Give thanks.
To the holy one.
Because he's given everyone.
Jesus cry.
Now lift your hands.
Lift your hands and say that.
Let the wig say I am strong.
Let the court say I am wakes.
Because of what the Lord has done.
Let the wig say I can song.
Let the court say I have written.
Because of what?
The Lord has done for us we may sing that verse again.
Maybe some of you other folks need to come up here and join us.
This is the Thanksgiving choir.
Amen?
Let's start on the verse.
Give thanks.
Give thanks with the grace.
Come on, be grateful.
Because he's given us.
He's given us the sun.
It fell with the great one.
In fruit of holding one.
In fact, because he's given Strong everyone.
He's one of the voice.
Let the wheat say I am send the course say I ever say because of one.
Let the wheat say.
Because I'm strong.
I am strong.
Let the wings say I am song.
Let the poor say I am raised.
Because of what the Lord has done.
Lord, we thank you for all your blessings.
We are rich in Jesus.
With the riches that never pass away.
We are strong in Jesus.
Not our strength, but his.
We have everything we need
therefore my God will supply everything we need.
We rejoice in your peace
and your love for us today.
We shall shake off any discouragement and depression.
In the name of Jesus Christ our Lord.
For the joy of the Lord is our strength today.
And we will rejoice and we will be glad in it.
Thank you, Lord, for another Sunday where we can praise you
, guide the meeting, direct the meeting
and most of all
fill this building with your presence and touch every single heart, Lord.
Please.
I plead with you
touch every heart and give a blessing to everyone present in Jesus' name.
I'm so glad that's mine.
Oh, the joy that birds are so that's baby all Nothing's better.
I think that's the dog.
Just no Nothing's better.
There is no one that's for me.
There's something better.
Oh the joy that loves my soul.
Jesus loves me all He did mind Jesus you are all bees in no Justin know nothing's better
Oh I tried to do in my own way
and nothing's ever changed Then he came his saving grace
and took my sins away The joy
and peace he's given me I'll have you just say there's nothing better
There's nothing better There's nothing better.
Because of who you are
I give you praise Because of who you are I will live my foolish
and say Lord I worship you
because of who you are Lord I worship you
because of who you are
because of who you are I give you glory
because of who you are I give you praise
Because of who you are I will lift my voice
and say Lord I worship you
because of who you are Lord I worship you
because of who you are Jehovah e seignehobash my prince of peace
and I worship you because of whom you are
because of who you are I give you glory
because of who you are I give you praise
because of who you are I will lift my voice
and say Lord I worship you
because of who you are I worship you
because of who you are easy to me
and I will wish you
because you're seeing my seat it's a great
so I praise I cause of who you are
because of who you are I believe you
because of who you are I give you praise
because of who you are I will give my voice for I worship you
because of who you are worship you
because I'm gonna be able to get the Jesus my scroll with me all
I have Jesus it is you my Jesus it is you so I
my soul yes
Who sees my brokenness and carries me
when I feel and we're Jesus beat you
and who tells the storm to rest?
I am overwhelmed and cannot speak.
Yes, Jesus it is youars my guilt on his shoulder
and who holds my heart in his head
and who takes my thoughts
and hangs them on the arms Jesus Is you
Yes, my Jesus
It's always you know Jesus.
See it out like it's your prayer.
Oh I lift my body all my days I give you all of my rights
and all of my to the two it's only the offering.
We don't take it physically, but oh
do we need for you to give today?
We're working out, by the way
we're not only gonna bless one prison in Louisiana,
Angola, with a a gift bag for Christmas,
with uh deodorant toothbrush, toothpaste, or soap, a pair of socks.
We're not only gonna bless that one
we might bless another prison that has what, fourteen hundred inmates?
Eighteen hundred inmates.
So we're trying to take monies that we God blesses us with to bless others and go out.
Plus pay the bills, plus make repairs.
Lord, I forgot to mention the offering
but you know what we need.
Please, Jesus, remind the people to give.
Those who can give special offerings
so those who are not giving systematically
would you convict them
and encourage them to share their substance with the work of the Lord
since you gave us everything that we have?
Bless this offering as the people leave or as they give online.
In Jesus' name.
Amen.
When Jesus died two thousand years ago
and then rose from the dead
he sent his disciples out with a message to share the good news.
What good news?
Gospel means good news.
The good news that God loves us
even though we've sinned
that there are things that are wrong called sin according to God
which are found in his word.
And we've all sinned.
And goes tell them that even though they've sinned
God has made a way to be brought close back to God in fellowship
through the death of his son.
He removes that guilt and that barrier through what he did on the cross, rose again
so now we can share fellowship with the Lord
and be part of his family.
That was the good news.
And go to heaven when life is over.
And that was part of the message.
Uh this life passes away
but eternity is coming.
And everyone's gonna spend by the way
everyone here looking at me
you're all gonna spend eternity somewhere.
A billion years from now?
Time will be no more
but let's use time.
A billion years from now
we're all gonna be somewhere.
Permanently with the Lord or away.
Well, when they went out and started to preach
they had almost exclusively a Jewish audience because they started in Jerusalem.
All the d all the apostles were Jewish, Jesus was Jewish.
So they preached to the Jewish people.
And in fact, the Roman Empire thought at first that Christianity was an offshoot,
some little sect of Judaism.
Uh so because they adhered to the Old Testament scripture
but we're now adding the message of Messiah has come.
So as they went around and preached that
everything was either rejection or acceptance
and the early church was made up of all Jewish people
and then Gentiles started started to come in.
But then the Apostle Paul
and others started to go on missionary trips me.
And the first one of the first missionary trips he took, in fact, his second one
he ended up going to what we call Turkey, they called Asia.
If I could have a tissue, please, thank you.
And um thanks so much.
And um it went out further than that.
Paul went to Greece.
Now all these places were part of the Roman Empire.
Jerusalem, Israel, Palestine, every place you go, Turkey, called Asia
everything was part of this mammoth empire, the biggest yet to be seen by at that day.
Bigger than the Assyrian Empire, bigger than the Babylonian Empire,
bigger than the Greek Empire under Alexander the Great.
And here was the Roman Empire
which had replaced all of them.
So when they went anywhere
they went to a Greek-speaking world
although someplace they spoke Latin
and they started to spread the gospel.
But now the audience was totally different.
Because now the people are saying, Jesus, who?
What a sin.
How do you say immorality is wrong?
When in the Roman Empire in Rome
the husbands would have their mistress stay in the house with the wife and the children.
To say immorality was wrong, like saying drinking coffee is wrong.
And the Greek thought and the Greek philosophy
and Greek values had permeated the Roman Empire.
So although it was the Roman Empire
it was very um Grecianized
Hellenized is the word.
And what meant in Greek culture
what meant something was education, philosophy, orators.
Some of the biggest names in the Roman Empire were orators, a few poets, but especially orators.
And if you could speak in front of the Senate
or if you could draw a crowd
and use ornate language and use your orat uh your your ability to speak to dazzle the crowd
you were a great person.
Athletes.
Athletes were great.
Because the Greek Olympic Games that they started
that was being done in the Roman Empire.
Wealth.
If you had a lot of money
you were like in our culture
you were considered special.
Why?
Because he made a lot of money.
But what if he's uh uh a horrible person?
It doesn't matter
he made a lot of money
so he's great.
Or he's on TV
or she's on in the movies.
So now when the gospel came to that audience
it was a whole different story.
The Jews were arguing either he is the Messiah that was promised in the Old Testament
or he's not the Messiah.
If he is the Messiah
I'll put my trust in him
and I'll become a Christian.
The Apostle Paul was one of the biggest persecutors of the early church.
He started out as a man called Saul of Tarsus
and he persecuted the church
had people thrown in prison, divided families
possibly had deaths uh connected to his name.
But then the Lord appeared to him
and he became a fervent Christian and spokesperson.
And he's the one who went into these Roman Empire places
and he was speaking to people who were idolaters.
That the Greek um the Greek religion brought into the Roman Empire like 10,000 gods.
They had 10,000 gods, they worshiped trees, they worshiped mountains
and they had their whole hierarchy of of idols and gods.
So when you started to talk about one God who sent his son into the world, they were going
Are you kidding me?
Is this a joke?
So the Jewish audience they stumbled at the fact
that the the preachers were saying
You missed the Messiah
he came and you you missed him.
He was there in front of you
and you didn't know it.
But to the Greek audience in the Roman Empire
it was a matter of ridicule.
Wait a minute, you gotta be kidding, right?
So you're telling me that the God
the true and only one God
sent his son who died on a cross.
He let soldiers crucify him.
And he bled, and they put a crown of thorns.
And you're saying that's the half naked on a cross
that's the God you worship?
Come on.
I mean, be real.
And the preachers who went out
the Roman Empire laughed at that.
They were used to orators.
What are you talking about?
This guy was a fisherman.
The people who got saved
the the church was overwhelmingly the new converts were slaves
which made up the great bulk of the population
but they were uh they were at the low part of the totem pole.
Slaves.
You got a bunch of slaves.
You don't even have buildings.
You don't meet in buildings
you're meeting in homes with a bunch of common people.
Where's the big names?
Where's the people with money?
Where's the philosophers?
I heard this guy, Saul of Tarsus, Paul the apostle, preached.
He ain't nothing.
He's not an orator.
We have real, we have the real thing.
We have philosophy.
We have wisdom.
Greek uh appreciation of wisdom.
Um got into that Roman Empire, and they just, oh
he's a philosopher
he's so wise.
What a communicator.
You know the story about that old Greek speaker named
I think it was Herodotus
who learned to speak perfectly by putting pebbles
gravel into his mouth
and he would practice for hours every day with pebbles in his mouth.
So that when you took the pebbles out
you can uh he could speak even more clearly
had control of his tongue.
By the way, I learned that from a guy who used to come to our church
who was a radio DJ.
This is many years ago
and he told me
before you do a taping or something
take a pencil and uh
and put it in your mouth, Pastor Simba, and you know, there, and talk.
Do do Psalm 23, or just talk, with the pencil in your mouth.
Because the tongue is fighting against the pencil, right?
To get out, the Lord is my shepherd
I shall not want, right?
With the pencil there.
And when you take the pencil out
your your tongue isn't like heavy
it isn't like sluggish
it's more alert.
I have no idea why I'm telling you this story.
It has nothing to do with anything I'm talking about.
I go down rabbit trails sometimes.
So, anyway, so that was the that was the problem when they spread the gospel,
like today in our culture.
Come on.
You're you know
you're you're saying like uh Jesus is all I need.
So you're talking about an invisible person who you've never seen
he's all you need.
You don't need money
you don't need a house.
Come on, be real, would you please?
That's our culture, right?
We're talking about things why, Pastor
I've had people say this.
I visited your church.
The lady next to me was lifting her hands.
You didn't tell anyone to lift their hands.
Why was she lifting her hands?
I don't get that.
And I saw, look, she was crying
but she wasn't sad.
She was happy, but she was crying.
What's going on in there?
How many understand what I'm talking about?
It's like Greek to them.
It's like, what are you talking about?
And this religion, yeah.
Oh, so he's gonna come back again and what?
We're all gonna go to heaven one day and all of that.
Come on, be real, would you please?
The only thing that exists is what you can investigate.
The scientific method controls reality.
If you can see it
test it with a microscope, even, or whatever
that's what's real.
Don't talk about another world that nobody can see.
That's a joke.
That's how you control people, pie in the sky and the by
and by and all of that.
So that's what the early church met with when they went out.
And Paul went to a city in southern Greece in a place called Achaea
and there he went to a city called Corinth and he preached there
he stayed 18 months there
and he founded a church
and then there's two letters that he wrote back to that church
because of problems that have arisen.
So one of the uh things that was uh uh accusations against him and the and the Christians
which the church was dealing with, was hey, hey, dude
it's a joke.
What you're talking about is a joke.
There's no where's the the the great speakers?
Where's the money?
Where's the the pomp and ceremony?
Where's the PhDs?
We're looking for PhDs here
we're not looking for fishermen and slaves.
What kind of low life religion is that?
That's what they face
which we still face today.
So Paul is telling them look
when I was with you and I preached
I had a wisdom.
They're making fun of you
but don't you get it?
The wisdom of this world is a joke to God.
What people call wise and great
God looks at it and goes
You totally missed it.
And the wisdom that we give is the true wisdom
but they don't get it.
In other words, Christians aren't unwise.
Christians are the only wise people on the face of the earth, according to God.
So he picks up this um line of thought
and he says this we do ever we do,
however, speak a message of wisdom among the mature, i.e. the spiritual,
but not the wisdom of this age and hold this up there, please, Joy
or of the rulers of this age who are coming to nothing.
Do we not need to just ponder that for a second?
He said, We have a wisdom
but it's not the wisdom of this age
because this age is passing away.
We speak another wisdom, which he says, not of this age
or of the rulers who are coming to nothing.
All the big names and all the big politicians
and all the rulers and all the palaces
and all the UN and all the billionaires
and everyone who quote made it
they're coming to nothing.
In the end, they will be nothing.
Because when God returns and opens the books
they're going to find out they're the biggest losers
and they were living in an illusory world.
Oh, they thought that the Christians were living in an illusory, make-believe world.
They're going to find out they were living their whole life for stuff that doesn't matter.
And the minute they died, they lost everything.
But we Christians, when we die
we're going home.
How many of you are planning to go home?
We're going to go home.
So do you get the tension here?
The wisdom of this world and of the rulers.
And he adds, hey
they're coming to nothing.
I know, but she's the biggest movie star.
Everyone wants to be like her.
She's an influencer.
You people talk, they follow influencers.
Why don't you let God and the Bible influence you?
Can we put our hands together and say amen to that?
Rather than some influencer who doesn't even know what life is about.
And that's sad.
People, even Christians who go to churches
are following people who are coming to nothing.
You got it?
They're coming to nothing.
Not me, I didn't say that.
God's word says it.
So then.
No, we declare God's wisdom.
A mystery.
Who's the mystery?
Jesus.
That has been hidden and
that God destined for our glory for time began.
So now he's saying Christians have a wisdom.
But it's a wisdom that's a mystery.
You don't see it on the surface.
It's not in the scientific method world.
In that mystery is Christ, salvation, God's love, redemption.
Heaven.
Becoming a born-again person.
That's a wisdom.
He said, that's the true wisdom.
That's the only wisdom that matters.
Brothers and sisters, never be intimidated by people who seem intellectual.
They ain't all that.
Trust me, they ain't all that.
In fact, some of the brightest people
it's just amazing how warped their lives are
and how they don't have a.
I was who is that?
The the was a Supreme Court Justice
or someone recently was coming in as the Secretary of Health and whatever.
And one of the questions they were asked is
could you define a woman?
They couldn't define what a woman
but they're really smart.
PhD.
They're gonna help rule our country.
They can't say what a woman like a man, like a woman,
because of all the other stuff, right?
So thinking they're wise, they become foolish.
So he goes on and says none of the rulers of this age understood it
, that wisdom, Jesus.
For if they had
they would not have crucified the Lord of glory.
All these bright people in the Jewish religion with their high IQs and their religious training.
And you can add the Gentile were with all their learning
and their Greek philosophy and their letters
and arts and all that they know.
They're not, they didn't even have a clue.
When God's own Son came
he was right in front of them.
They didn't even get it.
So how smart could you be?
God Himself was standing in front of you
the creator of the universe
and you didn't pick it up
but you're really bright.
You're really smart.
So Paul now is encouraging the believers here
that there's a secret wisdom
a spiritual wisdom that's that no one got it,
no one in the world without the help of the Holy Spirit can get it.
And this is the import that I want to leave you with you of this passage.
He said they didn't get it.
Had they really had any real wisdom
they would have known this is God.
Or how about this one?
I'm gonna die one day.
Wouldn't you think it'd be wise for me to prepare to die?
No, no, I'm gonna act like I live forever.
There's some now billionaire guy who says he's getting treatments now
and living in a cocoon of somehow
and he's guaranteed he's gonna live 180 years.
No, I just read about him.
He looks weird, by the way.
Very strange looking guy.
And he's gonna live 180 years.
So what if he does?
So then you die.
So then what?
No, I don't want to think about that.
Well, how intelligent is that?
How smart is it to make believe you're never gonna die?
But that's commonplace among the intelligentsia.
Don't bring up death or taxes, don't talk about those two things.
So now Paul finishes his thought by saying this.
However, and now he's quoting from Isaiah 64, verse 4 However
as it is written
what no eye has seen
what no ear has heard
and what no human mind has ever conceived
the things God has prepared for those who love him.
These are the things God has revealed to us by his spirit.
The Spirit searches all things, even the deep things of God.
Oh, go back.
Verse 9.
Go back.
However, as it is written from the Old Testament
what no eye has seen
no scientific method can touch it.
Are you really educated today?
You won't get a clue by using your brain.
You can go to the library and study
you'll never get it.
You can be very rich
You can be very poor
you'll never get it.
No eye has seen
no ear has heard.
What no human mind has ever conceived
the things of God are not privy to the human mind.
Unassisted.
But the things that God has prepared
uh when I was a kid
I thought that always meant God has prepared for those who love him,
meaning heaven and the things of heaven.
But that's not what it means.
Listen, go on.
These are the things God has revealed to us by his spirit.
The spirit, a very mysterious verse.
The spirit searches all things, even the deep things of God.
Everything pertaining to God that will change your life and my life,
not just salvation, but growth in God, being used by God.
It can only be revealed by the Holy Spirit.
There is, that's called revelation, revealed to the inner person by the Holy Spirit.
It's called revelation, revealed by the Holy Spirit.
Who's the Holy Spirit?
He, not it, he is the one who Jesus sent
after he accomplished his mission and went back to heaven.
He said, I'm sending you another helper to replace me.
He'll be more effective than me in certain ways.
I'm limited to one body
he'll be everywhere.
I've been alongside you
he'll live inside of you.
I taught you things
but you didn't get it.
Just to the very end
you were arguing who was the greatest.
But he's going to transform you from the inside out.
Without the Holy Spirit
there's no conviction of sin.
Every one of these new members who said they're a believer
they're only a believer
because of the ministry of the