Praise the Lord.
Are you ready to worship God?
Amen.
Open your heart right now.
God is looking so good.
He is so worthy of our praise.
Come on, let's lift our voices with all of our heart
earn all of our soul, amen.
Let's sing with me.
Every praise is to our God.
Every word of worship with one of the core.
Every praise.
Every praise is to our God.
Every grave is to our God.
Every word of worship is one of our four.
Every praise.
We want our boat.
Every brave.
Every race is to our God.
Sting high to hallelujah.
To our God.
Holy Hallelujah.
It's to our God.
Every place.
Every place is to our God.
Oh, every place.
Every way is to our God.
Every word of worship is one of the words.
Every place.
Every way is to our God.
Sit with me.
We can do all the places after you do it.
You will wake me, Jesus.
Give the heavy praise today.
We praise God.
We worship Jesus.
We worship today God.
We are hoping God for you today.
Come on, give him a shout of praise today.
We bless you, Lord.
We bless you, Jesus.
Hallelujah.
We worship you today, God.
It's the brain.
Oh day.
You are in high foreign.
If you give forgiveness
if you make peace, sing a song.
Hallelujah.
Thank you, Jesus.
If you are free.
And the angels come.
Your day.
Your day is the grace.
All powers and positions.
Your day sends above the world.
Say the love.
It's the brains
your name stands above the world.
Oh ghosts and the women.
Oh powers and the teachings.
Your name stays above the world.
He's a great day.
She goes to me.
To worship the Almighty God.
We open our hearts before God.
We pour our hearts.
Just feel good with thanksgiving for what God has done.
And if you're not
it's so easy to gravitate back towards just looking at what's wrong
what's not right in a broken world
where there's bound to be things wrong.
The more you understand who God is
the more you understand who we are and what we deserve.
What we were supposed to get because of our rebellion, because of our sin.
Because of turning from a holy God.
When the more you understand that
and you stop just thinking about just the world
and stuff and ambitions and things
but when you understand the eternal implications of we are a spirit.
And we were going to be separated from God.
And no, if you've ever felt any lack of fulfillment on this earth,
any sadness, any depression, emptiness.
Imagine an eternity of that.
An eternity, a complete absence of anything that would speak of the presence of God.
Gone, gone.
That's what we were headed for.
And God of Mercy, how he intervened.
How he intervened.
How he intervened because of his great love for us.
Amen.
And the more you get an understanding of who this great and this holy God is
and what we deserved
but what we've been given instead.
And the more you understand your word, the Bible
and you understand all the promises that are found in Christ Jesus
everything that has been awarded to us
because of the gospel and what Jesus did on that cross.
Everything that's been given to us
because He's given us His Spirit.
When you start to understand that more and more
then like we were saying at the end of the 9 o'clock
turn your eyes upon Jesus.
Look full into his wonderful things.
And the things of this earth
which there might be some good things here
and there that can get you excited
but then it comes all over again.
The depressing things, the broken things
the things that fail you
the things that are insecure
that that that betray you, whatever.
Your eyes, that that doesn't it's not greater than who Jesus is.
And that's why we have to keep our eyes fixed on him.
And as we do that
our hearts begin to overflow with thanks
and praise because we realize everything that we have in him.
The minute we look away
then we mumble and we grumble
because this life is not what it was meant to be.
But fix your eyes back on him
and everything your soul hungers for
everything it longs for, it satisfies him.
He answers it all and he gives abundantly until overflowing.
And that's why when we sing this song, we can sing.
And now let the weak say I am strong.
Let the poor say I am rich.
Not because of what we've done.
We can't take any pride in it.
We can't boast in it.
Because of what Jesus has done.
Look at all I have.
Look what the Lord has done.
Amen.
I lack nothing today.
You lack nothing today if Jesus is your Savior.
So let's sing that with thankful hearts today.
Let's be filled with thanks.
We'll leave our problems on the side.
God will be faithful to take care of those things.
But recount the goodness of God.
Remember your salvation today.
Remember that your sin has been cleansed and washed away.
He remembers it no more.
He doesn't hold it against you today.
You are his child.
You are his son.
You are his daughter today.
Rest in that today and rejoice.
Amen.
Let's give thanks to the Lord today.
Hallelujah.
We thank you, Jesus.
Every blessing, God, every promise
all that you've done, Lord
we give you thanks, God.
Let's sing it together.
Because you give us Jesus Christ with the wake of God in place to grace
because he also we thank Jesus.
Let's sing it again.
In place with the great heart in place to the world in place
because he's given Jesus Christ in place with the great God to the holy one.
We thank you, Jesus.
Thank you for every blessing, God.
Every mercy, Lord.
All of your faithfulness, God.
We say thank you.
Make us a thankful people, Lord.
That thanksgiving would pour out of us, Lord
every day because you have not changed.
You are the same yesterday, today, and forever, God.
You will not fail us.
You have been good, Lord.
We say thank you
and we love you in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Good afternoon, Brooklyn Tabernacle.
The word of the Lord says to let everything that has breath praise the Lord.
So today that's exactly what we intend to do
to give the Lord praise
and glory as we sing in this church.
Praise him.
Praise him in the sanctuary.
Praise him with the timber of.
Your face from this, your grace always.
I've got so much to thank God for so many wonderful blessings,
and so many breath each new day.
That's why I praise you
and for this I give you the prayer for me.
For you alone are worthy, God, of our praise.
We bless your name, Jesus
for every day that we just didn't feel like we could take another breath, God.
You were the breath in our lungs.
For every time we felt like we couldn't take a step, God
you walked with us and you held our hands, God.
Thank you, Jesus, for our children.
Thank you, Jesus, for our families.
Thank you, Jesus.
Thank you, God, for our jobs.
Thank you for providing for us, God.
Thank you, Jesus, for this building
that we get to gather and bless your name, and God.
Thank you, Holy Spirit
for being a comforter like we've never known.
Thank you, Jesus.
We bless you, Jesus.
For you, I'm not sure.
Everyone, open your mouth, use your voice, give them thanksgiving
give them a hallelujah.
Give them gracias, Senor, por todo, Senor.
We praise you, we adore you, we love you
we exalt your name, we extol you, Lord, we praise you.
You are everything, Lord.
And it's nine weeks of meeting once a week.
And these people have completed it.
Nine weeks meeting once a week.
So Jesus Rosa is one of the graduates.
And he's gonna come now.
Come on, Jesus.
And he's gonna read He's gonna read what What meant the most to him.
Come on, right over here, my friend.
Okay.
He's gonna read to us um what meant the most to him
in this uh program called Be Transformed.
Okay.
The lesson was what lesson changed or impacted you the most?
Lesson seven.
Expectations, anger, and bitterness has had the most significant impact on me.
It revealed the deep roots of unsolved unresolved anger that controlled me for years.
Growing up, bad things happened to me when I was a child.
I was confused and always felt
that I needed to be more masculine.
So there was no question about how was perceived how I was perceived as a male.
I didn't realize how much conflict changed my emotions and choices.
When I was eight years old
I was introduced to the boxing gym.
My father, who was my boxing coach
uh remained a heroin addict throughout my young years.
But stayed present and active as a good father.
From the age of nine through my teens
I won numerous uh tournaments, state championships.
Eventually, as his addiction progressed
my father made the bold step of going away with a long treatment over.
By the time he completed
I had started I had stopped boxing
and started getting in trouble in the streets and the rocks.
My father fought hard to recover from addiction.
But after nearly eight years of cleaning
he died from AIDS and complications.
I was unable to grasp.
I was taken so soon.
The pain turned inward Leading me towards self-destruction.
The anger was inward.
My anger led me into addiction
landing me in and out of the jails and the treatment programs.
I felt abandoned by God and consumed by resentment.
This this lesson helped me.
See, bitterness was another prison.
Keeping me from the peace Christ wanted for me.
Through scripture and reflective and reflections in lesson seven
I realized that holding on to anger only tightened my chains.
Forgiveness towards others and myself was a key to freedom.
I surrendered my pain to Jesus.
He began to heal the wounds beneath my anger.
I learned his grace that runs deeper than mine, without guilt or shame.
Today I've been clean for several many years
and served as a credential, alcohol, and substance use counselor
in the jails of the correctional health system.
Working with people who remind me of my past by God's grace.
Wow.
To expand my ability to serve those struggling with addiction and brokenness.
Though I still wrestle with anger
I no longer face it alone.
Jesus is freeing me layer by layer.
Replacing bitterness with compassion and peace.
I'm learning that what once destroyed me has become my testimony.
A reminder that God can turn even the most broken heart into hope.
Wait, wait, is it the offerings for those watching online?
Um the offerings that you send in, give online.
It helps everything going
things we're trying to do.
You know, project that we have now.
So we're not yet through with the numbers exactly.
But my wife is leading the way
encouraging me to do it.
You know, we met these Roma people from Slovakia.
Pastor Petri was over there on a fact-finding mission
and he he found out that in this poor, poor, poor, poor town
thousands of Roma people called gypsies in uh in a not a nice way.
Um God is saving them
and and they got this beautiful church but they've outgrown it
and my wife and I myself
we've been thinking
wouldn't it be nice if God helped us to build the biggest Christian Roma church in all of Europe
because th they're discriminating against wherever they go
they don't get hired for jobs.
Many times they won't let their kids go to school.
So, what would you do if you can't work
and your kids can't go to school?
You're gonna get in trouble.
So uh whatever we're facing
uh God supplies money through people giving large amounts, small amounts, regular amounts.
There's uh baskets as you leave today
where you can uh put your offering in.
But uh I just want you to know we really need your giving, your support.
So I heard this song years ago.
Bill Gaither actually called me
he's uh well-known person uh in the Southern Gospel.
He wrote a lot of songs we sang.
He said, Jim, have you heard this new song called Sometimes It Takes a Mountain
to get a hold of me to train train me to to believe to get my attention.
The thought of the song is sometimes God permits mountains to come in our way
or deserts so that we go, Oh no
I can't do this.
Oh God, God help us Just like uh Tiranda was praying.
So um that song really uh has been a blessing.
Choir used to sing it
maybe they'll come back with it.
But today we have uh a duet.
Not Peaches and Herb.
We got something better than that.
We have a visitor who uh just the brother has stood out to me
and I've prayed for him.
I don't even know him that well.
I only met him today right in person uh first time
and his name is Wesley
and he's a pastor
he's a singer.
He's a bass player
he can play the drums.
He's everywhere in gospel music, Wesley Pritchard.
And uh he's visiting with us here today with his wife Teresa
and uh he and Tiranda told me they have a version of uh sometimes it takes about Come on
let's give a loud welcome.
Wesley Pritchard!
I faced a mountain that I never faced before.
That's why I'm calling on you, Lord.
I know it's been a while, but Lord
please hear my prayer I need you like I never have before.
Sometimes it takes a mountain sometimes a trouble seas.
Sometimes it takes a deser to get a hold of me.
But you love it so much stronger.
Then what happens?
Sometimes it takes mountain to trust you and believe.
I thought I could control whatever life would throw my way
but it's thou will in me has brought me to my knees.
I need you, Lord
and I'm not a deep sometimes.
Amen.
Is that a great song?
It's so true to life, right?
Thank you, my brother.
Love you.
Um I want to talk to you briefly today
about taking a little different attack than I did this morning.
I want to talk to you about the mountains that you have to get over in life.
And one of the problems with Christians is
we get surprised by things that uh God told us are gonna happen.
And then we panic and we go
what's going on?
And the Apostle Paul especially in the end of one of his letters
the last letter he ever wrote
they're not sequential like in the New Testament.
The last thing Paul wrote is Second Timothy
a letter to a minister uh who was a convert under Paul.
And Paul says those famous words, okay
the Holy Spirit has showed me
my time is drawing to an end
I'm being poured out like an offering
and I'm gonna go home now to be with the Lord.
Isn't that something the Holy Spirit can show you sometimes before you die?
That's happened many times.
He's indicated the people
when they're going to be um uh leaving.
So uh he says to summarize his life to Timothy, he said
but I have fought a good fight
I finished the race
and I've kept the faith.
Let's think of that
because we all should be thinking about that.
I have fought a good fight.
What is Christianity?
Like our brother Jesus was saying, he boxed.
Christianity is partly a fight, not with people, with demons and powers and principalities
and the world and the flesh and the devil and everything.
You gotta fight.
You cannot be passive if you're a Christian.
You have to be ready to fight.
Did you turn the microphone off again on me, brother?
Because I'm not getting any response.
Is how many have found you're Christians?
How many have found it's a fight?
It's a fight.
So you gotta fight back.
So it's also a race, but he says
I finished the race.
A lot of people start a marathon
they don't finish.
I read about a guy from the New York City Marathon a couple weeks ago.
They start, you know, on the bridge in Staten Island.
He just made it over the bridge and then he dropped out.
He's supposed to run through all five boroughs.
He just said, No
I've had enough.
Let me get something to eat out here.
And um, so it's not who starts
it's who finishes.
So that's for all of us.
How many want to finish in the name of the Lord?
Right to the end.
And kept the faith
and that means Paul is not talking about faith
like trust in God
it's the faith, the Bible, the teaching, the doctrines,
Christ, the Holy Spirit, the second coming, the cross, and all of that.
He said, I didn't go off to some new teaching
down some rabbit hole that leads to nowhere.
So now he's signing off.
He loves Timothy, probably maybe was closer to Timothy than anyone.
It was his spiritual son.
And now he tells them what happened to him on the road on this trip, on this fight
on this journey that we're all on.
And under the inspiration of the Holy Spirit
although he's signing off the last letter he's writing
he says things that have so grabbed my attention over and over again.
Why would God have Paul say these things
if it wasn't for an encouragement to us that this is what happens sometimes?
Don't go south, don't get shaky.
He's saying, This happened to me.
I was God's greatest Christian we know of, God's apostle
and he's saying to Timothy as he signs off
but it's in a very casual way.
So look up here, he says
Do your best to come to me quickly.
For Demas, because he loved this world
has deserted me and has gone to Thessalonica.
He might have lived there.
Crescent has gone to Galatia
that was probably sent by Paul for ministry, and Tinas, Titus went to Dalmatia.
But it's up there at the very beginning.
Do your best to come to me quickly, for Demas has
because he loved this world, has deserted me.
Left me high and dry.
Now, this was no just ordinary Christian.
This guy, Demas, is mentioned twice in other places in the New Testament.
He was one of the ministerial team that Paul traveled with.
This guy traveled with Paul
saw what God can do, founded churches
and then he fell in love with the world.
By the way, that's a reminder for all of us.
How could you travel like that
and see Paul and love Jesus
and then get another boyfriend
and cheat on your your husband, Christ?
He did it.
The world has a pull.
Am I correct?
And it's a pull away away from Christ.
So this was a blow.
This was a blow.
Come come on to me quick because demons has forsaken me.
Now the Bible says if you love this world
if you want to date the world
and fit in with the world and be worldly and carnal, you know
just the nonsense that's in our culture.
You can't be uh loving God.
God and the world are opposites.
The world, when Jesus came, crucified Jesus.
So the Bible says, Don't love the things, don't love the world
neither the things in the world
which is made up of the lust of the eye
I want what I see, the lust of the flesh, other desires, and the pride of life
walking around shudding like you're somebody.
That's the world in summary.
And that's what happened to Demas.
And it hurt Paul.
So here's the first thing we want you to know.
If you serve the Lord and walk with him
you're gonna have people desert you
leave you high and dry, hurt you
stab you in the back sometimes
but not everyone who starts out with you is gonna keep going with you.
So don't go
what just I can't believe.
Listen, it happened to Jesus.
Did people turn on him?
Did they desert him?
It happened to David in the Old Testament
it happened to Moses in the Old Testament
and now Paul's telling us
while I was serving God
and he was one of my fellow ministers
he's out of, he's gone.
But notice it didn't shake Paul.
Paul just took it as this is what happens, it's unfortunate.
You cry sometimes, but you can't let it rock your boat.
You gotta get your foundation in Jesus, not in some man or woman.
As much as we love them
you're you gotta have foundation in Christ.
So I'm saying all of this is because when things go sideways
and they always do
you can't be shaken by it.
When I was younger
I just I didn't realize how immature that was.
That because something goes wrong with this minister
or this Christian or that, people go, Where's God?
Where is God?
Wake up.
This is what happens when you're a Christian.
You got people deserting you sometimes.
Do we want that?
No.
Does it happen?
Yes.
How many have ever been hurt, deserted
abandoned by anybody in your life?
Just hold your hand up.
Then we know.
My lovely wife and I started a long time ago on this little building on Atlantic Avenue in uh
with three or four, sometimes in the midweek service, 1520 on a good Sunday.
That's when we started.
And then the church began to grow
and we had um a Filipino couple come to the church and um very sweet.
And uh she was a prayer warrior and uh spiritual rock
if you know what I mean.
He was gifted too, he exhorted
and he led praise and worship and uh he would lead
and then I would come up and preach after that.
And they were with us for a couple of years in that little building
then we went to the YWCA on Atlantic and Third.
We held meetings there for two years
he was there with us
and then we moved into a building on Flappish Avenue, 290 Flappish Avenue, near Seventh Avenue
and he was there.
And I loved him
and we traveled together.
And one uh Tuesday or yeah, one weekday in my office over there
we had some leaders, the staff people
and I asked him to pray to close the meeting.
And he couldn't pray.
He hemmed, he hawed
he started to cry, he stuttered.
And I knew something was wrong
but I didn't have the maturity
the discernment and I just, you know, let it go.
But I should have done otherwise.
Well, about some months later
we were going on our one of our first vacations.
You remember that, Carol?
We went to Jamaica and uh we were in Jamaica a few days
and I get a call from a a friend who had preached at the Tuesday night prayer meeting
and he said to me, Uh, Jim
you better get on a plane and come back.
I said, Wait, I just got here a few days ago.
He said, No, no, no, no.
Your associate just took off with a woman in the church leaving two children behind
and a husband who was ready to just go crazy.
And along with that
he emptied the bank account of all the money
because he had access to deposit slips
and he knew all of that.
He was working, we trusted him.
Oh, I remember, I remember in that hotel room hearing that and going, What?
And then his his his wife, Filipino wife
she was heartbroken and angry and two children, and but listen
I couldn't hide it.
You know, love covers a multitude of sins.
I couldn't hide this
because you don't want to shame anyone.
He he led the worship, everyone knew him.
He was the face of the the services.
So I remember that first Sunday after we had prayed, got counsel
I had to go up there
and someone else led praise and worship
and then I got up
and I knew I had to cover it before I started to preach
or I I wouldn't get through.
And uh I said, ladies and gentlemen
I have sad news
and I explained it the best I could.
While I was speaking
I'll never forget
I was emotional myself
but as I was speaking
people were yelling up out at me.
No, don't say that, no
don't say that.
It turned into just crazy
and uh a long day
that was a long Sunday and ministered.
So worse, he left me a personal letter which said, Dear Pastor Simba
I would imagine at this point you're upset with me.
But I want you to know that she
and I are very happy in Jesus
and God directed us to do what we did.
You see how Satan could deceive any of us?
And uh I never saw him again.
He just died, I think I f
I heard about a year ago, out in California.
And his wife, we have stayed in touch with her and tried to help her.
But that was a blow
because in was I out of God's will?
Was I doing anything wrong?
No.
But these are the disappointments in life.
But you can't let it shake you.
You gotta wipe away the tears and you gotta say
I have decided to follow Jesus.
Can we put our hands together?
We're gonna follow Jesus.
So very quickly, that's gonna happen to you.
If it hasn't happened yet, it will happen.
It could happen many times.
There's disappointments in the Christian life.
Doesn't mean we're not right with God
doesn't mean we've done anything wrong.
Paul didn't do anything wrong
and Demas still forsook him.
But then Paul says an interesting one sentence.
He says this to Timothy Only Luke is with me.
You know who Luke is.
He was a Gentile doctor, physician
and he got converted probably on Paul's second missionary trip
and then went with him to Greece, and then went on the third missionary journey.
And there's not a sentence that I know of that quotes Luke in the entire Bible.
There's no sentence from Luke.
And yet he wrote two books of the Bible.
He wrote the Gospel of Luke, right?
Matthew, Mark, Luke, and he wrote the book of Acts.
And he attacked it like a scientist would.
He went back to the sources, he got witnesses, eyewitnesses.
He wanted to give the report of what really happened in the life of Jesus
and then in the life of the early church.
And that Luke was like this with Paul, just joined at the hip.
I'd like to suggest to you that on Thanksgiving week,
just think, don't thank God for a job
and uh whatever other blessings the Lord gives us.
The more longer you walk with God
you begin to thank God for friends that God has sent into your life.
Listen, wait, wait.
Spiritual pillars that when you're shaky, they're like, don't worry, come on, Jim
we can make this.
Right?
They're solid.
I hope you have some.
Do you have a prayer partner?
Do you have someone you can call?
I know some of you are so isolated.
I don't want my business out in the street.
I got all that.
But you can just save that, really save that.
Because you need to have someone you can call, pray with, talk.
Spouses are great, but we need other friends and support systems spiritually.
Paul said, Luke, my friend, is with me.
Luke was going to be there.
Didn't matter how pressured Paul got
whatever trouble he got into
Luke's going to be there.
I want to say this to all of you.
If you're here today
and I'm not being melodramatic
I'm saying the truth
at the end of this service
you come down here for prayer.
If you are a woman and you need a friend
you don't have a friend.
You don't have a spiritual friend.
Because remember, if you don't develop friends in the body of Christ
Satan will send other friends to you.
How many have found that out?
And they will drag you down
they'll poison your mind, they'll gossip
they'll do whatever, right?
So you come down here, ladies
and uh uh Teresa Robert
you have a pen
all some deacons have a pen and pencil
and uh we'll take your name
and a deaconess will call you twice this week, between now and next Sunday.
And then she's gonna refer you to another lady
in the church about your age who will be your friend.
Hello, I said we'll be your friend.
You can call her
she'll call you.
You can tell her problems without her blabbing, and and same thing with you guys.
Is I meet this is a strange thing about this city.
I don't know if it's something
because you know people get hurt and all that
like Brother Jesus was saying.
Uh, but people just hold everyone at a distance.
They don't let anybody in.
No, no, no.
I know you.
Yo, what's up?
How you doing?
God is good all the time and all that.
But really be open?
No, listen.
Be open, pray, encourage one another?
No, no, no.
Nobody comes in.
I hold everyone at a distance.
That is not a good way to live your life.
You need a spiritual Luke.
For you ladies, you need a spiritual Lucy.
Lucy, Luke, something like that.
Amen?
How many believe what I'm saying is true?
Put your hands together and say amen.
A lot of times we counsel with people
we pray with them
and then you find out as the weeks and months go by
everything you're praying for is being worked against by the posse they run with.
They run with bad people spiritually, dragging them down, no interest in Christ.
How are you gonna stay strong if the people around you are pulling you down?
Some of you need a house cleaning on your friends.
The truth.
So, Luke, thank God for Luke.
You know, I was saying this morning
I never knew that this was an anniversary for him.
I love all the pastors I have now
and the pastors I've worked with before.
Some have gone to be with the Lord.
But Pastor Charles Hammond
today is the anniversary which I did not know.
He's been a Luke to me, been such a dear friend.
Wait, wait.
What's the anniversary again?
Today, how many years?
45.
He came in this church 45 years ago on this date.
And you know what he did?
He came in, he was from another church in another part of Brooklyn.
He joined the choir.
He's a big encouragement to my wife.
Sang in a choir.
Then we found out he had a girlfriend
he was gonna bring her.
Everyone wanted to check her out, you know.
Myrna was her name.
And and lovely.
And um, she came, they got married
and we've been working together for 45 years.
Come on, brother.
I want to let's let's reenact this hub here.
Come on, my Luke.
Love you, Peter.
I love you, brother.
Love you.
So you know what he and I are still doing?
We we got a new little thing going, right, brother, on those Monday nights?
Oh, yeah.
Every month or every two months
we gather ministers that we don't know from around New York City.
He helps me find them.
I know of their names.
They know of my name, maybe
but we invite them together six, seven at a time.
We meet them in a restaurant in the city
we treat them to a meal for no purpose except, brothers
tell us how you're doing in your church.
How can we pray?
How can we help?
Is that a good thing?
That's a good thing.
So I thank God for Pastor Hammond.
Do you have some people in your life,
a pastor, a relative, a friend, a spiritual partner?
Thank God for them.
Tell them you love them.
Because when they're gone
you won't be able to tell them you love them.
So let me close.
So we know now it's gonna happen to you.
You're gonna have a demis who lets you down.
So don't get sideways about it.
Just know this is part of life
but Jesus is gonna help me.
You're gonna have a blessing.
Look for those lukes who can strengthen you.
Now, here's one, not so nice.
Alexander the metal worker did me a great deal of harm.
The Lord will repay him for what he's done.
You too, Timothy, should be on your guard against him
because he strongly opposed our message.
Now, Alexander the metal worker
everyone seems to believe it happened while Paul was in Ephesus
where he was the longest period of time, for three years, ministering.
And this Alexander metalwork persecuted him
tried to destroy him.
You will meet people, look at me
you won't probably be a better Christian than the Apostle Paul.
You won't be a better preacher than the Apostle Paul.
But one thing you will have Satan will send in your life people to try to destroy you.
You still want to be a soldier for Jesus?
That's gonna happen.
Jesus, you know, had Herod.
He never said one word to Herod.
Herod was so opposed to Jesus
and the good news that even though he mocked Jesus and called for him
he didn't get one word from Jesus.
Because he was up to no good.
There are people that come in our lives
they are up to no good.
And we're allowed to warn other people about them.
He told Timothy, yo, Timothy, be careful of Alexander.
He tried to do
he did me great harm.
We don't know the details.
Well, wait a minute.
If you're God's servant
and you're full of the Holy Spirit
and you have the Word of God
I heard the televangelist say
you'll never have a problem.
My foot.
How many know that they that live godly lives will suffer persecution, difficulty?
Wave your hand at me so we're on the same page, okay?
So remember that.
Remember that.
Be alert to it.
And uh make sure that you get discernment and you pray
and you don't get into partnership
or into a situation where that person can do you real harm.
I was telling them very quickly this morning about a huge guy, huge, huge.
6'2, 245, 50 when I met him in that little Lannock Avenue building.
And this crazy guy, um
he was in his probably mid-late 20s.
He went down and he put his hands on some woman
in the church whose husband wasn't a believer.
And when she found out what he had done, the husband said
I'm gonna come down there with a gun
and I'll show that guy putting his hands on my wife.
So I called this guy
and I said, Hey
I'm leaving his name out.
Uh, you have a problem.
Yeah, what's my problem?
I said, Here's your problem.
The guy might have a gun
and he's gonna shoot you in the head.
That would be a problem.
How many say amen to that?
So, oh yeah, but let me tell you something else.
I don't like you either.
I said, Okay, that's fine.
So he went.
In fact, tomorrow night in the prayer meeting
I'm gonna come down there
I'm gonna mess you up.
And his biceps were as big as most people's thigh.
No, no joke.
No joke.
So Sammy Ortiz, who's retired NYPD
he was back there
he preceded my wife and I. He was 17, 18 years old
and he was we had a difficult situation.
He was like the usher, security, deacon, treasurer, CFO.
I I don't know what he was
but he just took care of everything.
So we made an agreement.
If he comes in the prayer meeting, you know
pull me out of it.
I don't want him to come in the auditorium with the people.
So sure enough, I'm kneeling in the front row, red carpet, I'm praying
and then Sam taps me
says he's here
he's near the front door.
So I go out into this little gray, painted concrete steps, foyer
and then there was go up a landing
and then if you went up again
you went to the second floor.
So I say to the guy, all right, all right, all right, wait, wait
let's go upstairs and talk.
And then Sam took off to call the police.
So my job was
I figured to stall him.
But he was all up in arms and no
I'm gonna mess you up now.
That's what he kept saying
I'm gonna mess you up.
And he could have messed me up.
He was big.
And I'm just stalling him, but why look for trouble?
Yo, I'm trying to help you.
The man, you touched his wife
he's gonna get a gun.
He's not a Christian
he doesn't come here.
And oh yeah?
Forget about him.
What am I gonna do to you?
He kept going back to me.
I'm gonna mess you up.
Suddenly the doors fly open
and two police officers run in
and come up the landing to where we were
and they yell at him.
They both had billy sticks
and they yell at him
put your hands against the wall.
So he puts his hands against the wall
and he straddles and he's like that
and and and he moved accidentally while they were frisking him or whatever
and his elbow just hit one of the officers a little bit
but the officer didn't like that.
So he took his stick
and I can still hear that sound.
Oh!
Right on the back of the leg, he went whack!
And it hurt me
and I didn't even get hit.
That's how hard it was.
And so they said, okay
after they talked to him
he was just not well.
And so, Pastor, come on downtown
you're gonna press charges
we're gonna lock this guy up.
So um I said
I'm not going downtown
I'm not leaving this prayer meeting
and I don't want him in trouble.
I just want him to not cause trouble in the church.
He's gonna get in real trouble here.
Well, if you're not gonna go downtown
then I can't do anything with him.
So they let him leave and they told him
stay away and all that.
I have the prayer meeting before I gathered everything in my tiny little office, the phone rings.
It's him.
I know what you did to me tonight, but on Sunday
I'm gonna mess you up when I come on Sunday.
No, I'm gonna mess you up.
That was his phrase.
Just mess you up.
So I never saw him again.
I never saw him again.
He never came.
And uh his mother had mental problems.
And uh we move out of that building
we go to the Y for two years.
Now we're in our building on Floppish Avenue
it's the early 80s
10 years after this thing was to happen.
And someone comes to me and says
You know that guy?
He's here.
And he's in the second row
right off the center aisle
and he had gained 40 or 50 pounds.
He was pushing 300
but I don't mean a flabby 300.
And they said to me, I remember
if there's trouble
there's no two or three of us that are gonna remove him.
He's gonna mess us up.
That's that was the operational phrase.
So I went, okay
so let's just trust God.
We prayed, we came out, had the meeting, I was preaching
and the meeting ended.
He didn't move
he just was staring at me.
People prayed, and I said, Well
I gotta do this.
I walked down and I stood in front of the front row, everyone had vacated
and he was just there alone.
And he just was staring at me.
I said, Hey, how you doing?
He put out his hand.
It was like going in the Holland tunnel when I shook his hand.
He's like, Whoa
is that a hand?
So you know what he said to me?
It was so he said, Hey, yo
you know what happened those years ago?
I said, Yeah, I remember.
I'm sorry.
I was off my meds.
They got me on meds now, I'm better.
So there's an example of God that can change anybody.
But notice this when he first encountered us
he was up to no good.
Sometimes you meet people
they're up to no good.
We had a crazy guy years ago in that other building.
He he was he did home improvements
and he was going among the church people and saying
You need a new kitchen?
You need a new this?
Here, put a thousand down
and I'll come and fix it.
He took the thousand
he never visited them again ever.
He had about six or seven like that.
They came to us
so then we had to act on that, right?
Because he was up to no good.
There are evil people in the world.
Do I get a witness here from anybody?
There are people that at their current state
they're up to they want to hurt you.
Social media.
Social media or other things.
Thank you, Jeff, for your play.
So remember that.
You'll be disappointed by a demis
you'll be encouraged by Luke.
You might have somebody that Satan sends to hurt you.
You've got to know about that.
You gotta know about that.
Discern it, God, what do I do?
Give me wisdom how to handle it.
And then the worst moment of Paul's life
it ends this way.
He said, at my first defense when he was held in front of the judge
no one came to my support.
Wait a minute.
You started all those churches
you traveled with all those people
and none of them stood with you
when you were uh on trial?
No, no.
But everyone deserted me.
Notice what he says
may it not be held against them.
Brothers and sisters, let me tell you something as you walk through the Christian life.
Sometimes Christians fail, not because they don't love the Lord
they're just weak.
They get afraid.
Don't you get it?
He was being tried for his life.
And if they're gonna stand with him
and they're married with two children
what happens if the judge says, And you
are you one of those two?
Haul them in a prison.
They couldn't deal with that.
You get it?
That's why he says
May it not be laid to their charge.
They got afraid.
They didn't stand with me.
But notice what he says next
but the Lord stood by me.
They didn't stand by me
but the Lord stood at my side and gave me strength
so that through me
this is the last verse we'll use
the message might be fully proclaimed
and all the Gentiles might hear it
and I was delivered from the lion's mouth.
So I want to tell you something.
There are moments in life
when even your spouse can't understand what you're going through.
You're married and got a great husband or wife
but there's certain pressures
and attacks and things that happen in life they won't understand
they're not sensitive to it
your friends aren't there for you
you just lost your job
you don't know what's going to happen
but I want to tell you something.
You are never alone.
The Lord is with you.
He promised, I will never leave you nor forsake you.
Can we clap for that and say amen?
The Lord is with you today.
Let's close our eyes.
Some of the stuff I'm going through
or feeling is your sermon really fit me what I'm going through right now.
Maybe you've been deserted, hurt, abandoned emotionally, physically.
Or maybe there's some evil person, evil entity, you know
just trying to hurt you.
They're going out of their way to hurt you.
They're not believers.
They're up to no good.
Or maybe you're just going through this period of like
does anyone know what I'm going through?
Does anyone feel what I'm feeling?
I want to tell you Jesus does.
And I want you to turn your eyes upon him today.
I would like to pray over some people maybe who feel this sermon was especially for them.
Would you just stand, please?
Where you're sitting, just stand.
That'll let me know I can pray for you.
You haven't done anything wrong
you're in the center of God's will
you want to serve Jesus, and yet
why is this happening?
Because that's the way to go.
I fought a good fight.
I'm gonna finish the race.
Anyone else up in the balcony?
Don't be self-conscious and don't be embarrassed.
There's nothing to be embarrassed about.
This is life.
Paul admitted it to uh Timothy.
No, this one deserted me.
No, what's wrong with you, Paul?
Why did he desert you?
No, it's nothing wrong with me.
It's just that's the way life works sometimes.
People have a free will
and sometimes choose really a bad decision.
If you're standing
would you make your way out of your seat
and come up here to the front?
We're gonna sing over you
turn your eyes upon Jesus.
Come on, if you were standing, come on.
Rapid over the edge.
There you go.
It's so important that the Lord helps you today
because it's gonna have an effect on that boy.
Am I right?
That boy needs you, depends on you.
Looks for it is the front, just lift up one hand, just lift up and take.
Ma'am, I'd like to pray over you, may I?
Do you come here regularly
or no your first time or what?
You come, come on up.
That's your little baby.
You got a daughter.
How nice.
Come on up.
Lord, I thank you.
You never leave us.
People do mean things, they desert us
some are bent on evil.
Some even Christians get weak
and they don't understand what we're going through.
But Jesus, we turn our eyes on you.
You're gonna help all my friends here in the front.
You're gonna help my sister here, Lord.
Something beautiful is gonna start in her life today.
She's gonna walk with you, Jesus
but you gotta help her.
You gotta help her.
A lot of stuff's happened in her life, Lord.
You know that.
But now you're gonna help her and walk with her.
And she's gonna turn back to this day.
Wow, November 23rd, before Thanksgiving.
Oh, God met me at the church.
Pulled me right out.
I thank you for the God daughter.
I thank you for her situation
whatever it might be.
And all my other friends
you're gonna help us, Lord.
You're gonna help them be strong in their faith.
They're not gonna rock and roll and wobble
they're gonna stand strong on Jesus Christ.
This we pray in his name.
And everyone said, Let's pick it up there
and the things of this earth sing
and the thing will grow straight.